<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0004-033-0039"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, Journal</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG16337</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Louisville</settlement>
      <repository>Filson Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>Kentucky Confederate Provisional Government Journal</collection>
      <idno>p. 116-118</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-12-31">31 December 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Journal</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">116</note></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Tuesday </hi><date when="1861-12-31"><hi rend="underline">December 31</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 1861</hi></date></p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011019">Council </orgName>met. Present Messrs <persName ref="cwgk:N00000852">Bates</persName>. <persName ref="cwgk:N00000843">H. W. Bruce</persName>, <persName ref="cwgk:N00000846">E. M. Bruce</persName> <persName ref="cwgk:N00011225">Moore</persName>, <persName ref="cwgk:N00011020">Burnside</persName>, <persName ref="cwgk:N00000853">Thompson</persName>, and <persName ref="cwgk:N00000856">Scott</persName> -- 
<lb/>And the <persName ref="cwgk:N00000832">President</persName> and <persName ref="cwgk:N00000833">President Protempore</persName> being absent from leave and sickness -- 
<lb/>On Motion the Council proceeded to the election of a President Pro tempore -- which resulted in the unanimous choice of J. P. Bates- who thereupon took the Chair and the council proceeded to business.</p>
<p>Mr H. W. Bruce asked and obtained the unanimous consent of the Council to introduce a bill to amend an act "entitled an act to raise and arm thirty regiments of volunteer Infantry and Cavalry -- "
<lb/>The committee was constituted upon said leave as follows
<lb/>Messrs H. W. Bruce Thompson and Scott.</p>
<p>A message from the <persName ref="cwgk:N001002">Governor</persName> by <persName ref="cwgk:N00011014">Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee</persName> Secretary of State announcing his approval of the bond Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi>. <persName ref="cwgk:N00000835">H. E. Read</persName> as commissioner- and thereupon said approval was confirmed by the council and said bond ordered to be filed with the Secretary of State.</p>
<p>The Council then took up the bill entitled "An act to amend an act entitled an act to empower the Governor to appoint a commissioner to the Confederate States of America on the subject of Banks.</p>
<p>Ordered that said bill be read a third time -- 
<lb/>The rule of the Council, Constitutional provision and third reading were dispensed with -- 
<lb/>The question then being upon the passage of the bill, and being put it was decided in the affirmative.
<lb/>And so the bill passed.
<lb/>Ordered That the title be as reported.</p>
<p>Mr Scott moved the following resolution- Towit
<lb/>Resolved That this Council do now proceed to the election of two Senators to represent the State of <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003448">Kentucky</orgName> in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00012075">Senate of the Confederate States</orgName>.</p>
<p>Mr H. W. Bruce offerred the following as a substitute for said resolution Towit
<lb/>Resolved by the Council of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky that the Council proceed on the first Tuesday of <date when="1862-02">February next</date> to elect two Senators to represent the State of<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">117</note>
<lb/>Kentucky in the Senate of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003030">Confederate States</orgName>."</p>
<p>The question was taken upon the adoption of the substitute and it was decided in the negative -- 
<lb/>Messrs H. W. Bruce and Thompson having demanded the ayes and noes thereon and being called resulted as follows:
<lb/>Those voted in the affirmative were Messrs
<lb/>Thompson and H. W. Bruce -- 2 -- 
<lb/>Those who voted in the negative were Messrs
<lb/>Bates, Burnside, E. M. Bruce, Moore, and Scott -- 5.</p>
<p>Mr Moore then moved the following amendment to the original resolution -- Towit: "Amend by striking out the words "now" in the original resolution, and insert in lieu thereof the words "Wednesday the <date when="1862-01-01">first day of January 1862</date> at 1<hi rend="str">0</hi>2 O'Clock M"
<lb/>But before the question was taken on said amendment it was withdrawn.
<lb/>And then the Council took a recess until 2 O'Clock P. M.</p>
<p>Evening Session</p>
<p>The Council met- J. P Bates President Protem in the chair-</p>
<p>On motion a call of the Members was made and the following Members were found to be absent Mr Machen- on leave -- Excused -- Mr Crockett on leave -- excused <persName ref="cwgk:N00000837">Mr Chrisman</persName>- on leave excused -- Mr E. M. Bruce -- 
<lb/>Mr E. M Bruce was sent for by the se<hi rend="str">a</hi>rgeant at arms -- who appeared and was excused.</p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011361">Committee on enrollments</orgName> reported that they had examined an enrolled bill entitled "An act to amend an act entitled an act to empower the Governor to appoint a Commissioner to the Confederate States of America on the subject of Banks"
<lb/>and they had found the same truly enrolled -- whereupon the President Protem affixed his signature thereto.</p>
<p>Mr Thompson moved to postpone the further consideration of the resolution in relation to election of Senators -- which motion was lost.</p>
<p>Mr Moore then renewed his amendment and the question being taken thereon it was adopted -- </p>
<p>Messrs H W Bruce &amp; Thompson having demanded the ayes and naes, and the call being made it resulted as follows:
<lb/>Those who voted in the affirmative were Messrs
<lb/>Bates, Burnside, E. M. Bruce, Moore and scott -- 5<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">118</note>
<lb/>Those who voted in the negative were Messrs
<lb/>H. W. Bruce and Thompson -- 2 -- </p>
<p>The question then being on the adoption of the resolution as amended and being taken it was decided in the affirmative</p>
<p>And then the Council adjourned until tomorrow at 10 O'Clock A. M.</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00001858">A. Frank Brown</persName> Clerk</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
