<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0004-033-0036"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, Journal</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG16334</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Louisville</settlement>
      <repository>Filson Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>Kentucky Confederate Provisional Government Journal</collection>
      <idno>p. 101-102</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-12-27">27 December 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Journal</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">101</note></p>
<p>Friday <date when="1861-12-27">December 27.<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011019">council</orgName> met. <persName ref="cwgk:N00000833">Mr Crockett</persName> President Protem in the chair.</p>
<p>A message from the <persName ref="cwgk:N001002">Governor</persName> by Mr <persName ref="cwgk:N00011014">M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee</persName> Secretary of State was received -- </p>
<p>Mr President: I am directed to lay before this council a message in writing from the Governor:</p>
<p><orgName ref="cwgk:O00011543">Executive Office</orgName>
<lb/><placeName ref="cwgk:P00000560">Bowling Green</placeName> <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Ky</placeName>
<lb/><date when="1861-12-26">Dec. 26. 1861</date></p>
<p>Gentlemen of the Council of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>I herewith nominate for the Office of Sheriff of the County of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00001918">Christian</placeName>, <persName ref="cwgk:N00012023">J. M. Graves</persName> of said County</p>
<p>George W. Johnson</p>
<p>The nomination of J. M. Graves for Sheriff of Christian County was Confirmed Whereupon Mr Graves appeared and tooke the Oath prescribed by law</p>
<p>The council took up the bill in regard to raising Volunteers. The select Committee to whom was referred said bill reported a substitute entitled "an Act to raise and arm Thirty regiments of Volunteer Infantry and Cavalry-</p>
<p>Mr <persName ref="cwgk:N00000843">H. W. Bruce</persName> offered the following amendment to the substitute Towit: "The Governor is also authorized to receive in the same manner, One or more Companies of Artillery to consist of not less than <gap/> men nor more than <gap/> men
 <lb/>Said company or companies shall be mustered into the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000506">service of the Confederate States</orgName> on the same terms and conditions as aforesaid
<lb/>The Officers shall be elected by the members of <hi rend="str">of</hi> the Company.</p>
<p>The vote was taken on said amendment and it was lost<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">102</note></p>
<p>The question was then on the adoption of the substitute reported by the select Committee and being put it was decided in the affirmative
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00011225">Mr Moore</persName> then moved that the further consideration of the bill be postponed until tomorrow at 10 O'Clock A. M. and that the same be made the special order of the day for that hour which motion prevailed -- </p>
<p>Mr <persName ref="cwgk:N00008283">M. M Johnson</persName> Sheriff of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002312">Webster County</placeName> appeared and took the oath prescribed by law.</p>
<p>Mr H. W. Bruce from a select Committee reported a bill entitled "An act to provide for the election of Members to the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00012059">House of Representatives </orgName>of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00002994">Congress of the Confederate States</orgName>" which bill then had its first reading.
<lb/>On Motion the rule of the council Constitutional provision and second reading were dispensed with</p>
<p>On Motion of Mr Moore the further consideration of the bill was postponed until tomorrow -- </p>
<p>And then the Council adjourned until 10 O'Clock A. M. Tomorrow</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00001858">A. Frank Brown</persName> Clerk</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
