<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0052"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Noflet Jones, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9520</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Charles Welsko</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Kevin McPartland</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Charles R. Welsko</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-124</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-02-08">8 February 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><placeName ref="cwgk:P00002472">Caldwell County</placeName> sct.</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00014117">Norphet Jones</persName> states, that he is a near neighbor to <persName ref="cwgk:N00011764">Thomas B. Wadlington</persName>, and has been intimately acquainted with him and his family for a number of years. He states that Thomas B. Wadlington is a good and kind neighbor a peaable and law abiding citizen and such is the general opinion of his neighbors. He further states, that he does verily believe that manifest injustice has been done him by the verdict of the jury. He states that he has been acquainted with the deceased <hi rend="str">and</hi><persName ref="cwgk:N00011760"> Cartwright </persName>ever since he was a child, and that he is and has been regarded as a violent, quarrelsome and very dangerous young man, and has been so generally regarded by his neighbors.</p>
<p>He further states that he does verily believe that the evidence of <persName ref="cwgk:N00013981">Prince</persName> and <persName ref="cwgk:N00013982">Blalock </persName>made a false impression on the minds of the Jury and induced the Jury to bring in a verdict, which in his opinion is wholly unjust, and does violence to the best interest of society.</p>
<p>He further states, that from his acquaintance with all the parties, and his familiarity with the ground and place where the killing took place, and the manner of the killing, and who commenced it he is induced to believe, that the evidence as detailed by Prince and Blalock as to who commened and brot on the difficulty is and was not true, and he does verily believe, that the kill<pb/>
<lb/>ing of Cartwright was in self defence.</p>
<p>Noflet. Jones</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me by Norphlet Jones this <date when="1861-02-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Feby 1861</date>.</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00003859">J. C. Barnes </persName>D. C.
<lb/>for <persName ref="cwgk:N00003864">E. P. Watkins</persName> clk
<lb/><orgName ref="cwgk:O00000363">Caldwell Circuit Court</orgName></p>
<p>Caldwell County sct.</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00014116">Sam<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> C. Campbell </persName>says he has just heard the foregoing statement of Norflet Jones read over, and he adopts the same as his own, and believes the statements therein made are true.</p>
<p>Samuel. C, Campbell</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me by Sam<hi rend="underline">l</hi> C. Campbell -- This <date when="1861-02-08">8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Feby 1861</date>.</p>
<p>J. C. Barnes D. C.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
