<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0441"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Merie G. Banks to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4560</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Emily D. Moses</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-195 to BR9-196</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-25">25 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><placeName ref="cwgk:P00000337">Louisville </placeName><placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Ky</placeName>, <date when="1864-01-25">Jan. 25<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N001000">Gov. Bramlett</persName></p>
<p>You ar doubtless importuned and asked verry frequently to Parden men out of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000266">penitintiary</orgName>. So much So that I fear that I will be considered an intruder or tresspasser upon your Valueable time. But believeing in the Justness of my cause and having an abiding Confidence in your integrity and Patriotism I appeal with confidence and trust that he that ruleth and controlls all things will enables you to See that my poor unfortunate <hi rend="underline">Husband</hi> is a fit Subject for Executive Clemency,</p>
<p>My Husband W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Banks and his companion in arms ^John M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Clure^ were Sentenced to the State Prison upon the charge of having received Some tobacco which afterwards turned out to ^have^ been Stolen, now I will tell you the truth about that matter, about dusk one evening three large Size boys came to our place and Seeing that my husband &amp; McClure were Soldiers, Solisited them to buy Some tobacco from them Saying that we will Sell cheaper than you can buy elsewhere.<pb/>
<lb/>my husband asked them where they got tobacco they unhesitatingly Said their Employer at the Factory had given it to them for work which they had done in the factery, So my husband not dreaming of doing any wrong and certainly apprehending no wrong intent upon the part of Boys, did buy the tobacco from them, So I tell you of a truth <hi rend="str">the</hi> and in view of my future destiny that the tobacco was bough in good faith and believing that the Boys had told us the truth -- these Boys look dirty just as if though they had come out of a tobacco factory, let me assure you that the Streets of this city are full of Men Women Boys &amp; children who are importuning the Soldiers upon all hands to buy from them Various articles Such as tobacco cigars Sack, fruits &amp;c, the Soldier never thinks no it never enters his mind that these may have been stolen, he Simply Sees the article and if it Suits him he buys it never dreaming by So doing that he ha<hi rend="str">s</hi>d committed a wrong, my Husband was only a common Soldier his pay as you know was only $13, per month -- which was not enough to Support us.<pb/>
<lb/>the duties which he had to perform were that of being Guard at Barracks no 1, So his times was not occupied all the time, So he would Sell Various articles of necesities to Soldiers at the Barrack and Hospitals, Such as fruits tobacco and cigars the profits of which in addition to his regular pay enabled us to live tolerably comfortable, But when he got these two packages of tobacco from the Boys, he though he would Sell it at wholesale, hence he offered it ^to^ the Grocerymen Saying to the groceryman to Say nothing about it, the reason that he wished him to keep it a Secre<hi rend="str">c</hi>t was that he knew that the Police would arrest him for Pedling without licens if they became Conizant of the fact, So doing Such a Small business he could not afford to take out licens hence they requested Secrecy,</p>
<p>My Husband has Served nearly three years in the army- has gone through the perils and hardships of a Soldiers life, without a murmur, and this is the only blot upon his fair escutcheon either Civil or military<pb/></p>
<p>But, this this dark Spot is upon his heretofore fair character, it must be Blotted out. (provided your excellency will grant the privilege) by enlisting as a Veteran in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00001186">army</orgName> of my <placeName ref="cwgk:P001802">Country</placeName>, and by Valor upon the ensanguine fields of death &amp; carnage, I, pray God you will grant him this privilege</p>
<p>I could urge matters touching your Sympathy, Such as poverty destitution and misery which would ensue provided my <hi rend="underline">husband</hi> was deprived the privilege of contributing to my Support, but I Scorn to do it because I am the wife of a true patriot and a Soldier, and I believe in the justness of my cause, and have the proud conciousness of knowing that my husband is inocent, though a combination of circumstances induced the Jury to think otherwise,,&amp; c.</p>
<p><hi rend="str">With I</hi> With Deep feelings of Solisitude I await your response,</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00010738">Merie G Banks</persName></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
