<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0004-033-0019"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, Journal</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG16317</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Louisville</settlement>
      <repository>Filson Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>Kentucky Confederate Provisional Government Journal</collection>
      <idno>p. 53-55</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-12-07">7 December 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Journal</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">53</note></p>
<p>
 <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000560">Bowling Green </placeName><placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Ky</placeName><lb/><hi rend="underline">Saturday </hi><date when="1861-12-07"><hi rend="underline">December 7</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 1861</hi></date></p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011019">Council</orgName> met. <persName ref="cwgk:N00000832">W. B. Machen </persName>President in the chair.<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p><hi rend="underline"><persName ref="cwgk:N00000833">Mr Crockett</persName></hi> moved that the Governor be requested to return to this Council, without action, an enrolled bill sent to him for approval, entitled "an act to authorize the Governor to appoint a Commissioner to settle with the collecting Officers of this State." which motion prevailed -- 
<lb/>Whereupon the sergeant at Arms was sent to the Governor, who returned said bill as indicated by said resolution.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p> then moved to reconsider the vote by which said bill was pased- and the question being taken thereon, it was decided in the affirmative-<persName ref="cwgk:N00000833">Mr Crockett</persName><figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p><hi rend="underline">Mr Crockett</hi> then offered a substitute for the original bill, and the question being put upon the adoption of the substitute it was decided in the affirmative-
<lb/>Ordered That said substitute be read a third time -- 
<lb/>The rule of the Council Constitutional provision and third reading were dispensed with -- 
<lb/>The question was then taken upon the passage of the substitute for the original bill, and it was decided in the affirmative.
<lb/>And so the substitute for the bill passed
<lb/>Ordered That the title be as originally reported.<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p>A special message from the Governor by <persName ref="cwgk:N00011014">R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee</persName> Secretary of State -- Mr President-</p>
<p>I am directed by the Governor to lay before this Council a special message in writing:</p>
<p>Executive Office Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-12-07">Dec 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W B. Machen</hi>
<lb/>President of the Council of the State of Kentucky</p>
   <p>Sir. The Hon<hi rend="sup">l </hi><persName ref="cwgk:N001001">R Hawes</persName> who was appointed Auditor has not yet been heard from Officially; but having reason to suppose that he will be unwilling to leave the position he now holds in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000506">Confederate Army</orgName>- and the public interests requiring the services of an Auditor, I herewith nominate <persName ref="cwgk:N00011402">Josiah Pillsbury</persName> as Auditor <hi rend="underline">Pro:</hi> <hi rend="underline">Tem:</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">George W. Johnson</hi><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The question was then taken on said nomination and it was unanimously confirmed<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">54</note></p>
   <p><persName ref="cwgk:N00000847">Mr Moore</persName> from the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011477">Committee on Common Schools</orgName> reported a bill entitled "An act for the benefit of common Schools and for other purposes"
<lb/>Which was read a first time.
<lb/>Ordered that said bill be read a second time
<lb/>On motion the rule of the Council, Constitutional provision and second reading were dispensed with.
<lb/>Mr Crockett moved that the further consideration of said bill be postponed, and that it be made the special order of the day for Tuesday next at 10 <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">2</hi> O'Clock AM. and the question being taken on said motion it was decided in the affirmative.<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p>The resolutions introduced on yesterday by <persName ref="cwgl:N00000843">H. W. Bruce</persName> being in the orders of the day was then taken up and read.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">H. W Bruce</hi> moved the following as a substitute for the original resolutions offered by him on yesterday Towit:
 <lb/><hi rend="underline">Resolved</hi> By the Council of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky that this Council hereby return to that brave regiment the profound and grateful thanks of the freemen of Kentucky for the early and gallant services of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011479">first Kentucky volunteers</orgName> in the war for Independence- And while this Council do not desire to interfere with the plans and purposes of the <persName ref="cwgk:N00000259">President</persName> of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003030">Confederate States</orgName>, if he should choose to transfer that noble regiment, to duty in their native State, Kentucky will receive them with open arms, and cordially and thankfully welcome them to their homes again.<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p><hi rend="underline"><persName ref="cwgk:N00000853">Mr Thompson</persName></hi> moved to postpone the further consideration of said resolutions, and make them the special order of the day for Wednesday next <hi rend="str">next</hi> at 10 O'Clock A.M. and the question being taken it was decided in the negative.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr <hi rend="underline">H. W. Bruce</hi> moved the following amendment to the substitute
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Resolved</hi>. That a copy of the foregoing resolution and preamble be forwarded by the Clerk, to the <persName ref="cwgk:N00011631">Colonel</persName> of that regiment -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr Thompson</hi> moved the following as an amendment to the amendment to the substitute. Towit
<lb/>By striking out the words "and while this Council do not desire to interfere with the plans and purposes of the President of the Confederate States, if he should choose to transfer that noble regiment to duty in their native State."
<lb/>And before the question was taken thereon the mover was granted leave to withdraw the same.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline"><persName ref="cwgk:N00000852">Mr Bates</persName></hi> moved to reconsider the vote by which the Council refused to postpone the further consideration of said resolutions<persName ref="cwgk:N00000852">Mr Bates</persName><pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">55</note>
<lb/>until Wednesday next- and the question being taken thereon it was decided in the affirmative -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p><hi rend="underline">Messrs Machen and <persName ref="cwgk:N00011020"> Burnside</persName></hi> having demanded the yeas and nays on said vote, were as follows. viz:
<lb/>Those who voted in the affirmative were Messrs
<lb/>Machen, Crockett, Bates, Thompson, Moore, 5
<lb/>Those who voted in the negative were Messrs
<lb/>Burnside, H. W. Bruce, <persName ref="cwgk:N00000846">E. M. Bruce</persName>,<persName ref="cwgk:N00000856"> Scott</persName> 4<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>And then on motion the further consideration of said resolutions was postponed until Wednesday next 10 O'Clock A. M.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr Moore</hi> ^moved^ that the Council go into secret Session. which motion was sustained- and the Council went into secret session.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>On motion the council after having considered such matters as were before the secret session- again resumed its general session<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Adjourned until morning next at 10 O'Clock<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Attest
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00001858">A. Frank Brown</persName> Clerk</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
