<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0180"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Johnson A. Dawson et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8632</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Charles Welsko</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>CWGK Staff</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Charles R. Welsko</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-274 to R3-275</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Powell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-01-24">24 January 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excelency <persName ref="cwgk:N001004">Jas F Robinson</persName> Govenor of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Commonwealth of Kentucky</orgName></p>
<p>Your Petitioners would Beg Leave to Reprsent to your Excelency that at the <date>Sept term of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000491">Powell Circuit Court</orgName> 1861</date> that the Commonwealth obtained a Judgement against <persName ref="cwgk:N00017636">John H. Danehew</persName> &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00017632">Thomas Martin</persName> for the Sum of Fifty dollars Each for Carring Conceald Weapons,, and they would further Represent that at the time of the finding of Said Judgement that the Said Donehew and Martin had volunteered in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00001186">United States Army</orgName> in Capt <persName ref="cwgk:N00008506">G. M. Jackson </persName>Company and the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00005258">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Regement ^of Ky Vol^</orgName> then at <orgName ref="cwgk:O00009781">Camp Roberson</orgName>,, and that the Said Danehew &amp; Martin were Put in the Powell Jail in default of the Pament of Said Judgement </p>
<p>and they would further represent to youre Excelency that <persName ref="cwgk:N00006960">J N B Hardwick</persName> our County Judge a devoted Union Man and one that took a great interest in making up Capt Jackson's Company Repleved the fines for Said Danehew &amp; Martin and took them out of Jail and Sent them to there Command they Promising <hi rend="str">it</hi> him that when they drew there money for there Services from the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00002945">United States</orgName> that they would Send him the money to pay Said fines ^but^ they are Still in the Service and have failed to <hi rend="str">to</hi> Send the money as they promised,, and they are now Endevoring to Collect Said Judgements out of Said Hardwick which will be verry oppressive on him if he has it to pay<pb/>
<lb/>and we think Honestly taking Every thing into Consideration that the Case presents Strong grounds for the Exercise of Executive Clemency and we would aske youre Excelency to Remit Said fines. </p>
<p>yours with due respect
<lb/><date when="1863-01-24">Jan 24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00017633">Johnson A, Dawson</persName> D S, P, C
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006961">John F. Halley</persName> J P C
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006966">C D Creed</persName>. C. P. C.
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00017634">M Stewartt</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006959">Th<hi rend="underline">os</hi> C Judy</persName> C. P. C.C.<pb/></p>
<p>Powell Cir. Ct</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>J F Robinson</p>
<p>$50 each } Weapons
<lb/>Jno. H. Danehew
<lb/>&amp;
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Martin
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-02-03">Feby 3. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
