<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0004-033-0027"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, Journal</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG16325</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Louisville</settlement>
      <repository>Filson Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>Kentucky Confederate Provisional Government Journal</collection>
      <idno>p. 81-83</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-12-17">17 December 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Journal</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">81</note></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Tuesday </hi><date when="1861-12-17"><hi rend="underline">December 17.</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 1861</hi></date></p>
<p><orgName ref="cwgk:O00011019">The Council</orgName> met. <persName ref="cwgk:N00000833">J. W. Crockett</persName> President Pro.tem in the chair.<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p><hi rend="underline"><persName ref="cwgk:N00000847">Mr Moore</persName></hi> from the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011359">Committee on Ways and means</orgName> made the following report Towit</p>
<p>The Committee to whom was referred the resolution requiring a report in regard to the compensation of Commissioners to settle with the collecting officers &amp;<hi rend="sup">c.</hi> would beg leave to submit the following report.</p>
<p>In view of the difficulties which suggest themselves growing out of the nature of the duties to be performed by the Commissioners, we recomme<hi rend="str">d</hi>nd that no specific compensation be now fixed. While this Committee will be willing to allow and pay to said Commissioners a just and liberal compensation, we at the same time desire, that it shall be as nearly equal, as the nature of the case may require. In some sections of the Country the duties of the Commissioner will be as we apprehend comparatively easy -- in others very difficult. We therefore think that we can much more easily approach Justice and equity by making the allowance after the labor is performed- Therefore we ask to be discharged form the further Consideration of the subject of the resolution untill after the said Commissioners shall be discharged their duties.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Said report was adopted and the committee discharged from a further consideration of the subject.<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p><hi rend="underline">Mr Moore</hi> from the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011358">Committee on the Judiciary</orgName> reported a bill entitled "an act to define Treason" which bill was read a first time.
<lb/>Ordered That said bill be read a second time.
<lb/>On motion the rule of the Council Constitutional provision and second reading were dispensed. with.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr Moore</hi> moved the following resolution Towit
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Resolved</hi> That the Committee on the Judiciary be instructed to report a bill providing for the taking of the oath of allegiance to the Government of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003030">Confederate States of America</orgName>."
<lb/>And before the question was taken thereon it was withdrawn<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline"><persName ref="cwgk:N00000853">Mr Thompson</persName></hi> moved the following resolution Towit
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Resolved</hi> That hereafter there shall be but one daily session, of this Council, unless specially Ordered.
<lb/>The question being put said resolution was rejected -- <pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">82</note></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">A Special Message</hi> from the <persName ref="cwgk:N001002">Governor</persName> by <persName ref="cwgk:N00011014">R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee </persName>Secretary of State: Mr President I am directed by the Governor to lay before this Council a communication in writing:</p>
<p><hi rend="underline"><orgName ref="cwgk:O00011543">Executive Office</orgName>
<lb/><placeName ref="cwgk:P00000560">Bowling Green</placeName> <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Ky</placeName></hi>
<lb/><date when="1861-12-16"><hi rend="underline">December 16.</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 1861</hi></date>
<lb/>Gentlemen of the Council of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003448">State of Kentucky</orgName></p>
   <p>The resignation of the Office of Treasurer by the <persName ref="cwgk:N00000838">Hon<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> <persName ref="cwgk:N00000838">Theodore L. Burnett</persName></persName> is herewith inclosed to you. </p>
<p>I nominate for this Office <persName ref="cwgk:N00011354">John Burnam</persName></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">George W. Johnson</hi><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The resignation referred to in the foregoing message is as follows Towit</p>
<p>Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-12-16">16.<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dec. 1861.</date>
<lb/>His Excellency: George W Johnson</p>
<p>Sir. Having been honored by an election to a seat in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00002994">Confederate Congress</orgName> I here- tender my resignation as Treasurer of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>I have the honor to be most Truly
<lb/>Your Ob<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Serv<hi rend="sup">t</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">T. L. Burnett</hi><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The resignation of T. L. Burnett as Treasurer was accepted and the nomination of John Burnam unanimously confirmed.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Executive Office
<lb/>Bowling Green Ky.</hi>
<lb/><date when="1861-12-16"><hi rend="underline">Dec. 16.</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 1861</hi></date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Gentlemen of the</hi> Council of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>I herewith lay before you a communication by Telegraph from the Hon <persName ref="cwgk:N00000749">H. C. Burnett</persName>.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">George W. Johnson</hi></p>
<p>The communication referred to reads as follows Towit
<lb/>"By Telegraph from <placeName ref="cwgk:P00008174">Richmond</placeName> -- <date when="1861-12-16">16- 1861</date>
<lb/>To George W. Johnson Govr. of Ky.</p>
<p>Congress has rescinded resolution of adjournment -- Bill in regard to Kentucky Banks passed</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">H. C. Burnett</hi><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>And then the Council adjourned until 2 <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">2</hi> O'Clock P. M.<figure type="hr"/><pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">83</note></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Evening Session</hi></p>
<p>The Council met at 2 <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">2</hi> O'Clock P. M. J W Crockett Pres<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Pro tem in the chair<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011361">committee on enrollment</orgName>s reported that they had examined an enrolled bill entitled "An act requiring all the Officers of the State of Kentucky to take an oath to support the Constitution of the Confederate States of America." Also a preamble and resolutions in reference to the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011479">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Kentucky Regiment</orgName>" and that they had found the same truly enrolled-
<lb/>Thereupon the President Protem affixed his signature thereto<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>And then the Council adjourned until 10 O'Clock A. M. tomorrow.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Attest
<lb/><hi><persName ref="cwgk:N00001858">A. Frank Brown</persName> Clerk.</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
