<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0370"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Veachel H. Jones &amp; Lewis McQuown to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4489</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Kristen Bailey</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-87 to BR9-88</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-09">9 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><orgName ref="cwgk:O00000351">Barren Equity &amp; Criminal Court</orgName>
<lb/>The Commonwealth Plaintiff
<lb/>against
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00012483">Joh W Houze</persName> &amp;c Defendants</p>
<p>The Defendant John W Houze &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00012493">Marion Larrison</persName> State that sometime in <date when="1863-02">Feby, 1863</date> they were arrested and confined in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00013567">Barren County Jail</orgName> under a charge of Horse Stealing, that on the <date when="1863-02-25">25<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of February 1863</date> they were taken from said Jail under the operation of a writ of Habous Corpus &amp; admited to bail in the Sum of $500 Each</p>
<p>They further State that the defendants <persName ref="cwgk:N00010802">William Sampson </persName>executed a bond for each of them in the Said Sum of $500 Conditioned that he would pay the <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Commonwealth of Ky</orgName> Said Sums provided said defendants failed to appear in the Barren Equity &amp; Criminal Court at its Next <date when="1863-06">June term (1863)</date> to answer said charge &amp; at all times Surrender themselves Subject to the orders of Said Court &amp;c They State that they failed to appear in Said Court at its <date when="1863-06">June term 1863</date> &amp; that there was an order made in Said Court directing Said bonds to be forfeited &amp; directing a Summons to Issue against said Sampson They further State that at the time said charge was made against them &amp; said proceedings had &amp; Said bonds executed that they were &amp; had been Soldiers in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00001186">Military Servis of the united States</orgName> for Some Eighteen Months<pb/></p>
   <p>that they belonged to the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00012482">4<hi rend="str">0</hi>1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Reg 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Indiana Cavely </orgName>That when they were released from said Jail upon the execution of Said bonds, that they returned to their homes in the Sate of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001818">Indiana</placeName>, with the intention of returning if they were permited and answer said Charge- the defendant<hi rend="str">s</hi> Marion Larrison States that at the time Said Court was held in <date when="1863-06">June 1863</date> &amp; for sometime before he was Sick &amp; two unwell &amp; not abel to attend said court- they both State that the mode of Travel from their homes to <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000336">Glasgow Ky</placeName> is by railroad &amp; that was the way they expected to travel to said Court &amp; had so made their arrangements- That a Short time before the commencement of said Court they were informed &amp; so beleaved that the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00012501">rail Road</orgName> between <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000337">Louisville</placeName> &amp; Glasgow the only road they could Travel by rail had been destroyed by Guerrillas &amp; that there was no chance of passing on said road &amp; they State that Said road was or a portion of it destroyed a Short time before Said Court &amp; they were informed that they could not Travel in that way it was then Too late to travel by any other Conveyance besides the danger of ^their^ being captured by Gurrillas &amp; it was to<hi rend="str">d</hi>taly out of their power to get to sd Court- They State also that they were required by their officers and <orgName ref="cwgk:O00002945">the Government in Whoose Service they were</orgName> to return to their regiment, under penalty of being punished as deserters, That they could not pass<pb/></p>
   <p>from home to sd court without a pass from their <persName ref="cwgk:N00012499">officer </persName>&amp; that they were cut off from their Command at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00012496">Hartsville</placeName><placeName ref="cwgk:P001001"> Tenn</placeName> that to have attempted to go to Glasgow without permission of their officer they would have been arrested &amp; Tried as deserters- They refer to &amp; Make the writs of Habaus Corpus &amp; proceedings under them &amp; the order forfeiting said bonds part hereof- That they did return to the army &amp; their Regiments &amp; have been in Said Servis ever Since That their time will not expire until <date when="1864-09">Sept 1864</date> &amp; then or as soon as they can gain permission they desire to appear &amp; answer said charge Such permission they have as yet been unabel to obtain They further State that before the defendant Sampson went their bail &amp; executed Said bonds they deposited with him as indemnity the amount of Each bond in Mony that are the real parties in intrest in regard to the forfeiture of Said bonds</p>
<p>Wherefore they pray that they be made defendants hereto &amp; this be Taken as an answer &amp; the order forfeiting the same be set aside &amp; for all proper relief</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00012497">Jones</persName> &amp;<persName ref="cwgk:N00012498"> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Quown</persName> for Defts</p>
<p>State of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Kentucky</placeName> <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000558">Barren county</placeName></p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00012494">George Larrison </persName>&amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00012484">Micheal Houze</persName> state<hi rend="str">s</hi> that they are agents for Defendants John W Hauze &amp; Marion Larrison Whoo are absent from this County &amp; State and that they believe the Statements made in the foregoing answer are true</p>
<p>George Larrison
<lb/>M hauze<pb/></p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Micheal Hauze &amp; George Larrison this <date when="1863-12-09">9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of December 1863</date></p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00012597">T H M Winn</persName> D. C.</p>
<p>A Copy Attest</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00012500">W. L. Porter</persName> clk</p>
<p>Houze &amp; Lorimer
<lb/>Answer</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
