<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0347"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">B. Tinsley to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9815</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Charles R. Welsko</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-36 to MG18-37</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Daviess County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin,</p>
<p>Your petitioner Benjamin Tinsley would represent that at the <date when="1859-09">September Term 1859</date> of the Daviess Circuit Court, he was fined the sum of sixty dollars for selling liquor by the "small." At the time of the supposed selling he was a merchant tailor on a small scale. He kept a few goods in his shop, and likewise a little beer and Cider in a room adjacent, and his friends frequently partook of these innocent and refresing beverages -- But one John Frazier not content with the exilerating influences of beer and cider but desiring a more intoxicating fluid^s^, crept stealthily to a barrel of<pb/>
<lb/>whiskey, ^(Petitioner had license to sell by the quart)^ and did mix the same; and it was upon the evidence of said Frazier alone that your petitioner was fined as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Your petitioner denies that he ever violated any of the penal statutes of the Commonwealth and since he has discovered how his enemies may use their own wrong to his detriment, he pledges himself to abstain in future from all traffic in any of the foregoing articles.</p>
<p>Petitioner is a poor man -- he has a wife and five interesting children who are dependent on his labor for support, and he assures your Excellency upon the honor of a man that he has not sixty dollars to spare from his verry limited means.</p>
<p>In tender consideration of the premises Petitioner prays the interpo<pb/>
<lb/>sition of Executive clemency in his behalf. That your Excellency will remit his fine, and save himself and family from the ruinous consequence which the rigor of the law would entail upon them and as in duty bound he will ever pray for your Excellency,</p>
<p>B Tinsley</p>
<p>Yelvington
<lb/><date when="1859-09-29">Sept. 29. 1859</date>.</p>
<p>We the undersigned have Known Mr. Benjamin Tinsley for many years. He is a poor man, but a man of industrious habits, and we cheefully join in recommending him to Executive mercy. We believe there is merit in his petition</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Edwin Hawes
<lb/>Ch<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Morris
<lb/><cb n="2"/>T. C. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Creery
<lb/>Sam<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Hawes
<lb/>Cam Riley<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Davies Circuit Court
<lb/>&#36;60. &#125; Tipling
<lb/>Benj. Tinsley
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1859-10-05">5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Oct. 1859</date>
<lb/>Remission Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>
<lb/><date when="1860-06-25">June 25. 1860</date></p>
<p>Respite 12 months
<lb/>B. Magoffin</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>