<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0348"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. M. Quinton to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4467</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Kristen Bailey</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-53 to BR9-54</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1863-12-03">3 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency, the Govenor of <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Kentucky</orgName>;</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00012413">J. M. Quinton</persName> ^Your petitioner^ States that about the <date when="1863-08-14">14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of August, 1863</date>, he was fined thirty dollars in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003265">Police Court of Harrodsburg</orgName> for a breach of the peace, Said alledged offence growing out of a fight between Your petitioner and one <persName ref="cwgk:N00012415">Emanuel Garcia</persName>, a Mexican, and for a long time a Soldier in <orgName ref="cwgk:O00009906">John H- Morgan's Command</orgName>. Your petitioner further States that the Said Emanuel Garcia while attached to the command of Morgan, during one of his raids into Kentucky, c<hi rend="str">a</hi>ome to the house of Your petitioner -- durring his absences and while he was a refugee from home on account of his Union principles and Searched for your petitioner and insultingly demanded of his wife to make known his whereabouts, at the some time making threats &amp;c -- ; and that afterwards when Said Garcia had deserted Morgan and came home your petitioner meeting him asked him about his conduct at his house and that on receiving an insulting reply <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>Your <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>petitioner whipped the native Mexican and rebel deserter; and that the breach of the peace charged consisted in this. J. M. Quinton further states that at the time such insults were offered to his family he was, and is now, a discharged Union Soldier, having served in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00009930">19<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky regiment </orgName>under <persName ref="cwgk:N00009931">Col. Landrum</persName><pb/>
<lb/>for nearly a year and discharged on account of physical disability. On account of these facts he asks of your Excellency a favorable consideration in his behalf J. M. Quinton states on oath he believes the statements in the foregoing petition are true,, <hi rend="str">Sworn to before me this <date when="1863-11-03">3rd <unclear/> Novr 1863</date></hi> and that his knowledge of said Garcia being at his houses is based on information of his family; the other statements of the petition he knows to be true</p>
<p>J M Quinton</p>
<p>Subscribed and Sworn to before me this <date when="1863-12-03">3 December, 1863</date> -- </p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00002329">John G. Kyle</persName>,
<lb/>Police Judge of Harrodsburg.</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Mercer County Would urge and request Your Excellency to, remit the fine of J. M. Quinton, believing him to be especially an object of clemency -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006562">JW. V. Frapnall</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006609">O S Poston</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00003674">Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Edwards</persName> P J M C C
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00003205">J, L, Smedley</persName>
<lb/>John G- Kyle
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00012383">James D Hardin</persName>
<lb/><cb n="2"/><persName ref="cwgk:N00003678">C, S, Abner</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00002356">Richard Board </persName>C. M. C. C
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00009438">W, E, Riley</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00012416">George Frapnall</persName><milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p><placeName ref="cwgk:P00000555">Harrodsburg</placeName> ky
<lb/><date when="1863-12-16">Decr 16 1863</date>
<lb/><hi rend="str">Dear</hi> Governor Bramlette
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I present the enclosed petition for your consideration and execative clemency Trusting that at an early day you will give it a perusal</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Your friend
<lb/><hi>O S Poston</hi></p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">J G K
<lb/><date when="1863-12-03">3 Dec- 1863</date></note><pb/></p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N001000">Tho E Bramlette</persName></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
