<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0004-033-0028"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, Journal</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG16326</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Louisville</settlement>
      <repository>Filson Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>Kentucky Confederate Provisional Government Journal</collection>
      <idno>p. 83-86</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-12-18">18 December 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Journal</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">83</note></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Wednesday- </hi><date when="1862-12-18"><hi rend="underline">December 18</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 1862</hi></date></p>
   <p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011019">Council</orgName> met. <persName ref="cwgk:N00000833">J. W. Crockett</persName> President Pro tem in the Chair<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p>A. Message from the <persName ref="cwgk:N001002">Governor</persName> by <persName ref="cwgk:N00011014">R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee</persName> Secretary of State announcing his approval <hi rend="str">of</hi> of a bill entitled
<lb/>An act requiring all the Officers of the State of <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003448">Kentucky</orgName> to take an oath to support the Constitution of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003030">Confederate States of America</orgName>.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Also the bond of <persName ref="cwgk:N00011623">L. W Potter</persName> Sheriff of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001020">Warren County</placeName> with his approval.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>On motion the approval by the Governor of the bond of L. W. Potter was confirmed by the council and said bond ordered to be filed with the <persName ref="cwgk:N00011402">auditor of State</persName><figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p>The <persName ref="cwgk:N00000846">chairman</persName> of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011356">Committee on Banks</orgName> reported as follows Towit:
<lb/>Your committee to whom was referred a communication from <persName ref="cwgk:N00011628">G. C. Torbett</persName> and others of the City of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001004">Nashville</placeName> on the subject of Banks and currency -- report
<lb/>That they found many suggestions in said communication worthy of consideration and while we think some of their sugestions impracticable at this time yet believe the same ends can be accomplished by different means, and<pb/>
<lb/>offer an act, which we believe will relieve this question of much difficulty and embarassment<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The Committee on Banks reported a bill entitled "An act to regulate Banks and Currency."
<lb/>Said Bill was read a first time
<lb/>Ordered That said bill be read a second time.
<lb/>On motion the rule of the Council, Constitutional provision and second and third readings were dispensed with.
<lb/>The question was then taken on the passage of the bill, and it was decided in the affirmative -- 
<lb/>And so the bill passed.
<lb/>Ordered that the title thereof be a reported<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline"><persName ref="cwgk:N00011716">B. F. Allison</persName></hi> Commissioner appointed to settle with collecting Officers appeared and took the oath required by law.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011355">Committee on Military affairs</orgName> to whom was referred the communication of <persName ref="cwgk:N00011338">W. G. Bullitt</persName> reported as follows Towit:
<lb/>"The Committee on Military affairs to whom was referred the Comminication of W. G. Bullitt report.
<lb/>That they deem it inexpedient to give the authority asked or to legislate on the subject therein presented at the present time -- They ask to be discharged from the further Consideration of the subject</p>
<p><hi rend="underline"><persName ref="cwgk:N00000853">Phil B. Thompson</persName></hi> Chairman<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>On motion said Committee were discharged from the further consider of the subject mentioned in said report.<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p>On motion of <persName ref="cwgk:N00011225">Mr Moore</persName> the Council then went into Secret Session<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>And after considering the matters pertaining to secret Session the Council again resumed its general Session.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>A Message from the Governor by R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee Secretary of State announcing his approval of the bond of <persName ref="cwgk:N00011715">William Messick</persName> as Commissioner to settle with Collecting Officers -- 
<lb/>And on Motion said approal was confirmed by the Council and ordered to be filed with the Auditor.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr <persName ref="cwgk:N00000843">H. W. Bruce</persName></hi> moved the following resolution Towit:
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Resolved</hi> by the Council of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky That the Public printer is directed to print in pamphlet or in one number of the Courier all the laws passed by this Council up to this date, and to furnish the Council one hundred copies of the same for distribution among officers of the government" Which was adopted-<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">85</note>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Mr Moore</hi> Offered the following resolution Towit -- 
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Resolved</hi> by the Council of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky that the President of the Council be and he is hereby empowered and required to appoint a committee of three persons to negotiate a loan from the <orgName ref="cwgk:O001005">Southern Bank of Kentucky</orgName> at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002479">Russellville</placeName> for twenty five thousand dollars for the use of the Provisional Government of Kentucky<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr E. M. Bruce</hi> offered the following amendment Towit:
<lb/>"And if said Bank refuse to loan the twenty five thousand dollars, then said Committee be and they are hereby authorize to co-operate with the authorities of the confederate States and use such means as will secure the twenty five thousand dollars desired."<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr Moore</hi> then offered the following as a substitute for the original resolution and the amendment offered Towit: <hi rend="underline">Resolved</hi> by the Council of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky. That the Governor be and he is hereby authorized and requested to appoint two or more Commissioners to negotiate a loan from the Southern Bank of Kentucky for the sum of Twenty Five Thousand Dollars for the use of this Government, and the Governor is hereby authorized to direct and use such means as may be nescessary in his Judgment to obtain the money.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The vote being taken on the adoption of the subsitute it was decided in the affirmative, and so the substitute was adopted.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr E. M Bruce</hi> offered the following amendment viz: Strike out all after "Government" in 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> line and insert "and if said Bank refuse to loan the Twenty Five Thousand Dollars then the Governor is further authorized to use such means as in his Judgment may be necessary to obtain said Twenty five Thousand dollars of the said Southern Bank.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The question was then upon the adoption of the amendment, and being taken was decided in the affirmative.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The question being then taken in the adoption of the substitute as amended was decided in the affirmative.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The question then being upon the passage of the resolution and being taken it was decided in the affirmative-- and so the resolution passed.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The council then adjourned until 2 O'Clock P. M.<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header"><unclear>86</unclear></note>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Evening Session</hi></p>
<p>The Council re-assembled-- Jno. W. Crockett Prest. Pro. Tem in the Chair<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p>The Chairman of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011361">Committee on Enrollments</orgName> reported that they had examined a bill entitled
<lb/>An act for the benefit of Common Schools and for other purposes
<lb/>and had found the same truly enrolled, and therefore the President pro-tem affixed his signature thereto.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>A messsage from the Governor by R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee Secretary of State was received announcing his approval of the bond of John Burnam Treasurer.
<lb/>On motion said approval was confirmed by the Council and Ordered that said Bond be filed with the auditor.
<lb/><hi rend="underline"><persName ref="cwgk:N00011354">John Burnam</persName></hi> Treasurer appeared and took the oath prescribed by law.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The Committee on enrollments reported that they had examined an engrossed resolution in reference to the negotiation of Twenty Five Thousand dollars from the Southern Bank of Kentucky at Russellville-- and that they had found the same truly enrolled-- and thereupon the President pro.tem affixed his Signature thereto.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>A message from the Governor by R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee Secretary of State was received announcing his approval of a Resolution to negotiate a loan of Twenty Five Thousand dollars from the Southern Bank of Kentucky at Russellville -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>And then the Council adjourned until tomorrow at 11 O Clock. A. M.</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/><hi rend="underline"><persName ref="cwgk:N00001858">A. Frank Brown</persName> Clerk</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
