<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0004-033-0012"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, Journal</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG16310</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Louisville</settlement>
      <repository>Filson Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>Kentucky Confederate Provisional Government Journal</collection>
      <idno>p. 36-40</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-11-29">29 November 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Journal</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">36</note>
<lb/>Friday <date when="1861-11-29">November 29. 1861</date></p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011019">Council</orgName> met pursuant to adjournment
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000832">W. B, Machen</persName> President in the chair.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00000833">Mr Crockett</persName> asked and obtained leave to introduce a bill entitled "an act to authorize <persName ref="cwgk:N00011612">N. MC. Menifee</persName> to raise a regiment of Volunteers to serve three months or more in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000506">army of the Confederate states of America</orgName> -- 
<lb/>Said bill was read a first time -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr.<persName ref="cwgk:N00000846"> E M Bruce</persName> moved to strike out the name "N. M.<hi rend="sup">c</hi>C. Menifee" and insert "some Citizen of Kentucky"
<lb/>And thereupon the bill and amendment was referred to the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011355">Committee on military affairs</orgName> -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>General<persName ref="cwgk:N00002592"> S. B. Buckner</persName> and his Staff officers was formally introduced to the Council by His Excellency George W. Johnson and thereupon the council informally adjourned and after the retirement of General Buckner and his Staff the Council assumed its session<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>A Message from the Governor by<persName ref="cwgk:N00011014"> R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee </persName>Secretary of State was received:
<lb/>Mr President -- I have directed the Governor to lay before this Council a special message in writing -- </p>
<p>Executive Office
<lb/><placeName ref="cwgk:P00000560">Bowling Green</placeName> Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-11-29">Nov. 29.<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Gentlemen of the Council of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>In compliance with a resolution of the council requesting me to lay before them copies of the law enacted by the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00002994">Congress of the Confederate States </orgName>in relation to the People of Kentucky, if the same shall not in my estimation be detrimental to the public interests; I have the honor herewith to enclose the two acts above referred to.</p>
<p>These acts are intended "to aid the people of Kentucky<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">37</note>
<lb/>in repelling an invasion or occupation of their soil by the armed forces of the United States" and appropriating One million of dollars to "be expended in such manner as the President may think proper," for this purpose. I advise the publication of these acts, and will zealously unite with you in prompt and immediate measures, to bring to the assistance of the Confederate armies now in the field, Every man of suitable age, who may be disposed to take up arms for the maintenance of the liberties of his native State-</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N001002">George W. Johnson</persName><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The documents referred to in the foregoing special message are as follows Towit:</p>
<p>"No. 274- An Act to aid the people of Kentucky in repelling an invasion or occupation of their soil by the armed forces of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00001186">United States</orgName>-</p>
<p>Whereas the Government of the United States is threatening by an armed occupation of the territory of Kentucky, to violate the position of neutrality between the belligerents, which the people of that State have sought to hold; and whereas it may become the duty of the Confederate States to aid the people of Kentucky in repelling an invasion or occupation of their soil by the armed forces of the United States- Now therefore- The Congresss of the Confederate States of America do enact- That for the purpose aforesaid the President may, at his discretion, use the military forces of the Confederate States. He is also hereby authorized, in the event above recited, to muster into the service of the Confederate States, volunteers from the<placeName ref="cwgk:P001800"> State of Kentucky</placeName>. But the said volunteers shall be raised and treated in all respects, as the Other Volunteer forces of the Confederate States; and the laws heretofore passed in regard to them shall be applicable to the volunteers who may be raised in the State of Kentucky. Provided, however, that the President may, at his discretion, appoint the Officers of the line and staff of the companies and regiments thus raised, or authorize the said companies and regiments, to elect officers to such grades as he may designate.</p>
<p>Sec. 2 That the President may appoint as many major Generals and Brigadier Generals, to command such forces as he may deem nesessary</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00011613">Howell Cobb</persName>
<lb/>President of the Congress</p>
<p>Approved <date when="1861-08-30">Aug. 30. 1861</date>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000259">Jefferson Davis</persName><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Confederate States of America
<lb/><orgName ref="cwgk:O00011615">Department of Justice</orgName></p>
<p>I do hereby certify that the foregoing is a true copy of an act of the Congress of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003030">Confederate States of America</orgName><pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">38</note>
<lb/>approved <date when="1861-08-30">August 30.<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date> and of which the original role is deposited in this Office</p>
<p>In faith whereof I have herewith set my hand, and affixed the seal of this Department, this <date when="1861-09-02">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> day of September 1861</date></p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00011614">J. P. Benjamin</persName>
<lb/>Atty Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi></p>
<p><figure type="seal"/><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">No. 280-</hi></p>
<p>An Act making appropriation to aid the people of Kentucky -- The Congress of the Confederate States of America do enact That the sum of one Million of dollars be, and the same is, appropriated out of any money in the Treasury, not other wise appropriated, to be expended in such manner as the President may think proper, to aid the people of Kentucky in repelling any invasion, or occupation of their soil by the armed forces of the United States</p>
<p>Howell Cobb
<lb/>President of the Congress</p>
<p>Approved <date when="1861-08-31">August 31. 1861</date>
<lb/>Jefferson Davis</p>
<p>Confederate States of America
<lb/>Department of Justice</p>
<p>I do hereby certify that the foregoing is a true copy of an act of the congress of the Confederate States of America approved <date when="1861-08-31">August 3<hi rend="underline">0</hi><hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date> and of which the original role is deposited in this office</p>
<p>
<lb/>In faith whereof I have hereunto set my hand and affixed the seal of this Department this <date when="1861-09-02">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> September 1861</date></p>
<p>J. P. Benjamin
<lb/>Atty Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi></p>
<p><figure type="seal"/><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr Crockett moved that three thousand copies of the messsage and accompanying documents be immediately printed<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr E. M Bruce moved to amend said motion by making the number of copies Five thousand, instead of three thousand.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr Crockett moved the following resolution as a substitute for the original motion and amendment -- Towit -- 
<lb/>Resolved That the Clerk be instructed to furnish to the Editors of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011630">Courier</orgName> the Governors messsage and accompanying documents for publication, and that he negotiate with the Editors to furnish for distribution two thousand extra copies.
<lb/>Which was adopted -- <pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">39</note></p>
<p>Mr Crockett ^moved^ That the Governors message and accompanying documents this day presented to this Council be referred to the<orgName ref="cwgk:O00011357"> Committee on Foreign Relations</orgName> -- which motion prevailed<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The orders of the day were then taken up-
<lb/>The bill entitled "an Act regulating Currency" was ordered to be read a third time -- 
<lb/>On motion the rules of the Council Constitutional provisions and third reading were dispensed with-
<lb/>The question then being upon the passage of the bill- and being put was decided in the negative and so the bill was lost.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr Crockett moved a reconsideration of the vote by which the bill entitled "An Act regulating Currency" was lost- and the question being put was decided in the affirmative- and so the vote was reconsidered.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr E. M. Bruce then offered a substitute for the original bill the following Towit-</p>
<p>Be it enacted by the Council of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky that all sheriffs clerks and other collecting officers be and they are hereby authorized to receive Kentucky and <placeName ref="cwgk:P001001">Tennessee Bank</placeName> notes, Confederate notes, and all other Bank notes which are at par in the Confederate States in payment of all public dues -- 
<lb/>The question being upon the adoption of the substitute and being put was decided in the negative- and so the substitute was lost<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The question was then upon the passage of the original bill, and being put was decided in the affirmative- and so the bill passed
<lb/>Ordered That the title be as reported.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr Crockett from the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011358">Committee on the Judiciary</orgName> reported a bill entitled "An act concerning brokers- which had its first reading -- 
<lb/>Ordered that said bill be read a second time
<lb/>The rules of the Council constitutional provisions and second readings were dispensed with -- 
<lb/>Ordered That said bill be read a third time
<lb/>On Motion the rules of the Council Constitutional provision and third readings were dispensed with-
<lb/>The question was then upon the passage of the Bill and being taken was decided in the affirmative-
<lb/>And so the bill passed
<lb/>Ordered That the title be as reported<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">40</note></p>
<p>Mr Crockett from the same Committee reported a bill entitled "An act to license billiard or Jenny Lind tables and bowling Saloons"- which was read a first time.
<lb/>Ordered That said bill be read a second time
<lb/>On motion the rules of the Council constitutional provisions and second and third readings of the bill were dispensed with -- </p>
<p>The question there being upon the passage of the bill and being put was decided in the affirmative-
<lb/>And So the bill passed
<lb/>Ordered that the title be as reported.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>And then the Council adjourned until tomorrow at 10 O'Clock A. M.</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00001858">A. Frank Brown </persName>Clerk</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
