<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0004-033-0022"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, Journal</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG16320</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Louisville</settlement>
      <repository>Filson Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>Kentucky Confederate Provisional Government Journal</collection>
      <idno>p. 58-61</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-12-11">11 December 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Journal</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><hi rend="underline"><placeName ref="cwgk:P00000560">Bowling Green</placeName> <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800"> Ky</placeName>Bowling Green  </hi><placeName ref="cwgk:P001800"><hi rend="underline">Ky</hi></placeName>
    <lb/><hi rend="underline">Wednesday <date when="1861-12-11">December 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></hi></p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011019">Council </orgName>met. Hon<hi rend="sup">l</hi> <persName ref="cwgk:N00000832">W. B. Machen</persName> President in the chair.<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p>Mr <persName ref="cwgk:N00000846"><hi rend="underline">E. M. Bruce</hi> </persName>Chairman of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011356">Committee on Banks</orgName> reported a bill entitled an act supplemental to acts N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> <gap/> entitled an act appointing a Bank Commissioner to <placeName ref="cwgk:P00008174">Richmond</placeName> <placeName ref="cwgk:P001037">Virginia</placeName> &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>
<lb/>Said bill had its first reading
<lb/>Ordered That said bill be read a second time.
<lb/>On motion the rule of the Council, Constitutional provision and second readings were dispensed with.
<lb/>Mr <persName ref="cwgk:N00000843">H. W. Bruce</persName> offered the following amendment viz:
<lb/>Amend by striking out "all the" and inserting "squad" in the 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Section and second and third lines, from the bottom of said section, and strike out "if" and insert "with" in the second line from the bottom of said section."
<lb/>Which was adopted.
<lb/>Mr. E M Bruce offered the following amendment viz.
<lb/>"Amend section 1. by striking out the word "immediately" in Eighth line.
<lb/>And the question being on striking out it was decided in the affirmative<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00000852">Mr Bates</persName> moved that the further consideration of the bill be postponed until 2 O'Clock P. M. and the question being taken thereon it was decided in the affirmative.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>A message from the Governor by <persName ref="cwgk:N00011014">R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee</persName> Secretary of State:
<lb/>Mr President. I am directed by the Governor to lay before this Council a special message in writing -- viz:</p>
<p><orgName ref="cwgk:O00011543">Executive Office</orgName>
<lb/>Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-12-11">December 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>Hon<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> W. B. Machen
<lb/>President of the Council of the State of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I hereby nominate <persName ref="cwgk:N00011603">Henry J. Lyon</persName> a Commissioner under "an act entitled an act to regulate Banks Approved <date when="1861-12-10">December 10.<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>Very Resp.
<lb/>Your Obt Serv<hi rend="sup">t</hi>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N001002">George W. Johnson</persName><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>On motion the nomination of Henry J. Lyon as Bank Commissioner was unanimously confirmed<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">59</note>
<lb/>The bill reported by the committee for the benefit of common Schools was taken up.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr E. M Bruce moved that the further consideration of said bill be postponed until tomorrow at 10 <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">2</hi> O'Clock A. M. and that the same be made the special order for that hour- and said motion prevailed.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>On motion the resolutions, substitute and amendments in regard to the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011479">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Kentucky Regiment </orgName>was postponed until Friday next at 10 <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">2</hi> O'Clock A. M. and made the special order of the day for that hour.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The committee to whom was referred the communication of <persName ref="cwgk:N00011064">G. Malcom</persName> and the petion of <persName ref="cwgk:N00011612">N. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>C. Menifee</persName> reported as follows Towit.
<lb/>The Committee to whom was referred the petition of G. Malcom Report- that after duly considering the same and obtaining all the information they can on the subject proposed, have come to the conclusion, that it would be inexpedient to authorize the construction of the battery asked by the petitioner- They ask to be discharged from the further consideration of the subject</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00000853">Phil. B. Thompson</persName>
<lb/>Chairman -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The report of said committee in regard to the petition of N. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>C. Menifee is as follows Towit:</p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011355">Committee on military affairs</orgName> to whom was referred the letter of <persName ref="cwgk:N00011667">John M. Rice</persName> and others
<lb/>Report -- That at the present time they do not deem it good policy on the part of this Council to select particular persons to raise regiments for the use of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003448">Provisional Government</orgName>- The selection of any individual for such purpose implies a promise on the part of the Council that such person shall be appointed to the command of such force when raised- They deem it best that all regiments raised shall be raised under the authority of a general law -- this council reserving the right of appointment of all Officers, except company officers, and the right to form any companies into battalions, or regiments without reference to their having been raised for a particular battalion or regiment- They ask to be discharged from a further consideration of the subject</p>
<p>Phil. B. Thompson
<lb/>Chairman<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>and said Committee was discharged from a further consideration of the said matters contained in said reports -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>On motion of <persName ref="cwgk:N00000833">mr Crockett</persName> the Council then went into secret Session<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header"><unclear>60</unclear></note></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr Crockett</hi> obtained the unanimous consent of the Council to introduce a bill for the benefit of <persName ref="cwgk:N00006364">M M. Lyon</persName> of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002081">Lyon County</placeName><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The<orgName ref="cwgk:O00011356"> committee on Banks</orgName> presented a communication from <persName ref="cwgk:N00011628">G. C Torbutt</persName> President of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011629">Bank of Tennessee</orgName>, and others which was referred to said Committee.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr Crockett</hi> moved the following resolution Viz:
<lb/>Resolved That <hi rend="str">the</hi> it shall be the duty of the clerk of the Council to furnish to the public printer a synopsis of the acts passed by the Provisional Government except those ordered not to be published, and shall daily furnish an abstract of proceedings to be printed daily the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011630">Louisville Courier</orgName>. which was adopted -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>And then the Council took a recess until 3 O'Clock P M<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Evening Session</hi></p>
<p>The council took up the bill reported by E M. Bruce chairman of the Committee on Banks -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi><persName ref="cwgk:N00000852">Mr Bates</persName></hi> moved the previous question and the question being taken "shall the main question be now put" it was decided in the affirmative -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The question was then taken upon ordering said bill as amended to a third reading and being taken was decided in the negative -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr Thompson</hi> had the unanimous consent of the council to introduce a bill entitled "an act concerning corporations" which was read a first time -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Ordered that said bill be read a second time<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>On motion the rule of the council Constitutional provision and second readings were dispensed with<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Ordered That said bill be engrossed and referred to the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011358">Committee on the Judiciary</orgName><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>A message from the Governor by R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee secretary of State was received announcing his approval of 
<lb/>An act providing for the appointing of two or more commissioners to visit the counties in reference to sheriffs clerks and other civil officers -- <pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">61</note>
<lb/>Also the approval by the Governor of the bond of <persName ref="cwgk:N00011402">Josiah Pillsbury</persName> Auditor of state-
<lb/>said approval was confirmed by the Council.-
<lb/>And said bond ordered to be filed with the Secretary of State.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>And then the Council adjourned until tomorrow at 10'O'Clock A M.</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/><hi rend="underline"><persName ref="cwgk:N00001858">A. Frank Brown </persName>Clerk</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
