<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0004-033-0017"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, Journal</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG16315</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Sarah Haywood</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Louisville</settlement>
      <repository>Filson Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>Kentucky Confederate Provisional Government Journal</collection>
      <idno>p. 47-50</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-12-05">5 December 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Journal</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">47</note></p>
<p>Council Chamber  <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000560">Bowling Green</placeName> Ky<date when="1861-12-05"><hi rend="underline">December</hi> <hi rend="underline">5</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> <hi rend="underline">1861</hi></date></p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011019">Council</orgName> met pursuant to adjournment<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000832">W. B. Machen</persName> President in the chair<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p><hi rend="underline">S. S. Scott</hi> member of the Council from the tenth Congressional district, appointed to fill the vacany occasioned by the resignation of <persName ref="cwgk:N00000844">George B. Hodge</persName>, appeared, and the President having administered to him the oath prescribed by law, took his seat<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p><hi rend="underline"><persName ref="cwgk:N00000833">Mr Crockett</persName></hi> from the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011358">Committee on the Judiciary</orgName> reported a bill entitled "An authorizing the appointment of a commissioner to settle with the collecting Officers of this State" which was read a first time.
<lb/>Ordered That said bill be read a second time
<lb/>On Motion the rules of the Council Constitutional provisions and second and third readings were dispensed with.
<lb/>The question then being upon the passage of the bill and being put was decided in the affirmative
<lb/>And so the bill passed
<lb/>Ordered That the title be as reported<figure type="hr"/><pb/>
<lb/><note place="header"><unclear>48</unclear></note></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr Crockett</hi> from the Committee on the Judiciary also reported a bill entitled -- 
<lb/>An act fixing the fees of the Clerk in certain cases" which was read a first time-
<lb/>Ordered That said bill be read a second time.
<lb/>On motion, the rules of the Council, Constitutional provision and second and third readings of the bill were dispensed with and the same being engrossed,
<lb/>The question was then taken on the passage of said bill, and it was decided in the affirmative -- 
<lb/>And so the bill passed
<lb/>Ordered That the title thereof be as reported.<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p>A message from the Governor by <persName ref="cwgk:N00011014">R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee</persName> Secretary of state:</p>
<p>Mr President: I am directed by the Governor to lay before this Council a special message in writing:</p>
<p>Executive Office
<lb/>Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-12-05">December 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>W. B. Machen Esq
 <lb/>President of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011019">Council of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky</orgName> Sir.</p>
<p>The Sheriff of this County after full conference with me, has concluded to offer no resistance to the will of the Provisional Government, and to comply with its demands of a settlement and payment over to our Treasurer of all monies, now in his hands, and wishes some one appointed to investigate his accounts, and thinks that the Provisional Government should make its demand of him in writing for his books &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi> He expressed great reluctance to assuming this position, but thought it due to his sureties.</p>
   <p>In view of this fact I nominate <persName ref="cwgk:N00011623">Lewis W. Potter</persName> of this county as Sheriff thereof</p>
   <p><persName ref="cwgk:N001002">George W. Johnson</persName>
<lb/>Provisional Governor<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p>On Motion of <persName ref="cwgk:N00000843">H. W. Bruce</persName> the name of <persName ref="cwgk:N00000847">J. W. Moore</persName> was added to the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011357">Committee on Foreign Relation</orgName>s in place of Geo. B. Hodge.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The committee on the Judiciary reported a bill entitled "an act to amend an act entitled an act to regulate the currency."
<lb/>Which was read a first time-
<lb/>Ordered That said bill be read a second time.
<lb/>On motion the rule of the Council Constitutional provision and second and third readings were dispensed with -- and the same being engrossed.
<lb/>The question was taken on the passage of said bill and it was decided in the affirmative -- <pb/>
<lb/><note place="header"><unclear>49</unclear></note>
<lb/>And so the bill passed.
<lb/>Ordered that the title be as reported.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr H. W Bruce</hi> had the unanimous consent of the council to introduce a bill to repeal section 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> of Chapter 61 of the Revised Statutes. and thereupon said bill was introduced and read a first time
<lb/>Ordered That said bill be read a second time-
<lb/>On Motion the rule of the Council, Constitutional provision and second &amp; third readings of said bill were dispensed with -- and the same being engrossed.
<lb/>The question was taken on the passage of said bill and it was decided in the affirmative -- and so the bill passed.
<lb/>Ordered That the title be as reported<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr Crockett</hi> moved that the Council do now go into secret session -- and the question being taken thereon it was decided in the affirmative-
<lb/>And then the Council went into secret Session.<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p>Mr Crockett moved to reconsider the vote of yesterday by which the bill entitled "An act to enlarge the powers of the Commissioners to the Government of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003030">Confederate States of America</orgName>" was passed.<figure type="hr"/></p>
   <p> <persName ref="cwgk:N00000852">Mr Bates</persName> moved to lay the motion to reconsider on the table- and before the question was taken thereon leave was granted to withdraw the same.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr Crockett</hi> then moved the previous question on the motion to reconsider which was seconded.
<lb/>And the vote being taken "shall the main question be now put" it was decided in the affirmative
<lb/>The question was then taken upon the motion to reconsider and it was decided in the negative
<lb/>The yeas and nays having been required thereon by Messrs Crockett and H. W. Bruce were as follows. viz:
<lb/>Those who voted in the affirmative were messrs
<lb/>J. P. Bates
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000846">E. M Bruce</persName>. 2<lb/>Those who voted in the negative were
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Mr President.
<lb/>H. W. Bruce
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. W. Crockett
<lb/>S. S Scott
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00011020">J. P. Burnside</persName> 5.<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr E. M. Bruce from the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011356">Committee on Banks</orgName> reported a bill entitled "An act to regulate Banks" which was read a first time<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header"><unclear>50</unclear></note>
<lb/>Ordered that said bill be read a second time
<lb/>On motion the rule of the Council constitutional provision and second <hi rend="str">and</hi> <hi rend="str">third</hi> readings of the bill were dispensed with -- 
<lb/><hi rend="str">The question was then taken on the passage of the bill, and it was decided in the affirmative -- 
<lb/>And so the bill passed
<lb/>Ordered that the title be as reported.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr <gap/> Bruce</hi> moved to fill up by inserting in the blank where it occurs the words "twenty five thousand" and the question being taken thereon it was decided in the affirmative.</p>
   <p><hi rend="underline">Mr <gap/> Moved</hi> further to strike out the words "Other than the citizens of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Kentucky</placeName>" and insert in lieue thereof the words "who are citizens of the non-slaveholding States of the <placeName ref="cwgk:P001802">Old United States of America</placeName>" and the question being taken thereon it was decided in the affirmative.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Ordered that said bill as amended be engrossed and read a third time.
<lb/>On motion the rule of the Council, Constitutional provision and third reading be dispensed with.
<lb/>The question was then taken on the passage of the bill and it was decided in the affirmative, and so the bill passed.
<lb/>Ordered that the title be as reported<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The chairman of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011361">Committee on enrollments</orgName> reported that they had examined enrolled bill entitled<lb/>An act to regulate banks
<lb/>And had found the same truly enrolled, and thereupon the President affixed his signature thereto</p>
<p>And then the Council until tomorrow at 10 O'Clock A. M.</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/> Clerk<persName ref="cwgk:N00001858">A. Frank Brown</persName></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
