<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0377"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. S. Rankin to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4496</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Kristen Bailey</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-99 to BR9-100</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Williamstown, Grant County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-01">1 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><placeName ref="cwgk:P00002296">Williamstown</placeName>
<lb/><date when="1863-12-01">Dec 1 -- 1863</date>
<lb/>Hon <persName ref="cwgk:N001000">Thos E Brambet</persName>
<lb/>Gover. of <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Kentucky</orgName>
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Enclosed is the petition of <persName ref="cwgk:N00012601">John Marques </persName>of this <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000938">county</placeName> which explains itself. I will add that the facts are I believe correctly stated, but not so fully as they might have been <persName ref="cwgk:N00012530">John Neal</persName> is his son in law, lived near the line betwene <placeName ref="cwgk:P001030">Scott </placeName>&amp; Grant -- There was a great nest of theives in his neighborhood that annoyd&gt; the people greatly -- Neal was accused of being one of the theives -- was tried with a number of others &amp; held to bail by a court of inquiry -- Marques was his bail -- <pb/></p>
<p>After the trial a company of citizens mostly Home guards &amp; mostly <hi rend="underline">good citizens</hi> held a meeting &amp; resolved that John Neal should leave ^the^ neighborhood together with his brother <persName ref="cwgk:N00012615">Thomas Neal</persName> &amp; others or they would hang them. Neal was notified &amp; left &amp; has never returned -- now as I am informed lives out of the State -- I believe in <placeName ref="cwgk:P001818">Ia</placeName> -- The others left also -- The stealing had no connection with the rebelion the Neals being loyal <orgName ref="cwgk:O00002945">Union </orgName>men &amp; prosecuted in part by the best Union men in the country -- Neal is a bad man but is gone -- I was prosecuting him &amp; know what I write is true -- Marques <hi rend="underline">gets drunk</hi> -- but is an industrious peaceable old man -- is loyal -- owns 200 acres of poor bushy hill land &amp; nothing more<pb/>
<lb/>has a host of grandchildren to support -- the family of <persName ref="cwgk:N00012602">one son</persName> who has been in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00001186">Federal army</orgName> since <date when="1861">1861</date> -- being of the number -- He is truly &amp; actively loyal &amp; c &amp; except his disapition is a harmless citizen -- is old &amp; infirm &amp; will be ruined -- utterly ruined -- if he has this Judgt to pay. I therefor earnestly write in asking that you remit it all except officers fees &amp;c If desired he will try to get Neal &amp; have him tried although he is his son in law -- </p>
<p>Truly &amp;c <persName ref="cwgk:N00000208">W S Rankin</persName></p>
<p>His land is to be sold on the <date when="1863-12-14">14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> -- inst -- </date> <persName ref="cwgk:N00002277">Mr Scott</persName> is the comwlths atty -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
