<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-007-0638"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Robert P. Dechert to W. T. Ward</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2303</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Charles R. Welsko</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Appointments by the Governor, Civil Appointments, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR3-47</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Philadelphia, Philadelphia County, Pennsylvania</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-25">25 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>209 So: 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> St -- 
<lb/>Phila Pa: <date when="1865-11-25">Nov 25, 1865</date>
<lb/>My Dear General.</p>
<p>I regret to trouble you in a matter of purely a personal nature, -- but I desire to procure the appointment i<hi rend="str">f</hi>n this State, of Commissioner for the Acknowledgement of Deeds &amp;c, for the State of Kentucky. In some of the States, the <hi rend="underline">number</hi> of appointments by the Gov: is not limited by law, -- and I supposed that such might be the case in your State. -- I think a recommendation from yourself, to Gov: Bramlette as the qualifications &amp;c would be all that would be necessary. I am pursuing the study of the law, but am not yet admitted to practice, -- and should the laws of Kentucky, require a Commissioner to be an attorney, I would not be qualified.<pb/></p>
<p>Should you think proper to send to Gov. Bramlette, such a recommendation, with my address in Phila, I shall esteem it a personal favor, and will be greatly indebted.</p>
<p>I hope that you continue to enjoy good health..</p>
<p>Very Truly
<lb/>Your Friend,
<lb/>Robt P. Dechert
<lb/>late Bvt Lieut -- Col. U S. V.
<lb/>Army of Geog.</p>
<p>Gen'l W. T. Ward
<lb/>Kentucky.</p>
<p>Louisville Ky <date when="1865-01-05">Jan. 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 65</date></p>
<p>E. L. Vanwinkle sec of state the writer of this letter is well known to me being adjutant on the staff of our Corps Commander during the Atalanta Savannah &amp; Raleigh campaigns he is a fine business <hi rend="underline">man</hi> a gentleman &amp; a scholar. I therefore hope the Governor will give him the appointment he asks</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W. T. Ward</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>