<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1720"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. R. Bolling et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11188</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-35 to MG23-36</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-03-07">7 March 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency, Beriah Magoffin, Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </p>
<p>Your Petitioner, R. R. Bowling, would most respectfully state to Your Excellency; that, at <date when="1861-08">August term 1861</date> of the Marion Circuit Court of Kentucky a judgement was rendered in favor of the Commonwealth of Ky., and against your Petitioner, for the sum of five hundred -- dollars on a forfeited recognizance, executed by your Petitioner's brother, J. P. M. Bowling, and your Petitioner, as his surety -- Your Petitioner's brother, J. P. M. Bowling, was charged with larceny and Robbery. Your Petitioner has learned that the whole case was: that his brother, in a drunken frolic with some neighbour boys, broke open a Dutch pedlers waggen &amp; took out some of his goods and by <hi rend="underline">way</hi> <hi rend="underline">of</hi> <hi rend="underline">develing</hi> <hi rend="underline">him</hi>, took some off and hid them, but they were <hi rend="underline">all</hi> <hi rend="underline">restored</hi> to him, and besides he was compensated for the damage done to his waggen &amp; otherwise and the pedler <hi rend="underline">expressed</hi> <hi rend="underline">himself</hi> <hi rend="underline">satisfied</hi>, and would have gone off but some medlesome persons in the neighbourhood, told the Pedler if he did not have them up &amp; prosecute them for the act, he would be prosceuted himself, &amp; hence he went and informed the authorities, and the arrest ensued and after the trial before the Court of Enquiry the Dutch Pedler slipped off and was not recognised, and Bowling learning that fact, went off too, supposing the<pb/>
<lb/>the case was ended; and that is the cause of the forfeited recognizance. Now, your Petitioner would state, that he has not property enough to pay the Five hundred dollars take ^nearly^ every thing he has, and that he has not friends or relatives from whom he could get it, nor has he a salary that more than barely supports his family. In view of all these things, no one will be injured, &amp; no one <hi rend="underline">has</hi> <hi rend="underline">been</hi> i<hi rend="underline">njured</hi> if the bond is never paid but if payment is forced Your petitioner is ruined pecuniarily; therefore Your Petitioner prays a remission of the judgement</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Your Obt Svt
<lb/>R. R. Bolling</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by R. R. Bolling, <date when="1862-03-07">March 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date></p>
<p>W Franklin, Examiner
<lb/>Franklin Co.</p>
<p>We the undersigned most heartily join in the prayer of this petition John F Fisk</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/> E Gabbert
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> J Heady
<lb/>C, T, Worthington
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Alf Seen
<lb/></hi>Rich<hi rend="sup">d</hi> A Buckner
<lb/>J F Robinson
<lb/>James Speed
<lb/>J. R. <hi rend="underline">Thomas
<lb/></hi>Grant Green
<lb/><cb n="2"/>R T. Baker
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J F Bell</hi>
<lb/>J H Harney 
<lb/>William Johnson
<lb/>A. P. Grocer
<lb/>T. F. Marshall
<lb/><cb n="3"/>R. J. Browne
<lb/>Nat Wolfe
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Jno W Finnell</hi>
<lb/>J A Prall
<lb/>B Spalding 
<lb/>Zeb Ward
<lb/><hi rend="underline">T T Alexander</hi><pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Marion Cir Ct
<lb/>&#36;500 &#125; Recog.
<lb/>R R Bolling</p>
<p>Remission Is<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-03-10">Mar 10. 1862</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>