<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1652"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Cutburth to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11120</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-314 to MG22-315</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Whitley County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-01-30">30 January 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the excelence of Beria Magoffin 
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner James Cutburth wold Respectifull Represent to your exelence that at the <date when="1862-01">January term of the Whitley Quarterly ^courte^ 1862</date> that they was a warret Returned against him for Keeping a tipling hous and that a judgment was Render against <hi rend="str">the</hi> your petitioner for the sum of &#36;60,, Your petitioner states that he had ben a tavern Keeper for some time and that a few day's previous to <hi rend="str">the Whitley</hi> his licens had expired he states that he had no intention of violating the law and you petitioner state that he is a pore man and <hi rend="str">has</hi> if he has to pay said fine that <hi rend="str">he</hi> it will put him in greate troble and cause him to sacefise his property he states that it will be a mater of greate charity to Remit said fine he prays your <hi rend="str">Petitioner</hi> excelence to Remit said fine and for all proper Releaf</p>
<p>James Cutburth</p>
<p>James Cutburth says he beleaves the statements, in the foregoing petition he beleaves to be true</p>
<p>James Cutbirth
<lb/> 
<lb/>Sworn to before me by James Cutbirth this the <date when="1862-01-30">30 day of January 1862</date>
<lb/>L D Sutton P J W C<pb/></p>
<p>The under signed says that they believe that it wold be a <hi rend="str">mater</hi> ^act^ of charity to Remit said fine </p>
<p>John Smith</p>
<p>J. C. Foley
<lb/>william <unclear>peablr</unclear>
<lb/>W. H. Wilson
<lb/>D H Leforce
<lb/>James M Siler
<lb/>S P Braunn
<lb/>A. C. King
<lb/>A F. Campbell
<lb/>Samuel Denham
<lb/>H. S. Tye
<lb/>W G Tye</p>
<p>I believe you would be doing nothing wrong by remitting the within fine and that your course in so doing would be endorsed by this community</p>
<p>B. Boyd<pb/></p>
<p>Remitted 
<lb/>B. M. </p>
<p>Remission <hi rend="underline">made out</hi> <date when="1862-03-06">March 6" 1862</date> N G,
<lb/> 
<lb/>&#36;60.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>