<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-022-0076"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Burgess Preston to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG12001</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Natalie Smith</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>37th - 76th Regiments Enrolled Militia Primary Source Documents (1861-1866)</collection>
      <idno>Box 81, Folder 65th Regiment 1864-1910 Correspondences</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paintsville, Johnson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08-05">5 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Head Quarters <orgName ref="cwgk:O00006283">65<hi rend="sup">th</hi> <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Kentucky</placeName><lb/>Enrold Militia</orgName>
    <lb/><placeName ref="cwgk:P00006284">Paintsville</placeName> <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002566">Johnson Co, Ky</placeName><lb/><date when="1864-08-05">August 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>To his Excencley <persName ref="cwgk:N001000">Thomas E Bramlit</persName> Gavoner of the State of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Kentucky</placeName></p>
   <p>In obedieance to your order ordering me to make acompany of active Militia I am indevering to make the company and have detailed one hundred &amp; one men and have Fifty Five in Camp in Paintsville and have put Lieu<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Col <persName ref="cwgk:N00006287">G. W. Brown</persName> in Command he being the best driled man and I think the most campatant in my Reidgmment and Recamend that he be Commissioned as Captain of the Company and have appointed <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi><persName ref="cwgk:N00006288">E. H. Walker</persName> First Lieutenant <persName ref="cwgk:N00006289"><hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>C. G. <unclear>Rule</unclear></persName> second Lieutenant and <persName ref="cwgk:N00006914">John Turner</persName> Third Lieutenant and Recammend that they be commissioned if it is leagal for me to appoint the officier I made an effort to make the company by volunteers but could not get more than five or six I then made the detail by ballet out of the sevral Companeys in the Reidgment on the <date when="1864-08-03"><hi rend="str">2</hi>3<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of this instant</date> we are <hi rend="str">subsisten</hi> gitting our subsistance from the country have about 45 guns 10 enfield a few shot guns and the balance old guns that the Rebles left Scaturd about in the country I have vary litle amunition only a litle I got from the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00001186">united States Troops</orgName> at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000553">Louisa</placeName></p>
<p>We have a bad chance of infermation here have no Mail to this plase the nerist is<pb/>
<lb/>to Louisa which is 32, miles I have no regulations nor nothing to govern me in my duty in organinzeing the company I tharefore desire all the information from you that ^you^ can give me. as it respects the org<hi rend="str">i</hi>anization of the Company and ^how^ they are to be armed &amp; Equipted &amp; clothed and furnished with subsistence &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Thare is a good meny Reble Gerrillars in this country and I think the company might be in agratdeal of danger in the camp without being beter armed tharefore desire that I heare from you imeadatly,,</p>
   <p>The office of Captain in Company <hi rend="str">became Vacant</hi>, B, having became Vacant I had an election heldd in said company on the <date when="1864-08-03">3<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of this instant</date> and <persName ref="cwgk:N00006915">John S. Miller</persName> wase elected Captain an <persName ref="cwgk:N00006916">Jessey Murry</persName> Third Lieutenant in same company Co, C, <persName ref="cwgk:N00006990">John Hilman</persName> First Lieutenant Co, E, <persName ref="cwgk:N00006991">Nathaniel P Simer</persName> wase elected Captain <persName ref="cwgk:N00006992">William Vanhoose</persName> First Lieutenant &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00007750">Asey J Fairchild</persName> secand Lieutenant -- </p>
<p>The gurillar <persName ref="cwgk:N00007751">Sidney Coop</persName> made a rade in Paintsville on the night of the <date when="1864-07-16">16 July</date> ^with about fifty men^ and Robed the storse <hi rend="str">with about fifty men</hi> and the shrriffe caled on me and I ordered <hi rend="str">me</hi> my Ridgment in and had to send to Louisa for amunition and hunt up <hi rend="str">the</hi> guns from the country and started in pursuit<pb/>
<lb/>of the thievs on the <date when="1864-07-23">23<hi rend="sup">th</hi></date> about 5 ock P, M, and marched about 15 miles that night the next day pursued on within 7 Miles of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00005290">West liberty</placeName> and run him out which is about 35 miles from here took several prisoners but coud not git evidance against but one <hi rend="str">who</hi> he belonged to the band I sent him to Louisa and turned him over to the united States. forces</p>
<p>I had Seventy Five men with me I went in persan G, W, Brown Lt Col &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00007752">W. W. House</persName> Adjt wase in the scout with me</p>
   <p>At the Election on the <date when="1864-08-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> instant</date> thare wase apole assssed at apart of the voting precients for <hi rend="str">Col</hi> Colonel and Lieutenant Colonel and one <persName ref="cwgk:N00007753">M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Auxier</persName> wase poled for Colonel &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00007996">C. C. Price</persName> for Lieutenant Colonel and having no <unclear/> wase Elected the peple no agenral thing in this county did not under stand that that wase the time for Electing a Colonel &amp; Lieut Clonel if it had bin so under stood they could have Elected A loyal Man to have <hi rend="str">to</hi> filed them officers, and I think thare is genral ^dis^satisfaction</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00007997">Burges Preston</persName><lb/>Col Comdg, 65, Ky, E, M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
