<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0003-092-0121"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Johnson to Ann E. V. Johnson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14413</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Jesse Nasta</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>George W. Johnson Papers</collection>
      <idno>Folder 5</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-02-15">15 February 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><placeName ref="cwgk:P00000560">Bowling Green Ky
</placeName><lb/><date when="1862-02-15">Feb. 15, 1862</date>
<lb/>My most belov<hi rend="str">d</hi>ed, my <persName ref="cwgk:N00008172">Dear Wife</persName></p>
<p>The time of our severest afflictions, has now come, -- Our State is about to be abandoned by our armies -- a disaster caused by the Defeat of <persName ref="cwgk:N00007029">Crittenden</persName> and the surrender of <persName ref="cwgk:N00001266">Tillman</persName>. We stood in the presence of the enemy outnumbering us 3 and four to one, hoping that they would give us battle at Bowling Green. But they determined to turn our flanks both to the right and left, and had men enough to outnumber us greatly on both. <persName ref="cwgk:N00008199">Genl Johnston</persName> had ordered that his right flank should not cross <geogName ref="cwgk:G00006218">the Cumberland</geogName> but carried away by their ardour they violated his command, hoping to overwhelm <persName ref="cwgk:N00005245">Thomas</persName> -- He was reinforced the night before and our soldiers, wet, hungry, cold, wearied and without sleep, met a disastrous defeat. On his left <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>Tillman had command of Ft. Henry on the Tennessee. He was in my opinion incompetent -- I had months tried every plan to have him removed, and foresaw &amp; predicted our disaster. He had once before prevented <hi rend="underline">our advance</hi>. when stationed at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002431">Hopkinsville</placeName>, by telegraphing that an enemy of 10.000 were advancing on him &amp; that he had, only 500 effective men and must retreat -- If this vain &amp; impotent fellow had never been in command we now have held the heights of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000936">Covington</placeName>.</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Tell my Children not to complain because their names are not in this letter -- They are always in my heart and my affection -- </note></p>
<p>I now go with the army and intend<pb/>
<lb/>to remain constantly in the Field, and expect my he<hi rend="str">l</hi>alth to improve instead of falling off We will soon be ready to return -- The south has now waked up. Before they would believe that a Southern army however weak could be driven back. and would do nothing in spite of Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Johnston's remonstrances. Perhaps even these defeats were necessary to make the South willing to an honourable peace, upon the basis of Southern Independence and reciprocal free Trade. If <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>they have this effect, our disaster will be valuable to us.</p>
   <p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003030">Southern confederacy</orgName> have placed at my disposal millions of dollars, for our military purposes. and I have been highly honoured with their confidence, I do not intend that one dollar shall be misapplied, but I will Spend it as water, in the cause of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Ky</placeName>'s independance.</p>
   <p>I write this to you, my dear, my beloved wife, because <persName ref="cwgk:N00008220">M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Shower</persName>, who has boarded at the same house with me all this time since the Russelville Convention, will go to see you, and will tell you &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00008221">M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Breckenridge</persName> every thing personal.</p>
<p>Can you Spare <persName ref="cwgk:N00008215">Junius</persName>? If, you can give him up to his country I think God will bless you and him for it. It is right in itself and when he grows old he will love to think that he too did something in the field for our glorious Revolution I have a Cadet-ship for him in the army worth 40$ per month, and as From my intimacy with the commanders here, I can<pb/>
<lb/>attach him to some one, whose age &amp; character will keep him straight. I also can have an eye over him. If the war closes soon, then he will finish his education as a cadet in the Military Accademy which they design establishing. Can you then spare him? Can you have faith, my beloved, to support you in this additional trial? Can you put your faith in God, and give up your Son to his country? I have thought of it for some months before I could make up my mind to ask you, to make this additional sacrifice for your country. I now do it, because I am convinced it should be, and that God himself will reward us for it. When we meet again, I never will part with for more than a day -- never -- and many days of happiness, I am satisfied are before us -- </p>
<p><note place="left margin">Let Junius if you consent come out with Mr Shower I hope he will get him through.</note></p>
   <p>When the enemy were threatening <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000336">Glasgow</placeName>, the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003448">Council</orgName> directed me to remove the assets, Books and Money <orgName ref="cwgk:O00008223">the Bank at that place</orgName>. It is a branch of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00002742">Northern Bank</orgName>. I did so, in obedience to their order and sealed up <hi rend="underline">every</hi> <hi rend="underline">thing</hi> and deposited it in <orgName ref="cwgk:O00008222">the Bank at Bowling Green</orgName>. where it still is. I <hi rend="str">wrote</hi> sent word to them that I wished them to select an agent and send him to Bowling Green to take charge of every thing belonging to the bank, but they would not do so<pb/>
<lb/>but preferred to harass me with a suit, as I am informed by <persName ref="cwgk:N00008176">Madison</persName>. I have turned over this bank and the others, from my control, because although by Confederate law we claim, all the State stock and that of alien enemies, yet as we are not now in a situation to examine and decide who are alien enemies, rather than do injustice to the innocent we forego the clearest Belligerent Rights for the present</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00008219">Mr Calvert</persName> the ca<hi rend="str">ss</hi>shier of the Br. Bank of Ky at Bowling Green holds these assets of Glasgow Bank and has my orders to restore them to the President &amp; Directors of the Glasglow Bank. Madison can use this information if he chooses in my defence &amp; <hi rend="str">w</hi>I will not notice a suit in a court which I consider illegal -- </p>
<p>Yours till death <persName ref="cwgk:N001002">Geo. W Johnson</persName></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
