<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-079-0024"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas E. Bramlette, First Lieutenant, J. W. Boyd</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14023</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>AaronMPhillips</name>
</respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
</respStmt>


   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Enrolled Militia Records 1864 - 1865 ; Adair, Allen, Boyle, Daviess, Garrard, Owen, Pendleton, and Shelby counties</collection>
      <idno>Flat Box 7</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08-03">3 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Commission/Appointment</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>IN THE NAME AND BY THE AUTHORITY OF
<lb/>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Commonwealth of Kentucky</orgName>,
<lb/><figure type="seal"><ab>KENTUCKY
<lb/>UNITED WE STAND DIVIDED WE FALL</ab></figure>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N001000">THOMAS E. BRAMLETTE</persName>,
<lb/>GOVERNOR OF SAID COMMONWEALTH.
<lb/>To all whom these Presents shall come, Greeting:</p>
<p>Know Ye, That <persName ref="cwgk:N00013839">J. W. Boyd</persName> having been duly elected to the office of
<lb/>First Lieutenant <placeName ref="cwgk:P001811">Daviess County</placeName> <orgName ref="cwgk:O00013841">Militia Rangers</orgName>
<lb/>In the <gap/> Regiment of <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000303">Kentucky State Guard </orgName>organized under the Acts of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000923">General Assembly of the Commonwealth</orgName>:</p>
<p>NOW KNOW YOU, That, by the powers vested in me by the Constitution and Laws of said State, and reposing special trust and confidence in your patriotism, valor, fidelity, and ability, I do, by these presents Commission you as 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> Lieutenant as aforsaid, for the term <hi rend="str">prescribed by law</hi> ^six months^ unless sooner discharged, upon condition that you take the oath indorsed hereon, within ten days from receipt hereof, sending a certificate thereof to General Headquarters; and I do hereby authorize and require you to discharge, all and singular, the duties and services appertaining to your said office, agreeably to law and general regulations, and to obey such orders and instructions as you shall, from time to time, receive from your superior officers.</p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>SEAL OF KENTUCKY.
<lb/>UNITED WE STAND, DIVIDED WE FALL.</ab></figure></p>
<p>In Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto set my name, and caused the seal of the State of Kentucky to be affixed, at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000308">Frankfort</placeName>, the <date when="1864-08-03">third day of August, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and sixty=four</date> and in the seventy=fourth year of the Commonwealth.</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>BY THE GOVERNOR:
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N001777">E. L. VanWinkle</persName>, <hi rend="italic">Secretary of State</hi>.
<lb/>By <persName ref="cwgk:N001778">Jas R. Page</persName> 
<lb/>Asst Secty</p>
<p>Commonwealth Office -- <persName ref="cwgk:N00002718">WM. E. HUGHES</persName>, State Printer.<pb/></p>
<p>OATH.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>I do solemnly swear, that I will support the Constitution of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00002945">United States</orgName> and the Constitution of this State, and be faithful and true to the Commonwealth of Kentucky, so long as I continue a citizen thereof, and that I will faithfully execute, to the best of my abilities, the office of First Lieutenant according to law; and I do further solemnly swear, that since the adoption of the present Constitution, I being a citizen of this State, have not fought a duel with deadly weapons, within this State nor out of it, with a citizen of this State; nor have I sent or accepted a challenge to fight a duel with deadly weapons, with a citizen of this State; nor have I acted a second in carrying a challenge, or aided or assisted any person thus offending -- so help me God.</p>
<p>John W Boyd</p>
<p><hi rend="italic">Subscribed and sworn to before me, a Justice of the Peace for</hi> <placeName ref="cwgk:P001019">Franklin <hi>County</hi></placeName><hi>, <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Kentucky</placeName>, this</hi> <date when="1864-08-10">10th <hi rend="italic">day of</hi> August, <hi rend="italic">186</hi>4</date>.</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00002995">Geo W. Gwin</persName>
<lb/><hi rend="italic">Justice of the Peace</hi>.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>I hereby tender my Resignation of the within commisssion <date when="1864-10-20">October 20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date></p>
<p>John W Boyd</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
