<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0321"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. S. Kimberly to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4440</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Sarah Haywood</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>AaronMPhillips</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-17 to BR9-18</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Foster, Bracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-03">3 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><placeName ref="cwgk:P00008058">Foster K.y</placeName> <date when="1863-11-03">Nov" 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> 1863</date>
    <lb/>Hon <persName ref="cwgk:N001000">Govenor K.y.</persName></p>
<p>Dear Sir I have Just received your notice granting me a respite for twelve months on the payment of a fine of $200"\" assessed against me at the <date when="--08">August term</date> of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000347">Bracken Circuit Court</orgName>. for which allow me to express my thanks, and while I am sincerely thankful for your mediation thus far in my behalf allow me to say that I had hoped from the Statements of my case made you by my Neighbors in their Petition that you would have remitted entirely " So much of it as the power vested in you would permit</p>
<p>My case is a hard one, and I hope you will indulge me while I make you a true Statement of the case</p>
<p>The first day of <date when="1861-10-01">October 1861</date> I Bought a <orgName ref="cwgk:O00012358">Blacksmith Shop</orgName> and lot in this place divided then as well as now into three Apartments a Blacksmith Shop a waggon makers Shop and a grocery room, The Grocery room being a lower or basement room of the waggon shop being a Black -- Smith by trade I have occupied the Blacksmith shope myself ever since I owned it the other two rooms I have rented especialy the Grocery room which I can here positively State has never been under my control only as rented one whole day from the <date when="1861-10-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of <hi rend="underline">Oct</hi> 1861</date> to the <date when="1863-02-15">15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of <hi rend="underline">Feb</hi> 1863</date> and as this is where the gameing should have occured for which I was fined I call your attention particularly to this statement<pb/>
<lb/>the Truth of which I hold Articles of Agreement to prove,, the rentals being according to dates as follows. first,, from the <date when="1861-10-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> of <hi rend="underline">oct</hi> 1861</date> to the <date when="1862-01-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> of <hi rend="underline">Jan</hi> 1862</date> ^To <persName ref="cwgk:N00012355">V Metzger</persName>^. Second,, from the <date when="1862-01-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> of <hi rend="underline">Jan</hi> 1862</date> to the <date when="1862-03-10">10<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> of March 1862</date> ^To <persName ref="cwgk:N00006642">S. P. Shafer</persName>^. 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> from the <date when="1862-03-10">10<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of Mar 1862</date> to the <date when="1862-12-12">12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> December 1862</date> ^To V Metzger^. 4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> from the <date when="1861-12-12">12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> December 1862</date> to the <date when="1863-02-15">15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of February 1863</date> ^To <persName ref="cwgk:N00008059">B, F, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Gill</persName>^.</p>
<p>The prosicuting witness (for there was only one that knew or pretended to know any thing about the case. and he lived in <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000544">Pendleton county</placeName> at the time these things should have transpired) swore that on a blank day of <date when="1862-09">September 1862</date> he saw three several games of cards played in this room for cakes and wine,, that he saw nothing else staked and would not swear to seeing more than 3 games played, upon cross examination he swore that at the time of the gameing a man by the name of M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Gill was attending to the Business of the house but that I was the proprietor which he proposed to Know from a certain conversation which he heard between M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Gill and I, in which he heard me tell M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Gill to make me an offer to give or take for the stock in trade but further stated that he did not hear the begining or the end of the conversation,</p>
<p>that any such conversation between M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Gill and I ever took place as regards any stock or trade held jointly between us I emphatically Deny as I never held any stock in any such trade either with M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Gill or any other man</p>
<p>the only evidence which I could Bring to be of any avail was my Articles of Agreement<pb/>
<lb/>only one of which my lawyer used and that being the being the Article between M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Gill and I which only covered time from the <date when="1862-12-12">12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of December 1862</date> to the <date when="1863-02-15">15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of <hi rend="underline">Feb</hi> 1863</date>, and my lawyer failing to use the Article covering time prior to the <date when="1862-12-13">13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> December 1862</date>,, (as you can see on page 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi>) Thereby failing to meet the vidence upon which grounds the Jury gave its verdict</p>
<p>It can be plainly seen that the witness contradicts his own evidence else my statement <hi rend="str">contradicts</hi> is incorrect with regard to the rentals and dates but I can establish the correctness of my statements by the rentors as well as other substantial evidence so that his evidence stating that M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Gill was attending to business there in <date when="--09">september</date> is incorrect for M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Gill had nothing to do with the premises untill the <date when="1861-12-12">12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of December</date> after the same having been under the control and possession of V Metzger for several months prior to the <date when="1861-12-12">12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of December 1862</date></p>
<p>all of which as I stated I can prove by the best of evidence which I think proves to a demonstration that I had no control or possession of the property when these things should have occured</p>
<p>and now allow me to hope that your Honor will again take this matter under consideration and that you may yet be induced by this statement Backed by the vidence of my Neighbors which you have in their petition to remit instead of Respite for twelve mo<hi rend="sup">n</hi>ths and in thus asking you to remit the fine altogether I<pb/>
<lb/>Know that I ask you to do no wrong neither would I rather than ask you to do an injustice I would permit the last cent of my property to go</p>
<p>it is True I am a poor man. That I have to work hard throug These hard Times to make my family a comfortable though homely living and I would fain hope that my family might have the enjoyment of my hard earnings But as for me I care not for hardships, give me to know that I have done right, that I have wronged no man, that I have earned my living by the sweat of my brow,</p>
<p>let me Know that I have done the thing that is right and that I have done it like a man. and I will Trust to God to Truth and to the people fo my vindication and now again hoping for the sake of Justice and my Family that you will take the matter again under your consideration and that you will conclud to remit instead of respite for twelve months, and with many thanks I subscribe myse yours truly.</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00008057">G. S. Kimberly</persName></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
