<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-021-0031"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">The State v. William B. Chapman, Bond</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG3101</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG8-117 to MG8-118</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Union County, Tennessee</placeName>
    <date when="1861-05-06">6 May 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The State
<lb/>vs } Embezzlement
    <lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00012150">W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> B. Chapman</persName></p>
   <p>In this case came <persName ref="cwgk:N00011891">James W. Turner</persName>, <persName ref="cwgk:N00011893">Christian Ousley</persName> &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00011894">W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> J. Lay</persName> the Securities of the said W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> B. Chapman to his appearance Bond and assures the payment of the Money so Embezzled and also the costs of this Cause, upon which the <persName ref="cwgk:N00011898">attorny General</persName> releases the Securities from the <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>forteiture in the appearance Bond, It is therefore considered by the Court that <persName ref="cwgk:N00011899">R. J. Carr</persName> <hi rend="str">the</hi> Recover of the said J. W. Turner Christian <hi rend="str">o</hi>Ousley, &amp; W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> J. Lay the <hi rend="str">with th</hi> sum of dollars, together with the costs of this cause for which Execution May Issue. The Securities Jas. W. Turner &amp; C. Ousley &amp; took exceptions to the foregoing Judgment, which Judgment is hereby set as<hi rend="str">s</hi>ide &amp; forfeiture entered against the Securities</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Bond</note>
<lb/>State of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001001">Tennessee</placeName> <placeName ref="cwgk:P00011900">Union County</placeName>.
<lb/><date when="1861-05-06">May 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi>. 1861.</date></p>
   <p>Know all men by these presents the W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> B. Chapman, W. J. Lay<pb/>
    <lb/>James W. Turner &amp; Christian Ousley are held and firmly bound unto the State of Tennessee as follows that is to say, the Said W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> B. Chapman in the Sum of one thousand dollars and the said W. J. Lay, James W. Turner &amp; C. ousley each in the sum of f<hi rend="str">o</hi>ive hundred dollars be levied of their respective goods &amp; chattles Lands and tenements for the use of the State Yet to be void on condition that the Said W. B. Chapman does make his personal appearance at the next Term of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00012151">Circuit Court for Union County</orgName> State of Tennessee to be held at the Court House in <placeName ref="cwgk:P00011901">Maynardville</placeName> on the <date when="1861-06-03">first Monday of June next</date>. there to answer the Charge of the State exibited against him by a warrant for Embezzlement of of public Monies, and not depart the court without leave this date above written</p>
<p>Test.
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00012116">W. P. Owen</persName>, D. Shff.</p>
<p>W. B. Chapman <figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>W. J. Lay <figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>Christian Ousley <figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>J. W. Turner <figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>State of Tennessee
<lb/>Union County</p>
<p>I, R. J. Carr Clerk of the Circuit Court of Union County<pb/> </p>
   <p>Be it Remembered that at a <hi rend="str"><unclear>Ce</unclear></hi>regular <hi rend="str"><unclear>Court</unclear></hi>Term of the Circuit Court held at the Court House in Maynardville for the County of Union and in the Second Judicial Circuit for the State of Tennessee, on the first Monday after the fourth Monday in <date when="1861-05">May</date> it being the <date when="1861-06-03">3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> day of June <hi rend="str">1861</hi> in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and Sixty one,</date> and of the Indipendance of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00002945">United States of America</orgName> the eighty fourth year. Present and presiding the <persName ref="cwgk:N00012117">Honorable L. W. Lundy</persName> Judge &amp;c one of the Judges of the Circuit Court for the State of Tennessee duly commissioned &amp; qualified as such where the following proceedings were had to wit:</p>
   <p><persName ref="cwgk:N00012118">A. J. Brock</persName> high Sheriff of Union County, returns into Court the States writ: of Venire facias to him directed whereby it appears that the following persons good and lawful men were Summoned in said writ to attend here this day as Jurors to wit: District No 1. <persName ref="cwgk:N00012119">Jefferson Wyrick</persName> &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00012120">John A. Blackburn </persName>2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> <persName ref="cwgk:N00012148">John Evans Sr.</persName> &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00012121">Jordan Hunley</persName> 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> <persName ref="cwgk:N00012122">John Smith</persName> &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00012123">Isaac Haynes</persName>, &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00012125">William Davis</persName> 4th. <persName ref="cwgk:N00012127">Robert Fields</persName>, <persName ref="cwgk:N00015858">Daniel Cardwell</persName>, 5th. <persName ref="cwgk:N00012133">W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Boles</persName>, <persName ref="cwgk:N00012135">Samuel Ledgewood</persName> 6th. <persName ref="cwgk:N00012136">George W. Graves</persName>, <persName ref="cwgk:N00012139">C. L. Johnson</persName> &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00012140">Wesley Davis</persName>, 7th. <persName ref="cwgk:N00012134">Robert Wolfenbarger</persName>,  <persName ref="cwgk:N00012138">Volentine<pb/>
    <lb/>Turner</persName> &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00012142">Thos. Humphreys</persName> 8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> <persName ref="cwgk:N00012126">F. Erwin</persName> &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00012143">Lewis Lay</persName> 9th. <persName ref="cwgk:N00012149"><persName ref="cwgk:N00012149">Elisha Green</persName></persName><persName ref="cwgk:N00012149"> Jr.</persName>, <persName ref="cwgk:N00012137">H. G. Miller</persName> 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi>. <persName ref="cwgk:N00012124">Arthur Nash</persName> &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00012146">J. G. Palmer</persName> &amp; 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi>. <persName ref="cwgk:N00012145">R. J. Russell</persName> &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00012141">J. K. Rogers</persName>. and returns that by virtue of said writ summoned <persName ref="cwgk:N00012144">David Ridenour</persName> &amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00012147">Paris Frost</persName> to attend this court as constables, and thereupon from the Jurors summoned as aforesaid, the court proceeds as the Statutes in such case directs to select and empanneled a Grand Jury for said County of Union at the present time whereupon the following gentlemen were selected as Grand Jurors to wit: C. L. Johnson, Wesley Davis, J. G. Palmer, George W. Graves, Volentine Turner, Thomas Humphreys, W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Boles, R. W. Wolfenbarger Jefferson Wyrick, John Evans, W. G. Miller J. K. Rogers &amp; Samuel Legerwood, of whom the Court appoints J. G. Palmer who together with the rest of said Grand Jurors having been empanneled sworn &amp; charged to enquire according to law, for the body of the County of Union, retired to consider of their presentments attended by their officer David Ridenour a constable who was qualified according to law to wait upon the grand Jury &amp; Paris Frost to wait upon the Court.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
