<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1701"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph E. Hays to Andrew J. James</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11169</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-3</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jamestown, Russell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-03-28">28 March 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Jamestown Ky. <date when="1862-03-28">March 28<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>A J James,</p>
<p>D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Sir. I inclose to you the Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> pardon to George W. Collins for correction of clerical errors. Please do me the favor to get the Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> to erase the word "Russell" &amp; insert "Clinton circuit court, and erase "&#36;50" and insert &#36;75. &amp; it will then be all right. If he will look at the petition he will see that the Judgment was rendered in clinton cty &amp; for &#36;75. if I recollect right. I want also a copy of a 50 acre patent to John Mchenry, in Wayne Cty. on waters fall creek, and Joining a 322 acre grant to James McHenry if I recollect the No. of <hi rend="underline">acres</hi> in Jas. McHenrys grant correctly. I owe you 50 cts. for copy Bankrupt certificate to Frank Webb. I asked McClure to pay it &amp; to pay for the copy of this 50 acre grant. I have just landed from Somerset &amp; have not seen McClure, to learn whether he pd. it or not &amp; am compelled to write by todays mail to get the patent by the Wayne Court, which is all important as &#36;900 is tied up upon flimsy objections to land titles. If McClure has not paid I will inclose the money immediately. Please dont fail to have the pardon corrected &amp; remail it to me your friend</p>
<p>Joseph E Hays</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>