<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-009-0041"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James B. Gaines to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11508</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Kristen Bailey</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>45th, 47th, 48th, and 49th Regiments Kentucky Infantry Muster Rolls</collection>
      <idno>Box 42, Bundle 2</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Smithland, Livingston County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-09-22">22 September 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1863-09-22">Sept. the 22. 1863</date>.
<lb/>Dear <persName ref="cwgk:N001000">Gov</persName>,,
<lb/>Sir</p>
   <p>Permit me by way of an Introduction to you, For me to Say I am a Union Man Unconditionally,, and Your warmest Friend and Formerly a Citizen of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001013">Shelby County</placeName> <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Ky</placeName>, But Now a Citizen of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00004802">Smithland</placeName> and have been 13 Months ^there.^ a Physician, a Graduate of <orgName ref="cwgk:O001010">Transylvania University</orgName> of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001002">Lexington</placeName> Ky in the year 1844- and Having Practised The Greater Pourtion of My Time in The <geogName ref="cwgk:G00003748">Green River</geogName> Country in <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000441">Edmondson</placeName> &amp; <placeName ref="cwgk:P00005535">Butler</placeName> &amp; <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002417">Ohio</placeName> Countyes in that Section Of Country, and am now asking at your hands a Position as Surgeon in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00008607">48 Mounted Intfantry</orgName> of <persName ref="cwgk:N00002272">Col Burge,s</persName> Regiment now Orginizing at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002273">Princeton</placeName> Ky, <persName ref="cwgk:N00006112">Capt Belt</persName> The Commander at Post at Smithland Ky, is an aspirant For Major, in That Regiment, a worthy Officer, and an Enerjetic Man, as any Officer Belonging to <orgName ref="cwgk:O00009919">19 Ky Cavlery</orgName> under, Col <persName ref="cwgk:N00013089">Henry</persName>, His time having Expired In that Relation of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00013042">1 Congressional Destrict</orgName>,, I Reccommend him to you, as one well Deserves the Place as Major, of Col Burges Regiment, styled the 48, now Organising at Priceton Ky, now formed; Permit me to say to your Most Noble excellency, Dear Govnor,, Iff it meats with your Approbation To Give us Both and<pb/>
    <lb/>appointments Mr<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Belt as Major of The 48 Mounted Intfantry Of Col Burge,s Regment now formed at Princeton and my Selfe D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> <persName ref="cwgk:N00006693">James B Gaines</persName> of Shelby County Ky. But now a Citizen of Smithland Ky, a Position in that Regiment as Surgeon,, it will Be thankfully Reseaved worthy Bestowed, We Refer you To Our Old Collegue <persName ref="cwgk:N00000523">Maj. Gen, Boyle</persName> of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000337">Louisville</placeName>, and <orgName ref="cwgk:O00012970">The Medicle Bourd</orgName> By Whom I was Examined and Obtained a Sertificate as to My Qualifications as to my competency to fulfill that High Position to which I aspire, I have Practised 18 years Have Refferenes From D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> <persName ref="cwgk:N00012986">B. W. Dudley</persName> The Old Surgeon of Transylvania University of Lexington Ky. and D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> <persName ref="cwgk:N00013043">N. R. Smith</persName> of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00003303">Baltimore</placeName> of The Same University, and all The Professors of That Institution. </p>
<p>I Reccomend M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Capt Belt for Magor,, Because he has done more and his Company in taking Garillers and hard Lines these,s 12 month than any Col or Officer in this whole Congressional Destrict, and well Deserves the Position. Pardon my lenghened remarks and give us an uptmost Seat, in your remembrace and reccollection, when the time arrives To confer the appointments, in the above Mentioned Rejiment of Col Burges 48 Mounted Intfantry of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002472">Coldwell</placeName> &amp; <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002081">Lion </placeName>and <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002063">Livingston</placeName> Countys now at<pb/>
<lb/>at Princeton, Ky, Capt Belt has maid up 7 Companys For Col, Burges, Regiment, and wants Majors Place in It and me, as hed surgeon, and all The seven Companys. It is with you, To Give me a Position <hi rend="str">the</hi>As hed Surgeon, or assistant Surgeon one or The Two, The First I would Prefur,, But Iff not, The First, The Second. as It may Seem good in your sight,, The Capt wants us To Get our Appointments in this end of The Destrict, at Smithland as he has maid up All The Regiment through his Energy and Perservance, and thinks we ought to Be intitled to the two appointments,</p>
<p>Your Obedient 
<lb/>Servent and Friend
<lb/>D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> James. B. Gaines
<lb/>Smithland Ky.<pb/></p>
<p>48</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
