<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0356"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Painston to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9824</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Charles R. Welsko</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-50</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Scott County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>To the Sheriff of Scott County greeting</p>
<p>We command you that the estate of John Massie, G W Massie and S C Perrin -- late of your bailiwick you cause to be made the sum of Three Hundred Dollars which the Commonwealth of Ky. -- late in our Kenton circuit court hath recovered against them for Debt on Reconi<hi rend="sup">ce</hi> bond also the sum of &#36;4,30 which to the said plaintiff in the said court were adjudged for its Costs in that suit expended, Whereof the said Defendants are convicted as x appears to us of record and that you have the said sum of money before the judge of our said court on the first monday in <date when="1859-11">Nov</date>, next to render to the said Plaintiff its debts, cost aforesaid and have then &amp; there this next Witness Napoleon B Stephens clerk of our said court this <date when="1859-09-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Sept, in the year of our Lord 1859</date> in the 68<hi rend="sup">th</hi> year of the Commonwealth</p>
<p>N B Stephens clerk
<lb/>By Thos Painston D C</p>
<p>A copy</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>