<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0004-033-0021"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, Journal</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG16319</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Louisville</settlement>
      <repository>Filson Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>Kentucky Confederate Provisional Government Journal</collection>
      <idno>p. 56-57</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-12-10">10 December 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Journal</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header"><unclear>56</unclear></note>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Tuesday </hi><date when="1861-12-10"><hi rend="underline">December 10</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 1861</hi></date></p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011019">Council</orgName> met. <persName ref="cwgk:N00000832">W. B. Machen </persName>President in the chair.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Present Messrs <persName ref="cwgk:N00000853">Thompson</persName> <persName ref="cwgk:N00000846">E. M. Bruce</persName>, <persName ref="cwgk:N00000852">Bates</persName>, <persName ref="cwgk:N00000856">Scott</persName>,<persName ref="cwgk:N00000843"> H. W. Bruce</persName> <persName ref="cwgk:N00011020">Burnside</persName> and <persName ref="cwgk:N00000833">Crockett</persName>.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr Crockett had the unanimous consent of the council to introduce a bill entitled "An act to facilitate and complete the admission of <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003448">Kentucky</orgName> into the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003030">Confederate States of America</orgName>"
<lb/>And thereupon said bill was introduced and read a first time
<lb/>Ordered That said bill be read a second time
<lb/>On motion the rule of the Council constitutional provision and second and third readings were dispensed with
<lb/>The question was then taken on the passage of the bill and it was decided in the affirmative -- and so the bill passed
<lb/>Ordered that the title thereof be as reported-</p>
<p>The<orgName ref="cwgk:O00011361"> committee on enrollments</orgName> reported that they had examined an enrolled bill of the following title viz.
<lb/>An act to facilitate and complete the admission of Kentucky into the Confederate States of America."</p>
<p>And had found the same truly enrolled -- and thereupon the President affixed his signature thereto.</p>
<p>A message from the <persName ref="cwgk:N001002">Governor</persName> by<persName ref="cwgk:N00011014"> R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee</persName> Secretary of state was received announcing his approval of an enrolled bill entitled "an act to facilitate and complete the admission of Kentucky into the Confederate States of America- and that he had signed the same.</p>
<p>On motion the Council then went into secret Session.</p>
<p>Mr E. M. Bruce moved the following resolution viz
<lb/>Whereas the Council of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, have reason to believe and does believe, that <persName ref="cwgk:N00006237">Warner L. Underwood </persName>has aided and abetted in the persecution of Southern rights citizens of Kentucky, and has aided our enemies in every possible manner in his power Therefore be it Resolved by the Council of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky that the Governor be and he is hereby directed to cause the immediate arrest of Warner L. Underwood and have him safely held and conveyed to some safe place of confinement in the confederate States outside of the State of Kentucky, and th<hi rend="str">at</hi>e said<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">57</note>
<lb/>Underwood be held as a prisoner until <persName ref="cwgk:N00002722">Charles S. Morehead </persName>is released and safely delivered to his home, in this State, when the said Underwood shall be released- Provided that all the political prisoners which have been arrested in Kentucky and now held in or outside of this state are humanely treated- but in case of cruelty in confinement or other punishment administered to either one of said prisoners, then the same character of confinement and punishment shall be administered to the said Underwood</p>
<p>The question was then taken on the adoption of the preamble and resolution and it was decided in the negative.</p>
<p>Messrs Burnside and Crockett having demanded the yeas and nays and the call being made resulted as follows:
<lb/>Those who voted in the affirmative were Mr E. M. Bruce 1.
<lb/>Those who voted in the negative were Messrs
<lb/>President, Thompson, Bates, Scott, H W Bruce, Burnside and Crockett 7.</p>
<p>And then the Council adjourned until tomorrow at 10 O'Clock A. M.</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00001858">A. Frank Brown</persName> Clerk.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
