<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0004-033-0018"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, Journal</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG16316</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Sarah Haywood</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Louisville</settlement>
      <repository>Filson Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>Kentucky Confederate Provisional Government Journal</collection>
      <idno>p. 51-52</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-12-06">6 December 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Journal</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">51</note></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Friday </hi><date when="1861-12-06"><hi rend="underline">December 6</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 1861</hi></date></p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011019">Council</orgName> met. <persName ref="cwgk:N00000832">W B Machen</persName> President in the Chair.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J. W. Moore</hi> Member of this Council from the Ninth Congressional district appeared, took the oath prescribed by law and took his seat.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>H. W. Bruce asked and obtained leave to be relieved from further duty on the Committee on enrollments, whereupon the President substituted in his stead on said committee S. S. Scott.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The Committee on enrollments reported that they had examined enrolled bills of the following titles Viz.
<lb/>An act to amend an act entitled ^an act^ to regulate the currency approved <date when="1861-12-04">Dec 4.<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>An Act authorizing the appointment of a Commissioner to settle with the collecting Officers of this State.
<lb/>An act to fix the fees of the Clerk of this Council in certain cases.
<lb/>An act to repeal Section 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> of Chapter 61, of the Revised Statutes.
<lb/>and had found the same truly enrolled, whereupon the President affixed his signature thereto.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p> moved the following resolution. Towit.<persName ref="cwgk:N00000843">H. W. Bruce</persName></p>
<p>Whereas the first Regiment of Kentucky volunteers, now on duty on the Potomac in the Army of the Confederate States, was the first to tender its services to defend the Independence of the Confederate, and has since <date when="1861-05">last may</date>. arduously and faithfully discharged its duty in the field;
<lb/>And whereas Kentucky is now struggling against great odds to repel a ruthless invasion of her own soil, and therefore needs the services of all her skilled and experienced volunteers; and whereas this Council are informed that the gallant members of that noble and brave regiment desire to be transferred to their own native State, believing they can render as efficient service to the Confederate Government as in virginia Therefore be it Resolved- 1. By the Council of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, that the President of the Confederate States is hereby respectfully requested to transfer and assign the first Regiment of Kentucky Volunteers to duty and service in the State of Kentucky, if to do so would not be detrimental to the service and interest of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>2 Resolved That the Governor is directed to transmit a copy of these resolutions and their preamble to the President of the Confederate States</p>
<p>Mr Moore moved to postpone the further consideration of said resolutions until tomorrow and that they be made the<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">52</note>
<lb/>special order of the day for 10 <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">2</hi> O'Clock A. M.
<lb/>Which motion prevailed.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>On Motion of H. W. Bruce, the name of S. S. Scott was added to the Committee on Ways &amp; Means.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr<persName ref="cwgk:N00000846"> E. M. Bruce</persName> moved that the council do now go into secret Session- which motion prevailed<lb/>And then the<hi rend="str">n</hi> Council went into secret session.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr E. M. Bruce mvoed that a standing <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011625">Committee on Internal Improvements</orgName> be raised -- which was sustained<lb/>Whereupon the President constituted said committee as follows viz Dr. S S. Scott chairman <persName ref="cwgk:N00000852">J. P. Bates</persName> and E M Bruce.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr H. W. Bruce moved the following resolution viz-
<lb/>Resolved That reporters for the public press be allowed to take an abstract of the proceedings of this Council from the time of its organization, and until forbidden, for publication, except such as the Council may determine not to make public.
<lb/>Which was adopted.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr Bates moved that a standing <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011477">Committee on Common Schools</orgName> be raised -- Which motion prevailed -- <lb/>Whereupon the President constituted said committee<hi rend="str">s</hi> as follows viz. J. W. Moore Chairman, <persName ref="cwgk:N00000833">John W. Crockett</persName> and H W Bruce.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>And then the Council adjourned until tomorrow morning at 10 O'Clock</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00001858">A. Frank Brown</persName> Clerk</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
