<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0004-033-0004"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, Journal</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG16303</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Sarah Haywood</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Louisville</settlement>
      <repository>Filson Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>Kentucky Confederate Provisional Government Journal</collection>
      <idno>p. 13-14</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-11-21">21 November 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Journal</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">13</note><orgName ref="cwgk:O00011019">Council</orgName> of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003448">Provisional Government</orgName> </p>
<p>Be it remembered that on the <date when="1861-11-21">twenty first day of November A. D. One Thousand Eight hundred and sixty one</date> at the Chamber of the Hon<hi rend="sup">l.</hi><persName ref="cwgk:N001002"> George W. Johnson</persName> Governor of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky in the City of<placeName ref="cwgk:P00000560"> Bowling Green</placeName> and county of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001020">Warren</placeName>, pursuant to the provisions of a Convention by the people, begun at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002479">Russellville</placeName> on Monday <date when="1861-11-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> November 1861</date>, the Governor and Council met, for the purpose of organizing said government.</p>
<p>The following members having taken the oath prescribed by the Constitution appeared and took their seats in the Council</p>
<p>	Honl. <persName ref="cwgk:N00000843">H. W. Bruce</persName></p>
<p>On motion of the Hon<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> H. W Bruce, Hon<hi rend="sup">l.</hi> <persName ref="cwgk:N00000833">Jno. W. Crockett </persName>was unanimously elected President pro. tem- of the Council</p>
<p>On motion T. L. Burnett was appointed Clerk pro. tem.</p>
<p>The following resolution was offered by the Hon<hi rend="sup">l</hi>. <persName ref="cwgk:N00000853">Phil. B. Thompson</persName> viz: "<hi rend="underline">Resolved</hi> that the proceedings of this Council shall be governed by the rules of the late House of Representatives of Kentucky."</p>
<p>Which was unanimously adopted.</p>
<p>Hon<hi rend="sup">l.</hi> P. B. Thompson moved the following resolution viz.</p>
<p>"<hi rend="underline">Resolved</hi> that the Council now proceed to the election of a President."</p>
<p>Which was adopted.</p>
<p>The Council thereupon proceeded to the election of a President, which resulted in the unanimous choice of the Hon<hi rend="sup">l.</hi> Willis B. Machen, Hon<hi rend="sup">l.</hi> <persName ref="cwgk:N00000846">E. M. Bruce</persName> moved that messrs Thompson and H. W. Bruce be appointed a committee to inform His Excellency the Governor of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky that the Council was now organized and ready to receive any communication by way of message he may think proper to make which was adopted.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">14</note></p>
<p>Messrs H. W Bruce and Thompson the Committee appointed to wait on the Governor reported that they had performed the duty assigned them, and was informed by His Excellency the Governor that he would in a few days communicate with the<hi rend="str">y</hi> Council in writing</p>
<p>A special message was received from the Governor as follows viz
<lb/>"To the Honl. W. B. Machen President of the Council
<lb/>of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I have the honor to nominate for the Office of Treasurer of the Provisional Government of Kentucky the Hon<hi rend="sup">l.</hi> Thedore L. Burnett and hope that this nomination may receive your Sanction and support</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Your Ob<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Serv<hi rend="sup">t</hi>
<lb/>George W. Johnson</p>
<p>Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-11-21">Novr. 21.<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1861.</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>On motion of Hon<hi rend="sup">l.</hi> H. W. Bruce the Council went into Executive Session.
<lb/>On motion of Hon<hi rend="sup">l.</hi> P. B. Thompson the nomination by the Governor of T. L. Burnett was unanimously confirmed.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr Thompson moved the following resolution Towit:
<lb/>"<hi rend="underline">Resolved</hi> that the Governor be authorized to procure for the Provisional Government the necessary buildings for the use of the Government"
<lb/>Which was unanimously adopted<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>On motion leave of absence was granted to E. M Bruce until monday morning.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>An then the Council adjourned until tomorrow morning at 10 O'Clock.</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/>T. L. Burnett Sec'y ProTem.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
