<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1784"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Granville Bushy et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11252</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-141 to MG23-142</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-01">1 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency B. Magoffin Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your peitioners Granville Bushy and William Essex state that on the <date when="1859"><gap/> day of <gap/> 1859</date> Israel Thomas was arrested in Maysville in Mason County for passing counterfeit money and held to bail for his appearance at the next term of the Mason Circuit Court, in the sum of <hi rend="underline">five</hi> <hi rend="underline">hundred</hi> <hi rend="underline">dollars</hi> -- Your petitioners became his bail for his appearance The said Thomas failed to appear and the bail bond was forfeited and judgement rendered against your petitioenrs for said sum of &#36;500 -- and costs -- They now state ^that^ said Thomas gave them a mortgage on a small tract of land in Lewis County to indemnify them -- said land is worth some three hundred dollars and not more, at the same time he gave W H Wadsworth a leen on said land for fifty Dollars his fee in the sent -- both liens as included in the Same mortgage= They state that said land is all the estate said Thomas owns -- that he has a wife and three small children -- if said land is sold his wife &amp; children will be left without anything said land would not sell<pb/>
<lb/>for more than two hundred dollars with the wifes contingent right of dowermet -- Your petitioners are poor men and unable to stand the loss -- In order to protect themselves, and said Thomas wife and children they pray that you will remit all of said Sum of &#36;500 except officers costs and fees -- </p>
<p>Granville Bushy
<lb/>Wm Essex</p>
<p>P. S.
<lb/>The execution is in hand of sheriff of Lewis county If Judgement is remitted please send to us or sheriff at <hi rend="underline">Clarksberg</hi> <hi rend="underline">Lewis</hi> <hi rend="underline">co</hi> Ky</p>
<p>I Seth Parker Sheriff of Lewis county, State that I am well acquainted with the petitioners Granville Bushy and William Essex, and that I am satisfied that their case in one demanding the interposition of executive clemancy -- They are poor men with large families -- The land upon which they have a mortgage is not worth more than &#36;300 -- and that is all the estate said Thomas has</p>
<p>Seth Parker S L C<pb/></p>
<p>I James, R, Garland County Judge of Lewis County concur in the above statements of Mr Parker and hope that your Excellency will interpose and <hi rend="underline">remit</hi> said judgement for &#36;500</p>
<p>J.. R. Garland J. L. C. C
<lb/><date when="1860-12-01">Decr 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1860</date></p>
<p>I. Geo. T. Halbert Clerk of the Lewis Circuit and County Courts also concur in the above statements of Mr Parker and Judge Garland. </p>
<p>I have known the petitioners many years and they are men in limited circumstances It will be a great hardship if they have to pay the &#36;500</p>
<p>Geo. T. Halburt
<lb/><date when="1860-12-01">Decr 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1860</date></p>
<p>The statements in the above petitions, I am satisfied are true, and the effect of requiring the above penalty to be enforced will only be take from M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Thomas and her little children, all they have to live upon. She deserves a better fate, and I unite in asking that the penalty of the bond, so far as the Governor has a right to remit it, may be remitted,</p>
<p>R H Stanton
<lb/>Atty for Commonwealth<pb/></p>
<p>Mason Cir. Ct.
<lb/>Respite 12 Mo
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>&#36;500 &#125; Forfeited recognizance
<lb/>G Bushy &amp; W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Essex</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-12-12">Dec 12. 1861</date>
<lb/>Resp<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> 12 Mos
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-04-24">Apr 24. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>