<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0375"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">T. T. Sharp to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4494</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Kristen Bailey</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-95 to BR9-96</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hamilton County, Ohio</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-15">15 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N001000">Thos E Bramlette</persName>
<lb/>Govenor of <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Kentucky</orgName>
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>In <date when="1862-07">July 1862</date> I was recruiting in <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000936">Covington</placeName> <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000937">Kenton Co</placeName>, <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Ky</placeName> a Company for the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00006342">Seventh Ky Cavalry</orgName>, <persName ref="cwgk:N00009382">Col Leonidas Metcalfe</persName> commanding, He gave <persName ref="cwgk:N00012599">Major R, C, Bocking</persName> written authority to raise three companies, to constitute the third Battallion of said Regiment, Major R. C. Bocking gave me written authority to recruit a company for his Battallion, In the month aforesaid <date when="1862-07">July 1862</date>, Major R, C, Bocking received written authority from Col Leonidas Metcalfe to press horses for the service of the State of Kentucky in the Counties of Kenton and <placeName ref="cwgk:P00001194">Boone</placeName> with blank Rail Road passes to be filled by said Major R. C, Bocking to ship the horses to the Camp at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00005772">Cynthiana</placeName> Ky,</p>
<p>Major R. C. Bocking then gave me written authority to press horses of certain parties<pb/>
<lb/>in the counties aforesaid viz Kenton &amp; Boone The order read thus "<persName ref="cwgk:N00012630">Capt T. T. Sharp </persName>you are hereby ordered to take <gap/> horses from <gap/> to be used for the service of the State of Kentucky, by order of Col Leonidas Metcalfe, Major R. C. Bocking commanding Third Batt, 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cavalry",</p>
<p>I then proceeded to execute the order and among the number, was one horse from <persName ref="cwgk:N00012600">T. D. Kennedy</persName>, I delivered the said horse to Major R. C. Bocking in Covington Ky, and he shipped it to the camp at Cynthiana, Ky, as the Rail Road receipts for that month will show.</p>
<p>Major R. C. Bocking is now in the state of<placeName ref="cwgk:P001818"> Indiana</placeName> recruiting for the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00012629">23<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> Battery of Artillery</orgName>, where he is located I am unabled to say, he has all the papers, receipts &amp;c for the pressing of horses, recruiting for his Battallion of the 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cavalry, and therefore I am unable to procure the necessary documents to show under whose orders I acted, but the facts in the case, are as above set forth.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">T, T, Sharp</hi></p>
<p>Subscribed &amp; sworn to before me this <date when="1863-12-15">15" day of December A D 1863</date></p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00012598">Staughton Lynd</persName>.
<lb/>Notary Public
<lb/><placeName ref="cwgk:P00001873">Hamilton County</placeName> <placeName ref="cwgk:P001036">Ohio</placeName>
<lb/><figure type="seal"><ab>NOTORIAL
<lb/>HAMILTON COUNTY, OHIO</ab></figure><pb/></p>
<p>In <date when="1863-07">July 1863</date>, I was arrested in Covington Ky, on a charge of Felony, an indictment was found against me for unlawfully taking a horse from one T. D. Kennedy, I gave bail in the sum of $200<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> Mr <persName ref="cwgk:N00004640">L. D. Cronniger</persName> of Covington Ky as Surety and <gap/> <persName ref="cwgk:N00012588">Chatfield </persName>of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00001208">Cincinnati</placeName> as co-surety.</p>
<p>I now ask your Excellency to relieve my sureties, as the property taken was for the service of the State, and accordingly the State is responsible, I was acting under orders from my superior officers, and do not think, my sureties or myself should be held responsible</p>
<p>I have the honor to be
<lb/>Most Respectfully
<lb/>T. T. Sharp<pb/></p>
<p><orgName ref="cwgk:O00000410">Kenton Cir Ct</orgName>
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Cronniger <hi rend="str">&amp;field</hi>
<lb/>$200 -- 
<lb/>Bail Bond
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1864-01-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Jany/ 64</date></p>
<p>hand to <persName ref="cwgk:N00000460">Fisk</persName></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
