<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0403"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Lewis Frank and Solomon Shiffner to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4522</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Brian M. Trump</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Kevin McPartland</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-136 to BR9-137</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Hon <persName ref="cwgk:N001000">Thomas E Bramlette</persName>
<lb/>Governor of <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Kentucky</orgName></p>
<p>Your petitioners <persName ref="cwgk:N00015470">Lewis Frank</persName> and <persName ref="cwgk:N00015471">Solomon Sheffner</persName> (partners under the style of <orgName ref="cwgk:O00015472">sheffner &amp; Frank</orgName>) would respectfully represent that at the last <date when="--10">October term</date> of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000350">Bourbon Circuit Court</orgName> they were fined eighty dollars upon an indictment for trading with a slave, The charge in the indictment was true and the following are the circumstances under which it was committed. The undersigned are merchants in <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000514">Paris</placeName> <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Ky</placeName> and as part of their business frequently purchase various articles of country produce and during the last summer purchased a large amount of wool A negro man named <persName ref="cwgk:N00015512">George Dergen</persName> who lived in a house apparently his own with his family and carried on business for himself as a freeman came to the store of the undersigned in open day with a small lot of wool which the undersigned purchased from him believing it to be his own and that he was a free man. It turned out however that the said Dergen had purchased himself from his <persName ref="cwgk:N00018992">former owner</persName> but not being willing to leave the state had induced a <persName ref="cwgk:N00018991">friend</persName> in whom he had confidence to become nominally his owner and to take the bill of sale in his name so that he was a slave although permitted to go at large and trade for<pb/>
<lb/>himself as a free person It turned out also that the woo<hi rend="str">d</hi>l had been stolen (although Dergen had always sustained a good reputation for honesty) and the moment the undersigned were enquired of by the person whose wool had been taken they promptly pointed out this lot -- gave all the information in their power which led to the detection of the guilty parties and their punishment and gave up the wool to the proper owner. These facts coming as they do within the letter although not within the Spirit of the law were seized upon ^by a^ <hi rend="str">person</hi> malicious person as a means of venting his personal enmity and made the foundation of the indictment against We pray that so much of the fine as is within the control of the Executive may be remitted</p>
<p>Lewes Frank
<lb/>Solomon Shiffner</p>
<p>The undersign citizens of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000515">Bourbon county</placeName> unite with the foregoing petitioners Sheffner &amp; Frank in soliciting the remission of the fine against them</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00000235">John A Prall</persName>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Geo: W. Williams</hi>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00002551">R. J. <hi rend="underline">Brown</hi></persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000753">R, H, Hanson</persName>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> M.</hi> <hi rend="underline">Samuel</hi>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00002390">B F Pullen</persName><pb/>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00015463">Jesse H <unclear>Tallute</unclear></persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00015465">Tho <hi rend="underline">M Webb</hi></persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00015468">John Stuart</persName>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">H, T, Brent</hi>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006126">C S Brent</persName></p>
<p><hi rend="str">From conversation with</hi></p>
<p>From conversation with Col. Prall and other gentlemen. I believe the circumstances set forth in the Petition are True. and concur in its Prayer.</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00006117">W S Downey</persName><pb/></p>
<p>Bourbon Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Shiffner &amp; Frank</p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>Trading with Slaves
<lb/>$80 -- 
<lb/>Remt<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1864-01-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Jany 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
