<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0348"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Leander Allen, Copy of Record</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9816</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Charles R. Welsko</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-38 to MG18-39</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken Equity &amp; Criminal Court, Sct.
<lb/>The Commonewalth of Kentucky
<lb/>Against
<lb/>Leander Allen</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, accuse Leander Allen of the Crime of Grand Larceny committed as follows, (viz) The said Leander Allen on the <date when="1859-07-25">25<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of July 1859</date> in the County aforesaid did feloniously take and carry away one watch. the personal property of <hi rend="str">Leander Allen</hi> Henry Odell and of the value of more than four dollars against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>A. P. Thompson
<lb/>Attorney for the Commonwealth 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> J. D.</p>
<p>Information by
<lb/>Henry Odell</p>
<p>The following endorsements appear on the back of the above indictment.</p>
<p>"Bail is fixed upon the within indictment at Five Hundred Dollars. <date when="1859-07-30">July 30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1859</date></p>
<p>L. S. Trimble
<lb/>Equity &amp; Criminal Judge"</p>
<p>"We of the Jury say the prisoner is not guilty as charged in the in<hi rend="underline">dight</hi>ment</p>
<p>G. F. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clelland for."</p>
<p>"A true bill. Alfred Boyd foreman"</p>
<p>"Filed <date when="1859-07-30">July 30th 1859</date>"</p>
<p>A true Copy, Attest
<lb/>B. Small Clk
<lb/>By Jas. Leslie Brown D. C.<pb/></p>
<p>At the <date when="1859-07">July Term 1859</date> of the M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken Equity &amp; Criminal Court Ky, the following order was made to wit,</p>
<p>"The Commonwealth of Ky Plff
<lb/>against &#125; Grand Larceny
<lb/>Leander Allen</p>
<p>The Deft was again brought into Court and together with John Q. A. King, Albert H Noble, John L. Allard, R. J. Jordan, P. C. Smedley, &amp; Q Q Quigley as surety acknowledged themselves jointly and severally indebted to the Commonwealth of Kentucky in the sum of One Hundred And fifty Dollars to be void however if the said Leander Allen shall personally appear in this Court on the first day of its next <date when="1860-01">January Term</date> to answer the indictment in this case and not depart with out leave of the Court"</p>
<p>A true Copy, Attest
<lb/>B. Small Clk
<lb/>By Jas Leslie Brown D. C</p>
<p>At the <date when="1860-01">January Term 1860</date> of said Court the following order was made in same case towit,</p>
<p>The Plff appeared by attorney and the defendant was solemnly called but came not It is therefore ordered that his recogizance be taken as forfeited and that a summons issue against him &amp; J. Q. A. King, A. H. Noble, J. L Allard, R. J. Jordan, P. C. Smedley and Q Q Quigley sureties returnable to the next term of this Court."</p>
<p>A true copy, Attest, R. Small Clk
<lb/>By Jas Leslie Born D. C<pb/></p>
<p>Copy of Record</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>