<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-003-0080"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John H. Ward to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1597</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Brian M. Trump</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Matthew Roberts</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Charles R. Welsko</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-119 to BR5-120</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-02-03">3 February 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Camp <orgName ref="cwgk:O00001585">27<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Ky</placeName>.</orgName> M I
<lb/>Near. <geogName ref="cwgk:G00009417">Cumberland Gap</geogName>
<lb/><date when="1864-02-03">3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Feby 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov <persName ref="cwgk:N001000">Thos. E. Bramlette</persName>
    <lb/><placeName ref="cwgk:P00000308">Frankfort</placeName>. <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Ky</placeName>
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>As I wrote you before I am much displeased with the way <persName ref="cwgk:N00005705">Genl Foster</persName> proposes to conduct things in this command, am therefore willing to accept the position of Col of one of the State Regts, if they are to be organized &amp; officered on true miletary principles -- and to be a force the State may well be proud of, -- </p>
<p>I am the senior "<hi rend="underline">Lt</hi> <hi rend="underline">Col</hi>" Ky has -- and perhaps the senior in the army, I think you will find on inquiry of those under whom I have served -- that I am a good tactician -- a good deciplinarian -- and that few if any officers in the army have ^been^ more constantly with their commands -- or more attentive &amp; energetic in the discharge of their duties, when present.</p>
<p>I would ask for a "leave of Absence" &amp; come to see what could be done, -- But suppose I could not get one just now, because <persName ref="cwgk:N00009510">Mjr Magruder</persName> is absent<pb/>
<lb/>in Ky on sick leave. He may return soon however &amp; if he does -- I will apply for a leave. In the mean time I hope my friends will do what they can for me.</p>
<p>Gov I wrote you sometime ago about when this Regt would be mustered out. -- &amp; have heard nothing in reply.</p>
<p>I deem this a matter of vital importance to the Regt -- because the men have been accustomed to consider their time out <date when="1864-10-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct 64</date> and if not informed of the contrary soon no power can save them. They think they have borne enough allready &amp; I fear greatly a decision against what has all along been their impression.
<lb/>'
<lb/>It makes more difference with us than any other Regt, because all though many many enlisted in <date when="1861-09">Sept' 61</date>, The time at the organization of the Cos was agreed to be averaged at <date when="--10-12">12 Oct</date> &amp; for those recruited by<persName ref="cwgk:N00002582"> Col Pennebaker</persName> at <date when="--10-20">20 Oct</date>. Exspecting to be mustered out on <date when="1864-10-20">20 Oct, 64</date> &amp; so we understood <persName ref="cwgk:N001021">Mjr Sidell</persName> the U. S. mustering officer, when we were mustered in. Besides we were just as ready for muster in <date when="1861-12">Dec 61</date> as in <date when="1862-03">March, 62</date> -- and it was not our fault but missfortune that we were not mustered sooner. </p>
<p>For the credit of the state &amp; Regt I hope you will use every effort to get this matter arranged soon and let us know. -- for if we have to serve<pb/>
 <lb/>3 years from Muster in to<orgName ref="cwgk:O00001186"> <orgName ref="cwgk:O00002945">U. S.</orgName> service</orgName> -- we ought to Know it. At any rate it appears to me that the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00002945">U. S.</orgName> ought to take us from state muster in <date when="1862-01">Jan 62</date>.</p>
<p>Kind regards to all friends
<lb/>Your &amp;c
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00018530">J. H. Ward</persName>
<lb/>Lt. Col. 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Infty</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
