<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0004-033-0038"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, Journal</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG16336</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>James Bartek</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Louisville</settlement>
      <repository>Filson Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>Kentucky Confederate Provisional Government Journal</collection>
      <idno>p. 110-115</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-12-30">30 December 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Journal</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header"><unclear>110</unclear></note>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Monday </hi><date when="1861-12-30"><hi rend="underline">December 30</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 1861</hi></date></p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011019">Council</orgName> met <persName ref="cwgk:N00000833">Jno. W. Crockett</persName> President Pro.tem in the chair.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Mr Crockett called <persName ref="cwgk:N00011020">Mr Burnside</persName> to the chair.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mr Crockett</hi> moved the following resolution Towit:
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Resolved</hi> That a committee of three be appointed by the Council to examine the condition of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00008222">Branch Bank of Kentucky</orgName> at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000560">Bowling Green</placeName> -- and the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011617">Peoples Bank</orgName>. Said Committee are hereby invested with full power to summon persons before them and examine them on oath, touching any matter connected with said Banks, and shall also have full power all the papers of said Bank including its correspondence &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. S<hi rend="str">d</hi>aid committee Shall continue its labors from day to day until completed, and report in writing &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi>.
<lb/>Said resolution was adopted.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The council in pursuance of said resolution placed on said committee- Messrs Crockett, <persName ref="cwgk:N00000846">E. M Bruce</persName>, and <persName ref="cwgk:N00011226">Thompson</persName>.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The committee to whom was referred the bill apportioning the State reported a substitute for the original bill entitled "An act to district the State and provide for the election of members of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00012059">House of Representatives of the Confederate States</orgName>"<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The question was upon the adoption of the substitute and being taken it was decided in the affirmative.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Ordered That said bill be read a third time-
<lb/>And said bill was then read a third time.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The question was then taken on the passage of the bill, and it was decided in the affirmative-
<lb/>And so the bill passed.
<lb/>Ordered that the title thereof be as reported.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>A message from the Governor by <persName ref="cwgk:N00011014">Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee</persName> Secretary of State.
<lb/>Mr President: I am directed by the Governor to lay before this Council a special message in writing-</p>
<p><hi><orgName ref="cwgk:O00011543">Executive Office</orgName>
<lb/>Bowling Green <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Ky</placeName></hi>
<lb/><date when="1861-12-30"><hi rend="underline">December 30.</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 1861</hi></date>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Gentlemen of the Council</hi></p>
<p>Herewith I lay before you a communication from Hon<hi rend="sup">l.</hi> <persName ref="cwgk:N00000861">Thomas B. Monroe</persName> co<hi rend="str">n</hi>vering an act of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00002994">Congress of the Confederate States</orgName> entitled -- "An<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">111</note>
<lb/>act to determine the number of Members the State of Kentucky shall be entitled to in the House of Representatives of the Confederate States &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi> &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi>"</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N001002">George W. Johnson</persName></p>
<p>The "act" referred to reads as follows: Towit
<lb/>"An act to determine the number of Members which the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003448">State of Kentucky</orgName> shall be entitled to have in the House of Representatives of the Congress of the Confederate States, and in relation to the election and returns thereof
<lb/>The Congress of the Confederate States of America do enact that the State of Kentucky shall be entitled to have in the House of Representatives of the Congress of the Confederate States twelve members
<lb/>These members shall be elected, in the manner, at the time and at the places which has been, or may be hereafter prescribed by the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000923">Legislature of the State</orgName> subject to the provisions of the Constitution of the Confederate States
<lb/>The persons elected shall be certified by the Governor.</p>
<p>A special Messsage in writing from the Governor was announced by Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee Secretary of State:
<lb/>Mr President: I am directed by the Governor to lay before this Council a messsage in writing:</p>
<p>Executive Office
<lb/>Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-12-30">December 30.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>Gentlemen of the Council of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>I herewith inclose to you two letters from our <persName ref="cwgk:N00010674">Bank Commissioner</persName> at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002303">New Orleans</placeName>, and a copy of an act of Congress of the Confederate States of America to assist our Commissioner -- It seems to me, that under this act; our Commissioner will not have any difficulty in securing the assets, except to lay before the Court, proof of the fact, of their loan to the <placeName ref="cwgk:P001802">United States</placeName>, of which the <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">State Government</orgName> at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000308">Frankfort</placeName> claim to be a part</p>
<p>George W. Johnson</p>
<p>The Communications referred to in the message, were signed by <persName ref="cwgk:N00008127">Jno. D. Morris</persName>-
<lb/>read and ordered to be filed -- 
<lb/>The act of the Confederate Congress referred to reads as follows:
<lb/>"No 309. A resolution appointed John D. Morris of Kentucky. a receiver under the Act of Sequestration, approved <date when="1861-08-13">August thirteenth Eighteen Hundred and and Sixty one</date>.
<lb/>The congress of the Confederate States of America do resolve that J<hi rend="str">n</hi>ohn D. Morris appointed by the Government of Kentucky as their special Commissioner to secure the co-operation of the<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header"><unclear>112</unclear></note>
<lb/>Confederate States in the Sequestration of the property, effects, and credits of certain Banking corporations of said State, be hereby clothed with the powers of a receiver, under the act for the sequestration of the property of alien enemies approved <date when="1861-08-30">thirtieth of August Eighteen hundred and sixty one</date> -- throughout the Confederate States, and as such he alone be authorized, to ascertain, seize, and sequestrate the property effects and credits of all the banking Corporations of the said State, that may have made loans or extended pecuniary aid to the United States or the Government of Kentucky waging war against the Confederate States -- and when so sequestered -- instead of paying the same into the Treasury of the Confederate States, shall account for and pay over the same, under his Commission to the Government of Kentucky</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00012060">Th. S. Bocock</persName>
<lb/>President of Congress
<lb/>Pro tempore</p>
<p>Approved <date when="1861-12-16">Dec. 16. 1861</date>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000259">Jefferson Davis</persName></p>
<p>A special messsage from the Governor by Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee Secretary of State was announced:
<lb/>Mr President: I am directed by the Governor to lay before this council A Message in writing:</p>
<p>Executive Office
<lb/>Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-12-29">Dec. 29. 1861</date>
<lb/>Gentlemen of the Council of the State of Kentucky.</p>
<p>I hereby nominate <persName ref="cwgk:N00012065">S. B. Blackburn</persName> for the Offices of <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000585">Circuit</orgName> and <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000724">County Court</orgName> Clerk in the County of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001020">Warren</placeName>. Also <persName ref="cwgk:N00012067">P. B. Dunn</persName> for the Office of Circuit and County Court Clerk in <placeName ref="cwgk:P00005295">Simpson County</placeName>. Also <persName ref="cwgk:N00012068">Clement Fisher</persName> for the Office of Justice of the Peace for the County of Simpson, in place of <persName ref="cwgk:N00012069">Samuel R Hope</persName>, in the first civil District. Also <persName ref="cwgk:N00012070">James H Bradshaw</persName> for the Office of Assessor for the County of Simpson in place of the former assessor -- <persName ref="cwgk:N00011363">Williams</persName> -- who has removed from the State-</p>
<p>Also <persName ref="cwgk:N00012071">James M. Lane</persName> for the Office of Jailor in the County of Simpson, in place of <persName ref="cwgk:N00012074">William M Johnson</persName>, who resigned.</p>
<p>George W. Johnson</p>
<p>The question then taken and the entire list of the nominations in the foregoing message unanimously confirmed.</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00000852">Mr Bates</persName> asked and obtained the unanimous consent of the Council to introduce a bill creating the Office of Assistant Secretary of State -- 
<lb/>Said leave was referred to a special Committee consisting of Messrs Bates and <persName ref="cwgk:N00011225">Moore</persName>.</p>
<p>And then the Council took a recesss until 2 O'Clock P. M.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">113</note></p>
<p>Evening Session</p>
<p>The Council met- John W. Crockett Prest. Protempore in the chair.</p>
<p>The select committee to whom was referred the special leave to introduce a bill creating the Office of Assistant Secretary of State which bill was then read as follows.
<lb/>An act creating the Office of assistant Secretary of State.
<lb/>Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Council of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, that there is hereby created and established the Office of Assistant Secretary of State.
<lb/>Sec. 2. The assistant Secretary of State shall be appointed by the Governor by and with the consent of the Council and shall for his services receive a salary of six hundred dollars per anum payable monthly.</p>
<p>On Motion the rule of the Council, constitutional provision and second reading were dispensed with.</p>
<p>Mr <persName ref="cwgk:N00000843">H W Bruce</persName> moved to strike out the word "six" an insert "five" where it occurs in the second sec<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>tion.
<lb/>Said amendment was voted on and lost
<lb/>Messrs H. W. Bruce and Bates- having demanded the ayes and noes thereon- and being called resulted as follows:
<lb/>Those who voted in the affirmative were Messrs
<lb/>Crockett, Burnside, H. W Bruce and <persName ref="cwgk:N00000856">Scott</persName> -- 4 -- 
<lb/>Those who voted in the negative were Messrs
<lb/>Bates, Thompson, E. M. Bruce and Moore -- 4 -- </p>
<p>On motion said bill was ordered to th<hi rend="str">is</hi>e third reading
<lb/>The rules of the Council Constitutional provision and third reading were dispensed with-
<lb/>The question was then taken on the passage of the bill and it was decided in the affirmative -- and the bill passed
<lb/>Orderd that the title be as reported</p>
<p>The Committee on enrollments reported that they had examined the following enrolled bills Towit:
<lb/>An act entitled an act to raise and arm thirty regiments of volunteer infantry and Cavalry.
<lb/>An act to district the State and provide for the election of Members of the House of Representatives of the confederate States
<lb/>An act creating the Office of assistant Secretary of State.
<lb/>And that they had found the same truly enrolled -- Whereupon the President pro-tempore affixed his signature thereto.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">114</note></p>
<p>A special Message from the Governor by Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee secretary of State was announced
<lb/>Mr President: I am directed by the Governor to lay before this Council a message in writing:</p>
<p>Executive Office
<lb/>Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-12-29">Dec. <hi rend="underline">29</hi>.1861</date>
<lb/>Gentlemen of the Council of the State of Kentucky:</p>
<p>I hereby nominate General <persName ref="cwgk:N00000835">Henry E. Read</persName> as one of our Commissioners under an act directing the appointment of Commissioners, to visit officers and settle with Sheriffs and other collecting Officers</p>
<p>George W. Johnson</p>
<p>said nomination was unanimously confirmed by the Council.</p>
<p>The committee on claims reported as follows: Towit:
<lb/>"The Committee on claims having examined the accounts and vouchers of J. B. Thompson Jr. Sergeant at Arms find the same correct and that he has expended the sum of One-Hundred and ninety six <hi rend="sup">50</hi>/<hi rend="sub">100</hi> Dollars which they recommend be paid and offer the following resolution:
<lb/>Resolved That the Auditor draw a warrant on the Treasurer of the Provisional Government of Kentucky in favor of J. B. Thompson Jr. for the sum of one Hundred and Ninety six <hi rend="sup">50</hi>/<hi rend="sub">100</hi> Dollars in full of expenditures by him for this Government up to this date.</p>
<p>said report was accepted and said resolution adopted</p>
<p>The <orgName ref="cwgk:O00011356">Committee on Banks</orgName> reported a bill entitled "an act to amend an act entitled an act to empower the Governor to appoint a commissioner to the confederate States of America on the subject of Banks. Which was read a first time</p>
<p>On motion the rule of the council constitutional provision and second reading were dispensed with.</p>
<p>Mr H. W. Bruce offered the following amendment Towit
<lb/>"Amend by striking out wherever they occur the words "the Southern Bank and branches"
<lb/>and the question being put on the adoption of said amendment it was rejected.
<lb/>Messrs H. W. Bruce and Crockett having demanded the ayes and noes and being called resulted as follows.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">115</note>
<lb/>Those who voted in the affirmative were
<lb/>Messrs Crockett, Burnside, H. W. Bruce and Scott -- 4 -- 
<lb/>Those who voted in the negative were
<lb/>Messrs Bates Thompson, E. M. Bruce, and Moore -- 4 -- </p>
<p>A message from the Governor by Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee was received announcing that he had approved and signed the following bills -- Towit:
<lb/>An act to district the State and provide for the election of Members to the House of Representatives of the Confederate States.
<lb/>An act to raise and arm thirty Regiments of volunteer Infantry and Cavalry.</p>
<p>And then the Council adjourned until tomorrow at 10 O'Clock A M</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00001858">A. Frank Brown</persName> Clerk</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
