<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1302"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Patterson to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10770</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Matthew Roberts</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-191</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-08-26">26 August 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the <persName ref="cwgk:N00000258">Govenor</persName> of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Commonwealth. of Kentucky</orgName>-</p>
<p>Your petitioner <persName ref="cwgk:N00004883">John Patterson</persName> states that at the <date when="1860-10">October term of the Mercer Circuit Court 1860</date> he was indicted by a <hi rend="underline">grand</hi> <hi rend="underline">jury</hi> of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000556">Mercer County</placeName> for the offence of gaming with a slave ^named <persName ref="cwgk:N00018105">Alfred</persName> the property of <persName ref="cwgk:N00018003">Rhodd Kirkland</persName>^ and at the <date when="1861-04">April term of said court 1861,</date> a judgement for the sum of Seventy five Dollars was rendered against your petitioner -- </p>
<p>Your petitioner further states that the indictment was found upon the testimony of <persName ref="cwgk:N00018006">John Simonis Jr</persName>, and the judgement also rendered upon said Simonis' testimony alone-</p>
<p>Your petitioner says that on the trial of said indictment, John Simonis Jr, the only witness in the cause Swore that one <persName ref="cwgk:N00018012">John Kirkland </persName>and <persName ref="cwgk:N00018013">John Henry</persName> were present on the ground, and where said gaming was going on, and said this petitioner and said slave engaged in said game when indeed and in fact said gaming*<pb/>
<lb/>*never took place between your petitioner and said slave nor any other slave and that neither said John Kirkland nor John Henry saw any such gaming at said time and place stated by the Witness Simonis: as will appear from their Several affidavits, filed herewith: and the affidavit of <persName ref="cwgk:N00018014">Moses M William</persName> one of the Jury rendering said Verdect. showing the statement of said Simonis on the Trial.</p>
<p>Your petitioner says that he is well disposed towards the laws of the land and <hi rend="str">not</hi> does not intend nor did he violate the law in the case, or was he in any ^way^ guilty of the offence changed -- </p>
<p>Wherefore your petitioner respectfully asks the interposition of the Executive Clemency in his behalf. and that said fine saving cost &amp;c be remitted.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>^att.^ <persName ref="cwgk:N00006156">Henry Taylor</persName>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John ^his X mark^ Patterson<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>Sworn to before me by John Patterson this <date when="1861-08-26">26 Aug 1861.</date></p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00003198">E. J. Polk</persName> Examiner for Mercer Co</p>
<p>Affidavit of <persName ref="cwgk:N00003280">B. C. Allen</persName>-</p>
<p>The Affiant B. C. Allen says that the<pb/>
<lb/>Petitioner of John Patterson was indicted and convicted of the foregoing charge and that this affiant was present at said trial and heard the testimony of John Simonis; and that said simonis stated on said trial that one John Kirkland &amp; John Henry were present at the time of the alledged gaming, and saw the same- Neither of which were introduced by the common wealth- Affiant will not be positive as to the given names of Henry &amp; Kirkland but it is his impression that those are the given names.</p>
   <p><hi rend="underline">Ben</hi> <hi rend="underline">C.</hi> <hi rend="underline">Allin</hi></p>
<p>Sworn to before me by B. C. Allen this day <date when="1861-09">Septr 1861</date></p>
<p>E. J Park Examiner for Mercer Co</p>
<p>To the Gov Com of Ky</p>
<p>The affiant John Kirkland says that he knows nothing of the offince charged in the indictment aforesaid against John Patterson for gaming with the slave Alfred belonging to Rhoda Kirkland nor was he present at any time when said gaming was done</p>
<p>John Kirkland</p>
<p>The affiant John Henry says that he knows nothing of the offince charged against the said John Patterson for gaming with the the slave Alfred belonging to Rhoda Kirkland, nor was he present at the time of said gaming nor did he see the same -- </p>
<p>John Henry J. P.</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by John Kirkland and John Henry, this <date when="1861-09-04">4 Septr <hi rend="str">Aug</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00018053">A Cummins</persName> J P M C<pb/></p>
<p>we the undersigned petitioners respectfully unite in the prayer of the foregoing petition.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/><hi rend="underline">Names</hi>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00018055">James C Runsdell</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00018133">T. B. Hilingate</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00018062">John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Intyre</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006740">J.. C.. McIntire</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00018064">O, Lester</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00018067">W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>, F, Toms</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00018068">W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Mays</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00018069">F Norvell</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00018070">E. F. Matherly</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00018071">R. Leonard</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00018092">John Lester</persName>
<lb/>Henry Taylor
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00018094">Jas. T. Hale</persName>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Ben C. Allen</hi>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00002330">S S M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Fatney</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00018104">W S M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Intyre</persName>
<lb/>M M Williams
<lb/>E. J. Polk
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00002250">John Haveres Jr</persName>
<lb/><cb n="2"/><hi rend="underline">Names</hi><milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>Mercer Cir Ct</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B, M</p>
<p>$75. } gaming with negro
<lb/>Jno. Patterson</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-12-18">Dec<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 18. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
