<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0004-033-0040"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky, Journal</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG16338</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>##</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Louisville</settlement>
      <repository>Filson Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>Kentucky Confederate Provisional Government Journal</collection>
      <idno>p. 119-124</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-01-01">1 January 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Journal</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">119</note>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Wednesday </hi><date when="1862-01-01"><hi rend="underline">January 1</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 1862</hi></date></p>
<p>The Council met. J. P. Bates President Protem in the Chair.</p>
<p>Mr H. W. Bruce from a select Committee reported a bill entitled "An act to amend an act entitled an act to raise and arms thirty Regiments of volunteer Infantry and Cavalry"
<lb/>Which was then read a first time -- 
<lb/>On motion the rule of the Council Constitutional provision and second and third readings were dispensed with -- 
<lb/>The question was then taken on the passage of the bill and it was decided in the affirmative.
<lb/>And the bill passed
<lb/>Ordered that the title be as reported</p>
<p>A message from the Governor by Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee was received announcing his approval of the bond of Major W. R. Cunningham as revenue Commissioner -- 
<lb/>On motion said approval was confirmed by the Council.</p>
<p>On motion Mr H. W. Bruce was appointed a committee to call on the Governor and ask his consent to return to this council without action an enrolled bill entitled "an act to amend an act entitled an act to empower the Governor to appoint a commissioner to the Confederate States of America on the subject of Banks.</p>
<p>Mr Bruce reported that he had conferred with Governor and that he having consented to return said bill, he now laid it before the council -- </p>
<p>Mr Moore then moved that the vote by which said bill was passed and also the vote ordering said bill to its third reading be reconsidered- which motion prevailed -- 
<lb/>Whereupon said bill was referred to the Committee on Banks</p>
<p>The Council then took a recess until till 12 O'Clock M.</p>
<p>The Council met at 12 O'Clock M. Mr Crockett in the chair.</p>
<p>A message from the Governor by Mr M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Kee Secretary of State -- 
<lb/>Mr President: I am directed by the Governor to lay before this Council a special message in writing:</p>
<p>Executive Office
<lb/>Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-12-29">December 29. 1861</date>
<lb/>Gentlemen of the Council of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>I herewith inclose a communication<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header"><unclear>120</unclear></note>
<lb/>from Hopkinsville as to the management of the Lunatic Asylum. If the Council, shall consider this letter as sufficient evidence, on which to supersede the Old Managers, I herewith nominate the gentlemen recommended in this Communication, as a Board of Managers of the Western Lunatic Asylum at Hopkinsville Towit: A. D. Sears, H. A. Phelps, W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> A. Glass D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> T. G. Henry, and Thomas Green</p>
<p>George W. Johnson</p>
<p>The communication referred to reads as follows Towit:</p>
<p>"Hopkinsville Ky <date when="1861-12-23">Decem. 23.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Hon<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> George W. Johnson
<lb/>Gov. State of Ky.
<lb/>Bowling Green
<lb/>Sir.</p>
<p>The management of the Western Lunatic Asylum at this place has been in the hands of our enemies for some time and we have good reason to believe has been used to the prejudice of our cause.</p>
<p>General Clark in command here desires that immediate change be made through the Civil authorities, and requested the Military board to communicate with you. A change of the board of Commissioners, with authority to take charge of the means &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi> would effect the object.</p>
<p>We recommend the appointment of the following board Rev<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> A. D. Sears, H. A. Phelps, W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> A Glass, Doct T. G. Henry Thomas Green -- We suggest that the first intimation of a change be made known here by the authority to take possession</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Tho. S. Bryan 
<lb/>J Landes &#125; Mil. Board.</p>
<p>On motion said Message was referred to the committee on Ways and Means</p>
<p>A Message from the Governor by Mr M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Kee Secretary of State:
<lb/>Mr President: I am directed by the Governor to lay before this Council a special message in writing:
<lb/>Executive Office
<lb/>Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1862-01-01">January 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>Gentlemen of the Council of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>I nominate William Preston for the Office of Major General of the State forces of Kentucky.
<lb/>I nominate Joseph H. Morehead as a suitable person to raise a Regiment.
<lb/>I nominate J. Stoddard Byers as a suitable person to raise a Regiment.
<lb/>I nominate William P Bramblette as a suitable person to raise a Regiment.
<lb/>I nominate W. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c </hi></hi>C Menifee as a suitable person to raise a Regiment
<lb/>I nominate Guilford O. Talbott as Inspector for the County of Warren<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">121</note>
<lb/>I nominate J. H Nelson as Inspector for the County of Logan
<lb/>I nominate William Ratcliffee as Inspector for the County of Pike
<lb/>I nominate Green Witten as Inspector for the County of Floyd.
<lb/>I nominate Joseph H. Gardner as Inspector for the County of Magoffin
<lb/>I nominate John W. Kendall as Inspector for the County of Morgan
<lb/>I nominate John Hargis Jr as Inspector for the County of Breathitt</p>
<p>George W. Johnson</p>
<p>On Motion the entire list of nominations embraced in the foregoing Message was confirmed by the Council.</p>
<p>Mr Scott moved that before the Council proceed to election of Confederate Senators, a committee be appointed to inform the Governor that this Council is now ready to proceed to said election and invite him to participate therein
<lb/>Messrs H. W. Bruce and Moore having required the ayes and naes thereon and the call being made resulted as follows:
<lb/>Those who voted in the affirmative were Messrs
<lb/>Crockett, Bates, E. M. Bruce, and Scott -- 4 -- 
<lb/>Those who voted in the negative were Messrs
<lb/>Thompson, Burnside, H. W. Bruce and Moore -- 4-</p>
<p>And before the result of said call was announced by the chair Mr Bates moved an adjournment -- which motion was also withdrawn</p>
<p>Mr Bates then moved that the Council do now proceed to the election of Senators.</p>
<p>Mr Thompson then renewed the Motion to adjourn and the question being put was lost.</p>
<p>The question was then upon the motion to elect Senators -- and before the same was put said Motion was withdrawn.</p>
<p>Mr Bates moved that the Council do now proceed to the election of Senators and that the Governor be invited to preside at said election.
<lb/>Mr Thompson called for a division of the question</p>
<p>The question being first on the Motion to go into an election and Messrs Thompson and Moore having demanded the ayes and noes thereon -- the call was made and resulted as follows Twit:
<lb/>Those who voted in the affirmative were Messrs
<lb/>Bates, Burnside, E. M. Bruce, Moore and Scott. -- 5 -- 
<lb/>Those who voted in the negative were Messrs
<lb/>Crockett, Thompson, and H. W. Bruce -- 3</p>
<p>Before the result of said vote was announced by the chair<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">122</note>
<lb/>the question having been made, the chair decided that the Governor is entitled to a vote in the question before the Council.</p>
<p>Mr Bates appealed from the decision of the chair- to the Council and Messrs Thompson and H. W. Bruce having demanded the ayes and noes thereon- the call resulted as follows viz.Those who voted in the affirmative were Messrs 
<lb/>Bates, Burnside, E. M. Bruce and Moore -- 4 -- 
<lb/>Those who voted in the negative were Messrs 
<lb/>Thompson, H. W. Bruce and Scott -- 3 -- </p>
<p>Mr Crockett asked &amp; obtained the leaves of the council to be excused from voting on said question -- </p>
<p>The result of said vote was then announced and said appeal was sustained</p>
<p>The President then announced the result of the vote on the first branch of Mr Bates Motion to be in the affirmative.</p>
<p>The question was then taken on the second branch of Mr Bates Motion- and Messrs Thompson and Moore having demanded the ayes and naes and the call being made resulted as follows-
<lb/>Those who voted in the affirmative were Messrs 
<lb/>Crockett, Bates, Thompson H. W. Bruce, E M Bruce, and Scott -- <hi rend="str">5</hi>6 -- 
<lb/>Those who voted in the negative were Messrs 
<lb/>Burnside and Moore -- 2 -- 
<lb/>And the motion prevailed -- </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Senatorial Electoral College</hi></p>
<p>Governor George W. Johnson was invited to, and took the chair and then the Council was resolved into an electoral college to elect two Senators to the Confederate Congress.</p>
<p>Mr Crockett moved that the two absent members Messrs Machen and Chrisman should have the privilege of recording their votes in said election, provided they appear in this Council within ten days,- in the event there shall be opposing candidates in nomination for said Office -- and that the result of the vote cast in this electoral college shall not be announced until the expiration of ten days.</p>
<p>Mr Scott moved to amend by allowing said absent members to vote at any time during the session of the Council whenever they shall appear-
<lb/>said amendment was accepted by Mr Crockett.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">123</note>
<lb/>Mr Moore moved to postpone said election and the further consideration of the subject until the <date when="1862-01-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of January 1862</date> at 11 O Clock A. M. and that it be made the special order of the day for that hour-
<lb/>Which motion prevailed</p>
<p>Mr. E. M. Bruce moved that the Clerk be instructed to notify the absent members- Messrs Machen and Chrisman of the time of said election- which motion prevailed-</p>
<p>Mr Moore moved that this electoral College do now adjourn until Thursday the <date when="1862-01-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Inst</date> at 11 O'Clock A. M. which motion prevailed</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/>A. Frank Brown Clerk</p>
<p>The Council resumed its general session Mr Crockett in the chair.</p>
<p>And then on motion the Council adjourned until 7 O'Clock P M.</p>
<p>Night Session</p>
<p>The Council met. Mr Crockett in the chair.</p>
<p>The committee on Enrollments reported that they had examined an enrolled bill entitled "an act to raise and arm thirty regiments of volunteer Infantry and Cavalry" And that they had found the same Truly enrolled- Whereupon the President Pro. tem. affixed his signature thereto-</p>
<p>A Message from the Governor by Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee Secretary of State:
<lb/>Mr President: I am directed by the Governor to lay before this Council a verbal message Towit: The Governor has approved and signed an enrolled bill entitled "an act to amend an act entitled an act to raise and arm thirty regiments of volunteer Infantry and Cavalry"</p>
<p>The Committee on Banks to whom was referred a bill entitled an "An act to amend an act to empower the Governor to appoint a commissioner to the Confederate States on the subject of Banks "reported a substitute therefore which was then read a first time as follows. "An act to amend an act entitled an act to empower the Governor to appoint a Commissioner to the Confederate States of America on the subject of Banks"</p>
<p>Whereas the Council are in possession of facts and information which satisfy them that many of the Banks in the State of Kentucky have furnished their means and credit for the purpose of raising<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">124</note>
<lb/>troops in Kentucky to assist the Federal Government in carrying on the present war of attempted subjugation against the Confederate States -- and whereas the so called Legislature at Frankfort Kentucky have attempted to exercise the extraordinary and unwarranted power of dissolving the connection between several of those Banks and their Branches:
<lb/>Now in order to protect the good people of this State against such flagrant usurpations of power and such unmitigated outrages upon <hi rend="str">our</hi>their rights.
<lb/>Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Council of the Provisional Government of the State of Kentucky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
