<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-006-0091"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Richard J. Oglesby, Requisition</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1137</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Brian M. Trump</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Daniel Farrell</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Charles R. Welsko</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR6-116</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Springfield, Sangamon County, Illinois</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-17">17 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><persName ref="cwgk:N00006923">RICHARD J. OGLESBY</persName>,
<lb/><figure type="seal"><ab>STATE
<lb/>SOVEREIGNTY
<lb/>NATIONAL UNION</ab></figure>
<lb/>GOVERNOR OF THE <orgName ref="cwgk:O00014696">STATE OF ILLINOIS</orgName>.
<lb/>To any Sheriff, Coroner or Constable of any County in this <placeName ref="cwgk:P00004765">State</placeName>, -- Greeting:</p>
   <p>Whereas, It has been made known to me by the <persName ref="cwgk:N001000">Executive authority</persName> of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">State of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Kentucky</placeName></orgName> that <persName ref="cwgk:N00019873">Matthew Skifington</persName> stands charged in the state of <placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">Kentucky</placeName> with the crime of Felony and that the said Matthew Skifington has fled from the justice of said State and taken refuge in the State of Illinois:</p>
<p>Now, therefore, I, RICHARD J. OGLESBY, Governor of the State of Illinois, pursuant to the Constitution and laws of the <placeName ref="cwgk:P001802">United States</placeName>, and of this State, do hereby command you to arrest and apprehend the said Matthew Skifington if he be found within the limits of the State aforesaid, and cause him to be safely kept, and delivered to the custody of <persName ref="cwgk:N00005313">William Hipwell</persName> who has been duly constituted the agent of the said State of Kentucky to receive said fugitive from the justice of said State, he paying all fees and charges for the arrest and apprehension of said Matthew Skifington and make due return to the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00020644">Executive Department of this State</orgName>, the manner in which this writ may be executed.</p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>SEAL OF THE STATE OF ILLINOIS
<lb/><unclear>STATE
<lb/>SOVEREIGNTY
<lb/>NATIONAL UNION</unclear>
<lb/>1818</ab></figure></p>
<p>In Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto set my hand, and caused the Great Seal of State to be hereunto affixed. Done at the City of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00015391">Springfield</placeName>, this <date when="1865-10-17">17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of October in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and sixty five,</date> and of the Independence of the United States the ninetieth</p>
<p>Richard J. Oglesby
<lb/>By the Governor:
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00019892">Sharon Tyndale</persName>
<lb/>Secretary of State.<pb/></p>
<p>State of Illinois
<lb/><placeName ref="cwgk:P00019883">Peoria County</placeName> ss.</p>
<p>I, <persName ref="cwgk:N00019904">D. A. Wheeler</persName> a constable in and for said county and the <placeName ref="cwgk:P00019884">City of Peoria</placeName> did arrest, by and in pursuance of the within warrant, the within named Mathew Skifington and delivered his body and person into the custody of the withinnamed W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Hipwell, all of which was done at the city of Peoria on the <date when="1865-10-18">18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of October AD 1865.</date></p>
<p>D. A. Wheeler P. C</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
