<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011978">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John J. Ellis </title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011978">
                    <persName>
                      John J. Ellis 
                        (Jefferson County, KY, grocer &amp; flour dealer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1826"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1826</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Jefferson County, Kentucky, chairmaker, grocer, and wholesale flour dealer. New York native. Married to Sarah Ann Leatherman Ellis in Jefferson County on May 16, 1849. Father of Sarah E. “Libbie” Ellis, Josephine “Josie” A. Ellis, Ida May Ellis, Dixie D. Ellis, and Lee Ellis. Chairmaker in Columbus, Ohio, in 1850. Grocer in Louisville in 1860. Signed a petition as a wholesale flour dealer in May 1861 to appoint W. G. Timberlake as flour inspector.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Ohio, Franklin County, Columbus, p. 329A.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 1, p. 128.

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 6, p. 579A.

<hi rend="italic">Tenth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1880), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Enumeration District 108, p. 9B.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film #000482707, p. 382.

KYR-0001-017-0163.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
