<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010674">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Walter H. Peters</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010674">
                    <persName>
                      Walter H. Peters
                        (New Orleans, Louisiana, attorney and state official)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1827"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1827</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>New Orleans, Louisiana, attorney and state official. New York native. Married to Mary T. Peters. Clerk in New Orleans, Louisiana in 1850. Attorney in New Orleans, Louisiana in 1860. Employed Ellen Murray in New Orleans, Louisiana in 1860. Owned three enslaved persons in New Orleans, Louisiana in 1860. Notary public in New Orleans, Louisiana in 1861. Appointed commissioner for Commonwealth of Kentucky in Louisiana in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Louisiana, Orleans County, New Orleans, p. 135.<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Louisiana, Orleans County, New Orleans, p. 135. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Louisiana, Orleans County, New Orleans, p. 212. New Orleans, Louisiana, City Directory, 1861, U.S. City Directories, 1822-1995, 351, (accessed via ancestry.com). KYR-0001-007-0084.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
