<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003857">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Benjamin M. Winston</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003857">
                    <persName>
                      Benjamin M. Winston
                        (Union County, Kentucky, merchant, postmaster, and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1815"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1815</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Union County, Kentucky, merchant, postmaster, and soldier. Virginia native. Married to Annie Elizabeth Long Winston in Union County on September 26, 1850. Father of Charles Winston, Louisa Winston, Virginia Winston, and William Winston.  Merchant in Union County in 1850. Postmaster in Caseyville, Kentucky from July 6, 1853 to June 26, 1855. Merchant in Union County in 1860. Member of the convention of the provisional government held at Russellville in November 1861. Served in Winston&#39;s Scouts (C.S.A.) as a captain from 1861 to 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Union County, District 2, p. 519A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Union County, Caseyville, p. 559.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Union County, Caseyville, p. 420A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, Henderson Ward 2, p. 106B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Tenth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1880), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Union County, Morganfield, p. 529C.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Union County Marriages, Film #000562200, p. 143.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Record of Appointment of Postmasters, 1832-1971</hi>, NARA Microfilm Publication M841, Records of the Post Office Department, RG 28, Union County, Kentucky, Volume 14, (accessed via Ancestry.com on November 6, 2019), p. 354 of microfilm.<lb/>
U. S. War Department. <hi rend="italic">The War of the Rebellion: Formal reports, both Union and Confederate, of the first seizures of United States property in the Southern States</hi>. Washington, DC: Government Printing Office, 1897. Volume 53, pp. 1161, 1173-4, 1303.<lb/>
KYR-0001-029-0538. <lb/>
KYR-0001-029-0539. <lb/>
KYR-0004-033-0001.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
