<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00020507">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Theodore Droppelman</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00020507">
                    <persName>
                      Theodore Droppelman
                        (Louisville, Kentucky, tavernkeeper)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1829-09"  ><ab>1829-09</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1881-03"  ><ab>1881-03</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, tavernkeeper. Native of Hanover. Married to Mary Drichans Droppelman in Jefferson County, Kentucky, on May 4, 1854. Father of Mary Droppelman, Bernard Droppelman, Louisa Droppelman, Elizabeth Droppelman, and Theodore Droppelman. Tavernkeeper in partnership with Bernard Reiling in Reiling &amp; Company in Louisville, Kentucky, in 1860. Tavernkeeper in Louisville in 1861. Tavernkeeper in Louisville in 1863. Tavernkeeper in Louisville in 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 4, p. 22.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 7, p. 16A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Jefferson County, KY, June 1863, p. 128.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film 000819600.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Tanner’s Louisville Directory and Business Advertiser for 1861</hi> ed. Henry Tanner (Louisville: Directory Publication and Advertising Agency, 1861), 77, 203.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Edwards&#39; Annual Director to the Inhabitants, Institutions, Incorporated Companies, Manufacturing Establishments, Business firms, Etc., Etc., in the City of Louisville, For 1865-6</hi> (Louisville: Edwards, Greenough &amp; Deved, 1866), 280.<lb/>
&quot;Theodor Droppelmann (1829-1881),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 154536561, accessed July 28, 2023, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/154536561.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
