<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010374">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Queen</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010374">
                    <persName>
                      William Queen
                        (Nelson County, Kentucky, merchant)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1816"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1816</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Nelson County, Kentucky, merchant. Kentucky native. Son of James Queen and Elizabeth Boone Queen.  Married to Susan E. Hayden in Nelson County in May 1842. Father of Edward Queen. Married to Hettie Smith Queen. Father of Mary Queen and Pearley Queen. Resident of Nelson County in 1840. Merchant in Nelson County in 1850. Employed Lewis Queen and Lee Queen as clerks in Nelson County in 1850. Owned three enslaved persons in Nelson County in 1860. Merchant in Nelson County in 1860. Owned seven enslaved persons in Nelson County in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Sixth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1840), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, North East Division, p. 31.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 2, p. 386B.<lb/>
 <hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 2, p. 237, p. 17 of microfilm.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 1, p. 193.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 1, p.111A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, Bardstown, p. 64B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky, County Marriage Records, 1783-1965</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Film # 000481488, Nelson County, p. 103  (accessed via ancestry.com). <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky, County Marriage Records, 1783-1965</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Film # 000009668, Nelson County, May 31, 1842 (accessed via ancestry.com). <lb/>
Mackenzie, George Norbury, and Nelson Osgood Rhoades, editors. <hi rend="italic">Colonial Families of the United States of America: in Which is Given the History, Genealogy and Armorial Bearings of Colonial Families Who Settled in the American Colonies From the Time of the Settlement of Jamestown, 13th May, 1607, to the Battle of Lexington, 19th April, 1775</hi>. 7 volumes. 1912. Reprinted, Baltimore: Genealogical Publishing Co., Inc., 1966, 1995, p.443.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
