<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010312">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Constantine Culbertson</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010312">
                    <persName>
                      William Constantine Culbertson
                        (Kenton Co, Ky, and Pennsylvania, lumber dealer and mill operator)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1825-11-27"  ><ab>1825-11-27</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1906-05-24"  ><ab>1906-05-24</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Kenton County, Kentucky, and Pennsylvania lumber dealer and mill operator. Edinboro, Erie County, Pennsylvania, native. Son of Andrew C. Culbertson and Margaret Alexander Culbertson. Married to Margaret Culbertson.. Father of Delia Culbertson, Kate Culbertson, James Culbertson, Maggie Culbertson, William Culbertson, and Belle Culbertson. Engaged in the lumber industry in Jefferson County, Pennsylvania, before moving to Kentucky. Lumber merchant and mill operator in Covington in 1860. Employed Mary Rechtein and Mary Walking as servants in 1860. Lumber dealer in Kenton County in 1863. Moved back to Pennsylvania to engage in further timbering and land acquisition in 1863.\</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, Covington Ward 7, pp. 895-96.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Kentucky, 6th Congressional District, Vol. 1, June and July 1863, p. 93, p. 190 of microfilm, (Accessed via ancestry.com on April 2, 2020).<lb/>
Pennsylvania Historic and Museum Commission; Harrisburg, Pennsylvania; Pennsylvania (State). Death certificates, 1906–1967; Certificate Number Range: 041971-045380, File #43973, p. 2115 of microfilm.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;William Constantine Culbertson (1809-1884),&quot; Memorial 7774923, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/7774923  (accessed April 2, 2020).<lb/>
United States House of Representatives, <hi rend="italic">History, Art &amp; Archives: United States House of Representatives</hi>, “CULBERTSON, William Constantine,”<lb/>
https://history.house.gov/People/Listing/C/CULBERTSON,-William-Constantine-(C000965)/, (Accessed on April 2, 2020).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
