<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008199">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Albert Sidney Johnston</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008199">
                    <persName>
                      Albert Sidney Johnston
                        (Soldier in the U.S. Army and Confederate Army)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1803-02-02"  ><ab>1803-02-02</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1862-04-06"  ><ab>1862-04-06</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Soldier in the U.S. Army and Confederate Army. Washington, Kentucky, native. Married to Henrietta Preston Johnston in 1829. Married Eliza Griffin Johnston in 1843. Attended Transylvania University. Graduated from the United States Military Academy at West Point, New York, in 1826. Veteran of the Black Hawk War. Relocated to Texas in 1836. Enlisted in the Texas army. Veteran of the Texas Revolution. Senior brigadier general and commander of the Texas army in 1837. Secretary of war for the Republic of Texas from 1838 to 1840. Resigned and returned to farm in Brazoria County, Texas. Veteran of the Mexican-American War. Paymaster of the U.S. army in 1849. Commanded the 2nd U.S. Cavalry Regiment in 1855. Commanded the Department of Texas in 1856. Brevetted brigadier general in 1859. Commanded the Department of the Pacific of the U.S. Army in 1861. Resigned from the U.S. Army in 1861. Appointed a full general in the Confederate Army in 1861. Commanded the Western Department of the Confederate Army. Died at the Battle of Shiloh on April 6, 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl>Charles P. Roland, <hi rend="italic">Albert Sidney Johnston: Soldier of Three Republics</hi> (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 2001). <lb/>
Wright, John D., <hi rend="italic">The Routledge Encyclopedia of Civil War Era Biographies</hi>, (New York: Routledge, 2013), 318. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
