<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00017052">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Rhodes Viley</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00017052">
                    <persName>
                      John Rhodes Viley
                        (Fayette County, Kentucky, farmer, banker, major and quartermaster (C.S.A.))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1821-02-20"  ><ab>1821-02-20</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1880-12-21"  ><ab>1880-12-21</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Fayette County, Kentucky, farmer, banker, and soldier. Kentucky native. Son of Willie Viley and Carrie C. Hall Viley. Married to Mary S. Johnson Viley in Scott County, Kentucky, on November 27, 1843. Father of John F. Viley, Willa Viley, and Bettie F. Viley. Farmer in Washington County, Mississippi, in 1850. Owned forty-seven enslaved persons in Washington County in 1850. Employed Samuel E. Roberts as an overseer in Washington County in 1850. President of the Lexington Racing Association in Fayette County, Kentucky, in 1855. Director of the Northern Bank of Kentucky in Fayette County in 1857. Farmer in Fayette County in 1860. Owned sixteen enslaved persons in Fayette County in 1860. Director of the Northern Bank of Kentucky in Fayette County in 1860. Director of the Northern Bank of Kentucky in Fayette County until 1862. Served in the First Kentucky Brigade, Lewis&#39;s Brigade, and Bate&#39;s Division of the Army of Tennessee (C.S.A.) as major and quartermaster from October 25, 1862, to April 25, 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Mississippi, Washington County, p. 248B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Mississippi, Washington County, p. 499.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, District 2, p. 302.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, District 2, p. 431A-B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, Precinct 4, p. 89A-B. <lb/>
&quot;Bank Matters,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY), May 7, 1857. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Confederate Soldiers who Served in Organizations from the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M319, Roll 0255.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Scott County Marriages, Film #000183225.<lb/>
&quot;Northern Bank of Kentucky,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Daily Courier</hi> (Louisville, KY), May 17, 1860. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Sons of the American Revolution Membership Applications, 1889-1970</hi>, National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, Louisville, Ky, National #87083, State #58.<lb/>
Edwin Porter Thompson, <hi rend="italic">History of the First Kentucky Brigade</hi> (Cincinnati: Caxton Publication House, 1868), 165.<lb/>
George Washington Ranck, <hi rend="italic">History of Lexington, Kentucky: Its Early Annals and Recent Progress</hi> (Cincinnati: Robert Clarke &amp; Company, 1872), 133. <lb/>
&quot;John Rhodes Viley (1821-1880),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #98505600, accessed January 17, 2022, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/98505600.<lb/>
KYR-0001-031-0075.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
