<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00012531">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Palmer Satterwhite</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kristen Bailey</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Kristen Bailey</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00012531">
                    <persName>
                      Thomas Palmer Satterwhite
                        (Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky, physician)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1835-07-21"  ><ab>1835-07-21</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1917-06-03"  ><ab>1917-06-03</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky, physician. Lexington, Kentucky, native. Son of Thomas P. Satterwhite and Mary Calwell Breckinridge Satterwhite. Married to Maria Preston Pope Rogers Satterwhite in Louisville, Kentucky, on January 14, 1858. Father of Lilly R. Satterwhite and Thomas P. Satterwhite Jr. Graduate of Medical College of Louisville in Louisville in 1857. Student in Fayette County in 1850. Physician in Louisville in 1860. Employed Margaret Smith as a domestic servant in Louisville in 1860. Employed one enslaved person owned by William Ronalds in Louisville in 1860. Demonstrator of Anatomy of the Medical Department of Louisville in 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, District 2, p. 225A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 5, p. 138.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, p. 274A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 5, p. 546A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Dr. Thomas Palmer Satterwhite (July 21, 1835-June 3, 1917),&quot; Memorial #6589268, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/6589268 (accessed May 2, 2020). <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film #000482708 , p. 58.<lb/>
&quot;Death Claims Noted Doctor,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, Ky.), June 4, 1917, p. 1-2.<lb/>
&quot;University of Louisville Medical Department&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, Ky.), September 13, 1864, p. 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Directory of Deceased American Physicians, 1804-1929</hi> viewed on Ancestry.com.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">A centennial history of the University of Louisville</hi>, Federal Writers&#39; Project of the Work Projects Administration for the State of Kentucky (1939) Louisville, Kentucky: The University of Louisville, p. 67.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Vital Statistics Original Death Certificates – Microfilm (1911-1964)</hi>, KDLA, Roll #7016196, Jefferson County Deaths, File #17290. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
