<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00012091">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Warren Akin</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00012091">
                    <persName>
                      Warren Akin
                        (Cass County, Georgia, attorney and politician (CSA))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1811-10-09"  ><ab>1811-10-09</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1877-12-17"  ><ab>1877-12-17</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Cass County, Georgia, attorney and politician. Georgia native. Married Eliza Harper Akin in c1835. Father of Eliza H. Akin, Elbert Akin, Thomas W. Akin, Henry C. Akin, and John Wesley Akin. Married to Mary F. Akin. Established law practice in Cassville, Georgia in 1836. Admitted to Cherokee County, Georgia Supreme Court in 1836. Attorney in Cass County, Georgia in 1850. Owned fourteen enslaved persons in Cass County in 1850. Unsuccessful Opposition Party candidate for governor of Georgia in 1859. Attorney in Cass County in 1860. Owned fourteen enslaved persons in Cass County in 1860. Speaker of the Georgia House of Representatives in 1861. Member of the Confederate States Congress in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Georgia, Cass County, Division 12, p. 345.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Georgia, Cass County, Division 12, p. 999.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Georgia, Cass County, Georgia Militia District, p. 852.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Georgia, Cass County, District 828, p. 359A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Warren Akin Sr. (1811-1877),&quot; Memorial #9302, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/9302 (accessed January 28, 2020).<lb/>
“Warren Akin, Sr.- Confederate Congressman,” Etowah Valley Historical Society, https://evhsonline.org/bartow-history/people/warren-akin-sr-confederate-congressman. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
