<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00020476">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Levi</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00020476">
                    <persName>
                      James Levi
                        (Louisville, Kentucky, painter and lightning rod manufacturer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1826-09-13"  ><ab>1826-09-13</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1889-06-18"  ><ab>1889-06-18</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, painter and lightning rod manufacturer. Kentucky native. Married to Miranda Levi. Father of Charles E. Levi and Amanda Levi. Married to Jane Amanda Courtenay Levi in Jefferson County, Kentucky, on January 30, 1856. Father of Jennie Levi. Painter in Louisville, Kentucky, in 1850. Lightning rod manufacturer in Louisville in 1860. Lightning rod manufacturer in Louisville in 1861. Painter in Jefferson County in 1863. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 8, p. 392B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 8, p. 664.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Indiana, Floyd County, Georgetown, p. 161B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994041, Jefferson County Deaths.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film 000819604.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Jefferson County, KY, July 1863, p. 145.<lb/>
 <hi rend="italic">Tanner’s Louisville Directory and Business Advertiser for 1861</hi> ed. Henry Tanner (Louisville: Directory Publication and Advertising Agency, 1861), 150.<lb/>
&quot;James Levi (1826-1889),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 76073053, accessed July 21, 2023, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/76073053.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
