<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00020989">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Washington A. Gale</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>A. J. Blaylock</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>A. J. Blaylock</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00020989">
                    <persName>
                      Washington A. Gale
                        (Franklin County, Kentucky, carpenter and soldier (Priv. 6th Ky. Cav. U.S.A.))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1813"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1813</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Franklin County, Kentucky, carpenter. Frankfort, Kentucky, native. Married to Milly Moorehead Gale in Garrard County, Kentucky, on January 15, 1834. Father of Frances Gale, William Gale, James Gale, Thomas Gale, George Gale, Mary Gale, and Sarah Gale. Carpenter in Franklin County in 1850. Carpenter in Franklin County in 1860. Served in the 6th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry Regiment (U.S.A.) as a private from December 23, 1861 to October 12, 1862. Discharged on account of disability on October 12, 1862. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, District 1, p. 42A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, p. 254.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Garrard County Marriages, Film 000183256.<lb/>
&quot;Gale, Washington A.,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers Who Served in Organizations From the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0064.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), p. 146.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
