<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00014925">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Finis McLean Allison</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Rachael Nicholas</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00014925">
                    <persName>
                      Finis McLean Allison
                        (Butler County, Kentucky, lawyer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1829-03-04"  ><ab>1829-03-04</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1886-04-12"  ><ab>1886-04-12</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Butler County, Kentucky, attorney. Kentucky native. Son of John Adair Allison and Frances Watkins Allison. Married to Julia A. Burks Allison in Muhlenberg County, Kentucky, on August 1, 1849. Father of Lucy Allison, Finis H. Allison, John Allison, Alice Allison, James Allison, and Naomi Allison. Attorney in Muhlenberg County in 1850. Clerk in Morgantown in 1860. Owned one enslaved person in Woodbury in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Muhlenberg County, Subdivision 2, p. 272A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Butler County, Morgantown, p. 1007.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Butler County, Woodbury, p. 10.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Muhlenberg County, Greenville, p. 449B-450A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Muhlenberg County Marriages, Film #000557316, p. 54.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Sons of the American Revolution Membership Applications, 1889-1970</hi>, National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, Louisville, Ky, Allison, National #7746, State #959.<lb/>
&quot;Finis McLean Allison (1827-1886),&quot; Find A Grave,  Memorial #71451016, accessed June 30, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/71451016.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
