<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010653">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Philip Tomppert </title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
          </respStmt>        
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010653">
                    <persName>
                      Philip Tomppert 
                        (Louisville, Kentucky, mayor.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1808-06-21"  ><ab>1808-06-21</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1873-10-29"  ><ab>1873-10-29</ab></event>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, mayor. Wurttemberg, Germany native. Married to Margaret Tomppert. Father of Barbara Tomppert Doern, Philip Tomppert Junior, George, Charles, Henry, Theodore, and John Tomppert. Elected to Kentucky state legislature in 1849. Porter in Louisville, Kentucky in 1850. Insurance agent in Louisville, Kentucky in 1860. Served on Louisville City Council as representative from Second Ward from 1861 to 1864. Elected as mayor of Louisville as a Peace Democrat on April 1, 1865. Impeached on December 28, 1865 for neglect of duty. Reinstated by state Court of Appeals on February 14, 1867 and held office through 1868. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson, Louisville District 1, p. 19B.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson, Louisville Ward 2, p. 579.

&quot;Tomppert, Philip&quot; in <hi rend="italic">The Kentucky Encyclopedia</hi>, John E. Kleber, ed. (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 1992), 887.

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Philip Tomppert (1808-1873),&quot; Memorial #21462355, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/21462355 (accessed May 20, 2019).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
