<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002617">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Thompson Scott</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002617">
                    <persName>
                      William Thompson Scott
                        (Lexington, Kentucky, and Frankfort, Kentucky, soldier and inventor)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1833-06-28"  ><ab>1833-06-28</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1875-01-02"  ><ab>1875-01-02</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Lexington, Kentucky, and Frankfort, Kentucky, trader, soldier, and inventor. Lexington native. Trader in Lexington in 1860. Served in the 3rd Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment as lieutenant colonel from October 1861 to July 1862. Served in the 3rd Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment as colonel from July 1862 to December 1862. Resigned on December 7, 1862. Paymaster general of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1863 to 1865. Invented the Triplett &amp; Scott repeating rifle with Lewis Triplett, patented in December 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, Lexington, Ward No. 2, p. 426. 

<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0176. 

Roger D. Hunt, <hi rend="italic">Colonels in Blue: Indiana, Kentucky and Tennessee: A Civil War Biographical Dictionary</hi> (Jefferson, N.C.: McFarland, 2014), 183-184.

KYR-0002-222-0125.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
