<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018188">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Lafayette Wells</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Ian Iverson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018188">
                    <persName>
                      Lafayette Wells
                        (Henry and Shelby County, Kentucky, machinist, depot keeper, and soldier.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1834"  ><ab>1834</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1893"  ><ab>1893</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Henry County, Kentucky, machinist, farmer, and soldier. Montgomery County, Kentucky, native. Married to Sallie M. Lyle Wells in Shelby County, Kentucky, on November 14, 1858. Father of Mary Lucinda Wells, Joshua Wells, and John Wells. Machinist in Henry County in 1860. Served in the Eighth Kentucky Regiment Cavalry (C.S.A.) as a sergeant from September 10, 1862, to March 14, 1863. Taken prisoner at Mount Sterling, Kentucky, on February 26, 1863. Signed a loyalty oath to the U.S. government on March 14, 1863. Farmer in Henry County in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henry County, Subdivision 1, p. 378.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Shelby County, Christiansburg Precinct, p. 458A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Confederate Soldiers who Served in Organizations from the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M319, Roll 0047.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Henry County, KY, August 1863, p. 545.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994054, Shelby County Marriages.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, File 7547.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Unfiled Papers and Slips Belonging in Confederate Compiled Records</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M347, Roll 0415.<lb/>
&quot;Lafayette Wells (1834-1893),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 36071801, Accessed July 15, 2022, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/36071801/lafayette-wells.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
