<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000775">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">George Twyman Wood</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name></name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000775">
                    <persName>
                      George Twyman Wood
                        (Hart County, Kentucky, court clerk and politician.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1796-09-17"  ><ab>1796-09-17</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1876-02-24"  ><ab>1876-02-24</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Hart County, Kentucky, court clerk and politician. Virginia native. Son of W. J. Wood and Elizabeth Wood. Married to Elizabeth Helm Wood in Barren County, Kentucky, on February 7, 1821. Father of Henry C. Wood and Thomas John Wood. Father of William C. Wood, George T. Wood, Jr., Mary B. Wood, Henrietta Wood, and Amelia M. Wood. Clerk of the Hart County Court and Hart Circuit Court in 1850. Owned two enslaved persons in Hart County in 1850. Clerk of the Hart Circuit Court in 1860. Owned twelve enslaved persons in Hart County in 1860. Member of the Military Board of Kentucky from May 24,1861, to August 1862. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Hart County from 1863 to 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, p. 269A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, Munfordville, p. 955.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, District 2, p. 138B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, Munfordville, p. 346A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky, County Marriages, 1797-1954</hi>, Genealogical Society of Salt Lake City, Salt Lake City, UT, Barren County Marriages, Film 000209767.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky, Wills and Probate Records, 1774-1989</hi>, Kentucky County, District, and Probate Courts, Barren County Wills, vol. 4, May 1856 to September 8, 1884, p. 7.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1 (Frankfort: John H. Harney, Public Printer, 1866), vii. <lb/>
&quot;Death of Hon. George T. Wood,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY), February 26, 1876, p. 4.<lb/>
Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. II (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co., 1874), 322.<lb/>
Dan Lee, <hi rend="italic">Thomas J. Wood: A Biography of the Union General in the Civil War</hi> (Jefferson, NC: McFarland &amp; Company, 2012).<lb/>
&quot;George Twyman Wood (1796-1876),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 114277492, accessed August 30, 2023, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/114277492.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
