<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008241">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Alexander Keene Richards</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008241">
                    <persName>
                      Alexander Keene Richards
                        (Scott County, Kentucky, and Carroll Parish, Louisiana, planter, thoroughbred horse breeder, and livestock breeder)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1827-10-14"  ><ab>1827-10-14</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1881"  ><ab>1881</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Scott County, Kentucky, and Carroll Parish, Louisiana, planter, thoroughbred horse breeder, and livestock breeder. Georgetown, Kentucky, native. Graduated from Transylvania College in Lexington, Kentucky. Resident of Scott County in 1850. Planter in Scott County in 1860. Thoroughbred horse and livestock breeder at Blue Grass Park in Scott County. Owned twenty-nine enslaved persons in Scott County in 1860. Planter in Carroll Parish in 1860. Inherited the Transylvania plantation, a cotton plantation, in Carroll Parish, from his grandfather William B. Keene. Owned 104 enslaved persons in Carroll Parish in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Scott County, District No. 2, p. 447B. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Scott County, Georgetown, District No. 2, p. 13. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Scott County, District No. 1, p. 40. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Scott County, District No. 2, p. 6. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Louisiana, Carroll Parish, District No. 2, p. 84-85. <hi rend="italic">Passport Applications, 1795-1905</hi>; Roll #: 81; Volume #: Roll 081 - 27 Jun 1859-04 Aug 1859. &quot;A. Keene Richards: Some of the Incidents in teh Career of One of the Greatest Patrons of the American Turf,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal (Louisville, Ky.), March 24, 1881, p. 3. Ramage, James A. and Andrea S. Watkins, <hi rend="italic">Kentucky Rising: Democracy, Slavery, and Culture from the Early Republic to the Civil War</hi> (Lexington: The University Press of Kentucky, 2011), 69-70. _Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Alexander Keene Richards (1827-1881),&quot; Memorial #24843093, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/24843093/alexander-keene-richards (accessed January 23, 2018).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
