<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004989">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Joseph Rogers Underwood</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004989">
                    <persName>
                      Joseph Rogers Underwood
                        (Warren County, KY, attorney and State Representative and Senator)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1791-10-24"  ><ab>1791-10-24</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1876-08-23"  ><ab>1876-08-23</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Warren County, Kentucky, attorney and politician. Goochland County, Virginia, native. Son John Underwood and Frances Rogers Underwood. Married to Eliza M. Trotter Underwood. Father of Eliza Underwood and Jane Underwood. Married to Elizabeth Cox Underwood. Father of John Underwood, Robert Underwood, Thomas Underwood, Edith Underwood, Elizabeth Underwood, and Josephine Underwood. Graduated from Transylvania College in Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky, in 1811. Served in the 13th Kentucky Infantry Regiment as a lieutenant during the War of 1812. Admitted to the bar in 1813. Practiced law in Glasgow, Barren County, Kentucky. Glasgow town trustee and county auditor until 1823. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1816 to 1819. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1825 to 1826. Unsuccessful candidate for lieutenant governor of Kentucky in 1828. Judge of the Kentucky Court of Appeals from 1828 to 1835. Whig member of the House of Representatives of the United States from March 4, 1835, to March 3, 1843. Whig presidential elector in 1844. Speaker of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky in 1846. Whig member of the Senate of the United States from March 4, 1847, to March 3, 1853. Attorney and farmer in Warren County, Kentucky, in 1850. Owned five enslaved persons in Warren County in 1850. Attorney in Warren County in 1860. Owned seven enslaved persons in Warren County in 1860. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1861 to 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, District 1, p. 63A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, District 1.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, District 2, p. 639.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, District 2, p. 452B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Biographical Dictionary of the United States Congress, 1774-Present</hi>, UNDERWOOD, Joseph Rogers (1791-1876),“ http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=U000011 (accessed May 4, 2017).<lb/>
Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky: A History of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2, (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co., 1878), pp. 739-741.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
