<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002299">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Lovell Harrison Rousseau</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002299">
                    <persName>
                      Lovell Harrison Rousseau
                        (Louisville, KY, attorney, Col. 5th KY, General Army of Ohio (USA))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1818-08-04"  ><ab>1818-08-04</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1869-01-07"  ><ab>1869-01-07</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, attorney, soldier, and politician. Stanford, Kentucky, native. Married to Maria Antoinett Rousseau. Admitted to the bar in 1841. Member of the House of Representatives of the State of Indiana from 1844 to 1845. Served in the U.S.-Mexican War as a captain. Member of the the Senate of the State of Indiana from 1847 to 1849. Practiced law in Louisville after 1849. Attorney in Louisville in 1860. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1860 to 1861. Confirmed as a notary public for Jefferson County, Kentucky, on February 5, 1861. Resigned his position in the Kentucky Legislature to raise troops for the Union. Served in the 5th Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.) as colonel from September 9, 1861, until promoted to brigadier general on October 5, 1861. Promoted to major general on October 22, 1862. Commanded a division in the Army of the Ohio and in the Army of the Cumberland until November 17, 1865. Elected as an unconditional Unionist to the 39th United States Congress and served from March 4, 1865, to July 21, 1866.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 6, p. 316.<lb/>
Ezra J. Warner, <hi rend="italic">Generals in Blue: Lives of the Union Commanders</hi> (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1964), 412-13. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Maria Antoinette Dozier Rousseau (1826-1898),&quot; Memorial #49305630, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/49305630 (accessed June 28, 2021).<lb/>
Jack DeBerry, &quot;Lovell Harrison Rousseau&quot; in <hi rend="italic">The Kentucky Encyclopedia</hi>, ed. John E. Kleber, (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 1992), 783.<lb/>
Joseph G. Dawson, <hi rend="italic">General Lovell H. Rousseau and Louisiana Reconstruction</hi> Louisiana History 20 (Fall 1979), 373-91.<lb/>
KYR-0001-017-0062.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
