<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00019703">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">George H. Towery</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Jeremy Knoll</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00019703">
                    <persName>
                      George H. Towery
                        (Crittenden County, KY, farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1834"  ><ab>1834</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1913-06-08"  ><ab>1913-06-08</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Crittenden County, Kentucky, farmer. Kentucky native. Son of Mannering Towery and Rebecca Towery. Married to Jane O&#39;Neal Towery in Crittenden County, Kentucky, on November 22, 1864. Laborer in Crittenden County in 1850. Household owned two enslaved persons in Crittenden County in 1850. Farmer in Crittenden County in 1860. Household owned six enslaved persons in Crittenden County in 1860. Farmer in Crittenden County in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Crittenden County, District 2, p. 271B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Crittenden County, District 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Crittenden County, District 1, p. 459. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Crittenden County, District 1, p. 355B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Crittenden County, Precinct 7, p. 451B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Crittenden County, KY, July 1863, p. 34.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Crittenden County Marriages, Film 000558428.<lb/>
&quot;George H. Towery Passes Away at Dixon,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Hustler</hi> (Madisonville, KY), June 13, 1913, p. 2.<lb/>
&quot;G. H. Towery (1834-1913),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 41905295, accessed April 6, 2023, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/41905295.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
