<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018802">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Worthington Frothingham</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Matthew Roberts</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Matthew Roberts</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018802">
                    <persName>
                      Worthington Frothingham
                        (Albany, New York, attorney and commissioner of internal revenue)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1832"  ><ab>1832</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1911"  ><ab>1911</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Albany, Albany County, New York, attorney and commissioner of internal revenue. New York native. Married to Harriet A. Shepard Frothingham. Father of Walter D. Frothingham and Isadore S. Frothingham. Graduated from the University of Albany in Albany, Albany County, New York, in 1854. Attorney in Albany, New York, in 1850. Attorney in Albany, New York, in 1860. Commissioner of Internal Revenue in Albany County, New York, in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, New York, Albany County, Albany Ward 2, p. 73B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, New York, Albany County, Albany Ward 10, p. 521.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, New York, Albany County, Albany Ward 10, p. 26A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Albany County, NY, June 1863, p. 210.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Catalog and Circular of the Law School of the University of Albany for the Year 1854</hi>, (Albany, NY: Joel Munsell, 58 State Street., 1854).<lb/>
&quot;Worthington Frothingham (1832-1911),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 141818724, accessed October 20, 2022, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/141818724.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
