<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00009751">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Joshua Fry Speed</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>        
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00009751">
                    <persName>
                      Joshua Fry Speed
                        (Louisville real estate broker)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1814-11-14"  ><ab>1814-11-14</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1882-05-29"  ><ab>1882-05-29</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, real estate broker and surveyor. Kentucky native. Son of John Speed and Lucy Fry. Attended St. Joseph’s Academy in Bardstown, Kentucky. Married to Fanny Henning on February 15, 1842. Merchant in Springfield, Illinois. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Jefferson County, Kentucky, in 1848. President of the Louisville, Cincinnati &amp; Lexington Railroad from 1853 to 1855. Partner in the real estate firm Henning &amp; Speed in Louisville. Surveyor in Louisville in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 4, p. 57.

<hi rend="italic">The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 174.

“Joshua Fry Speed” in ¬<hi rend="italic">The Encyclopedia of Louisville</hi>, John E. Kleber, ed. (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 2001), 844. 

Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2 (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co., 1874), 357.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky, Death Records, 1852-1965</hi>, Film # 7007127, Louisville, May 29, 1882, p. 230 (accessed via ancestry.com).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
