<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003714">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William R. Hydes</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003714">
                    <persName>
                      William R. Hydes
                        (Louisville, Kentucky, plasterer, deputy sheriff and city marshal)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1822"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1822</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1895-04-22"  ><ab>1895-04-22</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky, plasterer and city marshal. Indiana native. Married to Amanda C. Hydes in 1851. Father of William H. Hydes and Calvert Hydes. Elected M. W. Grand Patriarch of The Grand Encampment Oddfellows Lodge in Louisville on July 16, 1856. Plasterer in Jefferson County in 1860. City marshal in Louisville in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865 (Civil War Union Draft Records), Jefferson County, KY, June 1863, p. 153, (Accessed via ancestry.com).

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Ward 6, p. 360

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson, Louisville, Ward 5, p. 550B.

Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1 (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co., 1874), 535.

&quot;Born in a Log Cabin. Funeral of William R. Hydes Yesterday Afternoon. A Louisvillian For Seventy-Six Years. A Local Landmark,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, Ky.), April 24, 1895, p. 6.

<hi rend="italic">Birth and Death Records: Covington, Lexington, Louisville, and Newport – Microfilm (before 1911)</hi>, KDLA, Roll Film 7007129: Jefferson County, Books 9-11, p. 42 of microfilm.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
