<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00009855">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William C. Grier</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00009855">
                    <persName>
                      William C. Grier
                        (Carter County, Kentucky, farmer and provost marshal)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1819-07-10"  ><ab>1819-07-10</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1881-01-08"  ><ab>1881-01-08</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Carter County, Kentucky, farmer, politician, and provost marshal. Portage County, Ohio, native. Married to Clarinda Grier. Father of Jennie Grier. Married to Amanda N. Estill Grier in Lewis County, Kentucky, in February 1854. Father of Harriet A. Grier, Ida Grier, Louwilla Grier, Sophia Grier, and Ella Grier. Farmer in Greenup County, Kentucky, in 1850. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Greenup County from 1851 to 1853. Farmer in Carter County, Kentucky, in 1860. Member of the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Carter County from 1861 to 1865. Served as the provost marshal for the 9th Military District of Kentucky from May 8, 1863, to May 29, 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Greenup County, District 1, p. 259A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Carter County, pp. 178-9.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Missouri, Barton County, Lamar Township, p. 831B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Lewis County Marriages, Film 000344052.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Reports of Bvt. Brig. Gen. D. C. McCallum, Director and General Manager of the Military Railroads of the United States, and the Provost Marshal</hi>, Part II (Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, 1866), 151.<lb/>
&quot;Jenkin&#39;s guerillas,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Louisville Daily Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY), October 13, 1862, p. 4.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The Louisville Daily Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY), October 20, 1862, p. 1.<lb/>
&quot;Reminisces in the Life of Mrs. Jennie Grier Cartmel: Installment III,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Liberal News</hi> (Liberal, MO), April 25, 1919, p. 8.<lb/>
&quot;Reminisces in the Life of Mrs. Jennie Grier Cartmel: Installment IV,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Liberal News</hi> (Liberal, MO), May 2, 1919, p. 8.<lb/>
&quot;Reminisces in the Life of Mrs. Jennie Grier Cartmel: Installment V,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Liberal News</hi> (Liberal, MO), May 9, 1919, p. 8.<lb/>
&quot;Reminisces in the Life of Mrs. Jennie Grier Cartmel: Installment VII,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Liberal News</hi> (Liberal, MO), May 23, 1919, p. 8.<lb/>
&quot;Reminisces in the Life of Mrs. Jennie Grier Cartmel: Installment XVIII,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Liberal News</hi> (Liberal, MO), August 15, 1919, p. 5.<lb/>
&quot;Reminisces in the Life of Mrs. Jennie Grier Cartmel: Installment XXIV,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Liberal News</hi> (Liberal, MO), September 26, 1919, p. 8.<lb/>
Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. II (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co., 1878), 122, 300.<lb/>
&quot;William C. Grier (1819-1881),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 80461743, accessed November 20, 2023, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/80461743.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
