<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011403">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Henry Lyter Giltner</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011403">
                    <persName>
                      Henry Lyter Giltner
                        (Carroll County, KY, carpenter, sheriff, and  prov govt conv rep)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1829-06-05"  ><ab>1829-06-05</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1892-08-19"  ><ab>1892-08-19</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Carroll County, Kentucky, carpenter and sheriff. Kentucky native. Son of Michael Giltner and Mary Giltner. Married to Martha G. Young Giltner in Carroll County on December 3, 1856. Father of Lela B. Giltner, William Henry Giltner, and Gideon Giltner. Carpenter in Carroll County in 1850. Sheriff in Carroll County in 1860. Member of the convention of the provisional government held at Russellville in November 1861. Served in the Fourth Regiment Cavalry Kentucky Volunteers (C.S.A.) as captain and colonel from September 10, 1862 to May 1, 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Carroll County, District 1, p. 160B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Carroll County, Carrollton, p. 24.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Trimble County, Milton, p. 232A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Col Henry Lyter Giltner (1829-1892),&quot; Memorial 18948243, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/18948243  (accessed November 14, 2019).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Carroll County Marriages, 1837-1891, Film #000414689, p. 592<lb/>
KYR-0004-033-0001.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
