<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00009175">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Elias Hubbard Smith</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00009175">
                    <persName>
                      Elias Hubbard Smith
                        (Grant County, Kentucky, clerk, attorney, and politician.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1872-12-01"  ><ab>1872-12-01</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Grant County, Kentucky, clerk, attorney, and politician. Barren County, Kentucky, native. Son of Elias Smith and Elizabeth Milzener Smith. Married to Sallie C. O’Hara Smith in Grant County, Kentucky, on July 11, 1850. Father of Helen M. Smith, Lucy R. Smith, Kate Smith, and James W. Smith. Clerk in Grant County in 1850. Household owned two enslaved persons in Grant County in 1850. Clerk in the office of the Grant County Court and Grant Circuit Court from 1847 to 1852. Household owned two enslaved persons in Grant County in 1850. Deputy clerk of the Kenton Circuit Court from 1852 to 1853. Attorney in Grant County in 1860. Owned one enslaved person in Grant County in 1860. Member of the House of Representatives for the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Grant County from 1863 to 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Grant County, Williamstown, p. 360B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Grant County, Williamstown, p. 114.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Grant County, Williamstown, p. 990.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Grant County, Williamstown, p. 41A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Grant County, Williamstown, p. 601A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Grant County Marriages, Film 001490815.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Grant County, KY, June and July 1863, p. 229.<lb/>
Robert H. Elliston, <hi rend="italic">The History of Grant County, State of Kentucky: As Compiled by Robert H. Elliston and Read by Him on the Fourth Day of July, 1876</hi> (Williamstown, KY: Sentinel Office, 1876), 21.<lb/>
W.H. Perrin, J.H. Battle, and G.C. Kniffin, <hi rend="italic">Kentucky: A History of the State</hi>, vol. 7 (Louisville, KY: F.A. Battey and Company, 1887), 886-7.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
