<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008487">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert Augustus Toombs</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008487">
                    <persName>
                      Robert Augustus Toombs
                        (Confederate Secretary of State)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1810-07-02"  ><ab>1810-07-02</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1885-12-15"  ><ab>1885-12-15</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Wilkes County, Georgia, native. Son of Robert Toombs and Catherine Huling Toombs. Married to Julia A. Dubose Toombs. Attended the University of Georgia. Graduated from Union College in Schenectady, New York. Graduated from the Law Department at the University of Virginia in Charlottesville, Virginia. Admitted to the Georgia bar. Member of the Georgia General Assembly from 1837 to 1843, with a one year interruption. Member of the House of Representatives of the United States from Georgia from 1844 to 1853. Member of the Senate of the United States from 1853 to 1861. Resigned on February 4, 1861. Secretary of State for the government of the Confederate State of America from February 1861 to July 1861. Brigadier general in the Army of the Potomac (Confederate) and the Army of Northern Virginia (Confederate) from July 1861 to March 1863. Colonel of the 3rd Cavalary of Georgia Militia in March 1863. Resigned and returned to Washington, Georgia. Self-imposed exile to Cuba and Paris, Francis, from 1865 to 1867.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl>William C. Davis, <hi rend="italic">The Union that Shaped the Confederacy: Robert Toombs &amp; Alexander H. Stephens</hi> (Lawrence, KS: University Press of Kansas, 2001).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
