<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00020587">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Henry Clay Bowman</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00020587">
                    <persName>
                      Henry Clay Bowman
                        (Breathitt County, Kentucky, farmer.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1827"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1827</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1865-04-03"  ><ab>1865-04-03</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Breathitt County, Kentucky, farmer. Kentucky native. Married to Mary &quot;Polly&quot; Lawson Bowman in Morgan County, Kentucky, on December 21, 1852. Father of Woodson Bowman, Zerilda Bowman, Nicholas Bowman, and Caroline Bowman. Farmer in Breathitt County, Kentucky, in 1850. Farmer in Owsley County, Kentucky, in 1860. Farmer in Breathitt County in 1863. Enrolled in the Three Forks Battalion (U.S.A.) as a private on December 3, 1864. Killed by Cas Ledford and John Jones in Breathitt County on April 3, 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Breathitt County, District 1, p. 20B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Owsley County, p. 426.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Breathitt County, KY, July and December 1863, p. 12.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994029, Breathitt County Births.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Morgan County Marriages, Film 000839918.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), p. 781.<lb/>
Miles Nicholas Crawford, <hi rend="italic">Early Pioneers on the Three Forks of the Kentucky River</hi> (Cullman, AL: The Gregath Company, 1984), 98-9.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
