<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018654">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Bigger Bibb</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018654">
                    <persName>
                      John Bigger Bibb
                        (Franklin County, Kentucky, politician and attorney)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1789-10-27"  ><ab>1789-10-27</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1884-04-13"  ><ab>1884-04-13</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Franklin County, Kentucky, politician and attorney. Prince Edward County, Virginia, native. Son of Richard Bibb and Lucy Booker Bibb. Married to Sarah P. Horsley Bibb in Henderson County, Kentucky, on August 24, 1831. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Logan County in 1827. Member of the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Logan County from 1831 to 1834. Resident of Logan County, Kentucky, in 1850. Owned six enslaved persons in Logan County in 1850. Attorney in Franklin County in 1860. Owned forty-eight enslaved persons, including Betsy, Robertson, Peyton, Henry, Franklin, Polk, Marion, Charlotte, Sarah, Sylvia, Venus, Phil, Cornelia, Louisa, Martha, Wesley and Washington Wallace, in Franklin County in 1860. Owned one enslaved person in Logan County in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Logan County, Russellville, District 2, p. 134A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Logan County, Russellville, District 2, p. 438.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Logan County, District 2, p. 388.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, District 1, p. 239.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, District 1, p. 488B-489A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Logan County, District 2, p. 23.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, p. 110A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Henderson County Marriages, Film 000576460, p. 47.<lb/>
Frazer, T.A. Letter to John B. Bibb, January 12, 1864. <hi rend="italic">Bibb Family Papers, 1760-1887.</hi> From Filson Historical Society, Louisville, Kentucky. <lb/>
Frazer, T.A. Letter to John B. Bibb, February 4, 1864. <hi rend="italic">Bibb Family Papers, 1760-1887.</hi> From Filson Historical Society, Louisville, Kentucky. <lb/>
Frazer, T.A. Letter to John B. Bibb, February 5, 1864. <hi rend="italic">Bibb Family Papers, 1760-1887.</hi> From Filson Historical Society, Louisville, Kentucky. <lb/>
Frazer, T.A. Letter to John B. Bibb, January 12, 1865. <hi rend="italic">Bibb Family Papers, 1760-1887.</hi> From Filson Historical Society, Louisville, Kentucky. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">United States Freedmen&#39;s Bureau Claim Records 1865-1872</hi>, NARA RG 105, Microfilm Series M2029, Roll 12, Certificate 615663.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 264.<lb/>
&quot;John B. Bibb (1789-1884),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 59762923, accessed September 26, 2022, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/59762923.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
