<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000827">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Samuel McKee</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000827">
                    <persName>
                      Samuel McKee
                        (Kentucky attorney, soldier, and politician)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1833-11-05"  ><ab>1833-11-05</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1898-12-11"  ><ab>1898-12-11</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Kentucky attorney, soldier, and politician. Mount Sterling, Kentucky, native. Married to Sophia Brainerd McKee. Father of Frank McKee, Samuel McKee, Eugenia McKee Nettelroth, and Brainerd McKee. Graduate of Miami University in Oxford, Ohio in 1857. Graduate of the Cincinnati Law School in 1858. Attorney in Mount Sterling, Kentucky. Captain in the 14th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry (U.S.A.) from 1862 to 1864. Prisoner of war for 13 months at Libby Prison. Member of the United States House of Representatives from the Ninth Congressional District of Kentucky as an Unconditional Unionist from 1865 to 1867.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</hi>, s.v. “McKee, Samuel,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=M000497) (accessed January 5, 2017). Charles Lanman, <hi rend="italic">Biographical Annals of the Civil Government of the United States</hi> (Washington: J. M. Morrison, 1887), 334. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Montgomery County, Mount Sterling, p. 119. <hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, 7 Ward City Louisville, p. 125-126. <hi rend="italic">Find a Grave</hi>, “Samuel McKee (November 5, 1833-December 11, 1898),” Memorial #7095889, http://findagrave.com/memorial/7095889 (accessed January 5, 2017).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
