<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018710">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Alexander B. Semple</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018710">
                    <persName>
                      Alexander B. Semple
                        (Jefferson County, Kentucky, merchant and hardware store owner)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1807"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1807</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1873"  ><ab>1873</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Jefferson County, Kentucky, merchant and hardware store owner. Pennsylvania native. Married to Eliza McComb Semple. Father of William Semple, Ann S. Semple, Alexander Semple, John Semple, Edward H. Semple, Elizabeth Semple, Charles Semple, and Henry M. Semple. Married to Emeline H. Price Semple in Jefferson County, Kentucky, on April 30, 1851. Father of Patty B. Semple, Emire P. Semple, Andrew Bonner Semple, Frank Semple, and Nellie Semple.  Iron merchant in Jefferson County, Kentucky, in 1850. Hardware store owner in Jefferson County in 1860. Enslaved two people in Jefferson County in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville District 2, p. 161B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 4, p. 94-95.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 4, p. 270A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 6, p. 599A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Vermont Vital Records 1871-1908.</hi> Windsor County Marriages, New England Historic Genealogical Society, Boston, Massachusetts. Reel 777, p. 1677. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film 000819593.<lb/>
&quot;William Semple Passes Away After an Illness of a Few Days,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal,</hi> (Louisville, KY) July 2, 1894. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
