<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00014438">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Baylus L. D. Guffy </title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00014438">
                    <persName>
                      Baylus L. D. Guffy 
                        (Butler County, Kentucky, judge)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1832-12-24"  ><ab>1832-12-24</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1910-02-27"  ><ab>1910-02-27</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Butler County, Kentucky, judge. Kentucky native. Son of James Guffy and Malinda Guffy. Married to Mahalie A. Monroe Guffy in Ohio County, Kentucky, on May 25, 1854. Father of Luella F. Guffy, Estill Guffy, and Olive Guffy. Resident in Logan County in 1850. Attorney in Butler County from 1860 to 1910. Assistant marshal in Butler County in 1860. Owned one enslaved person in Butler County in 1860. County Judge in Butler County in 1862. Alternate delegate to the Union Democratic National Convention from Butler County in 1864. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Logan County, District 1, p. 45B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Butler County, Morgantown, p. 1007.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Butler County, Woodbury, p. 1 of 1 of microfilm (accessed via ancestry.com, May 12, 2021).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Butler County, Morgantown, p. 345A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Ohio County Marriages, Film #000494956, p. 173.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865 (Civil War Union Draft Records), Butler County, KY, July and August 1863, p. 529 (accessed via Ancestry.com).<lb/>
&quot;Louisville Daily Journal 1864-05-26,&quot; Newspapers.com, https://www.newspapers.com/image/592167418 (accessed May 12, 2021).<lb/>
&quot;Owensboro Messenger 1910-03-01,&quot; Newspapers.com, https://www.newspapers.com/image/376052415 (accessed May 12, 2021).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
