<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010355">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Francis &quot;Frank&quot; Queen, Sr.</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010355">
                    <persName>
                      John Francis &quot;Frank&quot; Queen, Sr.
                        (Nelson County; multiple candidates)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1807-11-07"  ><ab>1807-11-07</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1898-09-04"  ><ab>1898-09-04</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Nelson County, Kentucky, merchant. Kentucky native. Son of James Queen and Elizabeth Boone Queen. Married to Mary Malvina Price Queen in Nelson County on July 19, 1841. Father of Mary E. “Lizzie” Queen, John Queen, Julia Queen, Joseph Earnest Queen, William J. Queen, Louisa Queen, and Alice Queen. Married to Sarah Queen. Resident of Nelson County in 1840. Merchant in Nelson County in 1850. Owned six enslaved persons in Nelson County in 1850.  Merchant in Nelson County in 1860. Employed S. Mullican as a salesman in Nelson County in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Sixth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1840), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, North East Division, p. 31.

<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 1, pp. 274B-275A.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 1, p. 179.

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, Bardstown, p. 70A.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Nelson County Marriages, 1783-1954, Film #000481488, p. 103.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;John Francis Queen (1807-1898),&quot; Memorial 72225308, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/72225308/john-francis-queen  (accessed April 13, 2020).<lb/>
Mackenzie, George Norbury, and Nelson Osgood Rhoades, editors. <hi rend="italic">Colonial Families of the United States of America: in Which is Given the History, Genealogy and Armorial Bearings of Colonial Families Who Settled in the American Colonies From the Time of the Settlement of Jamestown, 13th May, 1607, to the Battle of Lexington, 19th April, 1775</hi>. 7 volumes. 1912. Reprinted, Baltimore: Genealogical Publishing Co., Inc., 1966, 1995, p.443.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
