<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000304">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Bushrod Washington Foley</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000304">
                    <persName>
                      Bushrod Washington Foley
                        (Covington, Kentucky, attorney, politician, and police guard)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1809"  ><ab>1809</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1867"  ><ab>1867</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Covington, Kentucky, attorney, politician, and police guard. Wood County, Virginia, native. Married to Elvira S. Foley. Father of James Foley and Bushrod Foley. Mayor of Covington from 1845 to 1860. Attorney in Covington in 1860. Employed Lizzie Smith, Ellen Dugan, and Julia Lalley as servants in 1860. Police guard of the Kentucky Central Railroad from September 17, 1861, to December 10, 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, Covington, Ward 2, p. 30. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, Covington, Ward 4, p. 152.<lb/>
“Covington Mayors.” December 30, 2013. http://www.kentonlibrary.org/genealogy/regional-history/covington/downtown/covington-mayors. <lb/>
A. G. Hodges, <hi rend="italic">Reports Communicated to Both Branches of the Legislature of Kentucky at the December Session, 1845</hi> (Frankfort, Kentucky: A.G. Hodges State Printer, 1845). Roger D. Hunt, <hi rend="italic">Colonels in Blue: Indiana, Kentucky, and Tennessee: A Civil War Biographical Dictionary</hi> (New York, NY, United States: McFarland &amp; Company, Inc., Publishers, 2013.)<lb/>
Theodore H. H. Harris, &quot;Underground Railroad, Campbell and Kenton Counties,&quot; in <hi rend="italic">The Encyclopedia of Northern Kentucky</hi> Paul A. Tenkotte and James C. Claypool, eds. (Lexington: The University Press of Kentucky, 2009), 903. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Bushrod Washington Foley ( 1809 - March 16, 1867),&quot; Memorial #94192591, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/94192591 (accessed June 26, 2017).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
