<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011626">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">George Woolfolk Givens</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>        
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011626">
                    <persName>
                      George Woolfolk Givens
                        (Lincoln County, KY, farmer, physician, and university curator.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1818"  ><ab>1818</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1881"  ><ab>1881</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Lincoln County, Kentucky, farmer, physician, and university curator. Kentucky native. Son of Patsy Givens. Married to Mary M. Finley Givens in Shelby County on October 18, 1853. Father of Alice Givens. Farmer in Lincoln County in 1850. Owned twenty enslaved persons in Lincoln County in 1850. Physician in Lincoln County in 1860. Owned fourteen enslaved persons in Lincoln County in 1860. Household members owned an additional fourteen enslaved persons in Lincoln County in 1860. Member of the board of curators of Kentucky University in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Lincoln County, District 1, p. 276A.

<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Lincoln County, District 1, p. 229, p.19 of microfilm.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Lincoln County, p. 49.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Lincoln County, pp. 345B-346A, pp. 14-15 of microfilm.

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Lincoln County, Stanford, p. 78B.

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;George Woolfolk Givens (1818-1881),&quot; Memorial 86584135, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/86584135  (accessed December 23, 2019).

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Shelby County Marriages, Film 000259291, p. 512 of microfilm.

KYR-0001-009-0038.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
