<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008422">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Kaye</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008422">
                    <persName>
                      William Kaye
                        (Louisville, Ky, mayor (1863-65))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1813-02-13"  ><ab>1813-02-13</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1890-11-19"  ><ab>1890-11-19</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, foundry owner and mayor. Native of Yorkshire, England. Son of Joshua Kaye and Hannah Kaye. Married to Mary Patterson Kaye in 1836. Father of Mary A. Kaye, Edward H. Kaye, Emma W. Kaye, Samuel J. Kaye, and Willie Kaye. Resident in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, in 1819. Machinist in Pittsburgh in 1827. Established Patterson &amp; Kaye in partnership with [Unknown] Patterson in Louisville, Kentucky, in 1836. Established Kaye &amp; Co. Brass Founders and Machinists in Louisville in 1841. Bell foundry owner in Louisville in 1860. Employed Delia Claherty and Hannah Purcell as domestic servants in Louisville in 1860. Member of the Louisville City Council in 1862. Mayor of Louisville from April 4, 1863, to April 14, 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Shelby County, District 2, p. 207A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Ward 4, p. 90.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Ward 6, p. 603A.<lb/>
&quot;William Kaye&quot; in <hi rend="italic">The Encyclopedia of Louisville</hi>, ed. John E. Kleber (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 2001), 457.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
