<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00017902">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Hickman P. Richie</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Ian Iverson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Ian Iverson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00017902">
                    <persName>
                      Hickman P. Richie
                        (Nicholas County, Kentucky, farmer and soldier.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1821-09-11"  ><ab>1821-09-11</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1911-12-04"  ><ab>1911-12-04</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Nicholas County, Kentucky, farmer and soldier. Kentucky native. Son of Zack Richie and Betsey McDaniel Richie. Father of Mary E. Richie, John H. Richie, Margaret E. Richie, Rosette E. Richie, Fortbosia Ritchie, Zachariah B. Richie, and Isaac R. Ritchie. Married to Nancy Holmes Richie in Nichols County, Kentucky, on May 14, 1860. Father of Martha Josephine Ritchie, Levity Ritchie, and McPherson Ritchie. Farmer in Nicholas County in 1860. Enrolled in 7th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry (U.S.A.) on August 1, 1862. Reported as missing following Battle of Big Hill in Madison County, August 23, 1862 before officially mustering in to Federal service. Subsequently reported as deserted. Farmer in Nicholas County in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nicholas County, District 2, p. 70.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nicholas County, Precinct 2, p. 216. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0083.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Nicholas County, KY, July 1863, p. 12.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, File #32346.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Nicholas County Marriages, Film 000252410.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
