<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00019821">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Fleming</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Jeremy Knoll</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00019821">
                    <persName>
                      William Fleming
                        (Allen County, Indiana, sheriff and clerk of the Allen County Circuit Court.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1828-06-17"  ><ab>1828-06-17</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1890-01-13"  ><ab>1890-01-13</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Allen County, Indiana, sheriff and clerk of the Allen County Circuit Court. Native of County Wicklow, Ireland. Son of Luke Fleming and Sarah Holt Fleming. Married to Ann McLaughlin Fleming on August 18, 1854. Father of Luke M. Fleming and Mary E. Fleming. Married to Helen F. Mayer Fleming on July 7, 1859. Father of Catherine S. Fleming, Helen G. Fleming, and Georgie F. Fleming. Stonecutter in Allen County, Indiana, in 1850. Sheriff in Allen County in 1860. Clerk of the Allen County Circuit Court in 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Indiana, Allen County, Fort Wayne, p. 127B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Indiana, Allen County, Wayne, p. 984.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Indiana, Allen County, Fort Wayne Ward 5, p. 380B.<lb/>
&quot;William Fleming,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Fort Wayne Gazette</hi> (Fort Wayne, IN), January 14, 1890.<lb/>
Robert S. Robertson, <hi rend="italic">History of the Maumee River Basin: Allen County Indiana</hi> (Indianapolis, IN: Bowen &amp; Slocum, 1905), vol. 3, p. 208.<lb/>
KYR-0001-006-0013.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
