<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00009107">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John M. Burns</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Emily D. Moses</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00009107">
                    <persName>
                      John M. Burns
                        (Floyd County, Kentucky, attorney.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1827"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1827</ab></event>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Floyd County, Kentucky, attorney. Kentucky native. Son of Roland T. Burns and Elizabeth Rewland. Married to Keziah Clay. Father of Kate Burns, Roland Burns, Mary Burns, James Trimble Burns, Sophia Burns, Mittan Burns, and Leonidas Burns. Admitted to the bar in 1851. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1857 to 1859. Attorney in Floyd County in 1860. Elected to the Kentucky Senate in 1860. Owned one enslaved person in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Floyd County, p. 4.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Floyd County, District 2, p. 478A.

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Boyd County, Cattlesburg, p. 113A.

Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2 (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co., 1874), 1882.

W. H. Perrin, J. H. Battle, and G. C. Kniffin, <hi rend="italic">Kentucky: A History of the State</hi>, 8th ed. (Louisville and Chicago: F. A. Battey and Company, 1888), 758-59.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
