<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00005540">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Bayless Leander Durant Guffy</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Stephen Powell</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Stephen Powell</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00005540">
                    <persName>
                      Bayless Leander Durant Guffy
                        (lawyer and judge)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1832-12-24"  ><ab>1832-12-24</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1910-02-28"  ><ab>1910-02-28</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Morgantown, Kentucky, attorney and judge. Kentucky native. Graduate of Urana College, in Glasgow, Kentucky, in 1855. Married to Mahala A. Monroe Guffy on May 25, 1857. Admitted to the bar in 1856. Police judge of Morgantown in 1858. Attorney in Morgantown in 1860. Judge of the Butler County Court in Butler County in 1862. Delegate from the 2nd Congressional District to the Democratic convention in Chicago in 1864. Re-elected as Judge of Butler County Court in 1866. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Butler, Morgantown, p. 179. <hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865 (Civil War Union Draft Records), Butler County, KY, July/August 1863, p. 14, (Accessed via ancestry.com). James Terry White, <hi rend="italic">The National Cyclopedia of American Biography</hi> (1904), J. T. White Company, p. 454. <hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, “Bayles Leander Durant Guffy (December 24, 1832-February 28, 1910),” Memorial #21401700, https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=21401700 (accessed June 5, 2017). 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
