<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010668">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Wolcott Stewart</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
          </respStmt>        
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010668">
                    <persName>
                      John Wolcott Stewart
                        (Middlebury, Addison County, Vermont, attorney and politician)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1825-11-24"  ><ab>1825-11-24</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1915-10-29"  ><ab>1915-10-29</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Middlebury, Addison County, Vermont, attorney and politician. Vermont native. Son of Ira and Elizabeth Hubbell Stewart. Married Emma Seymour Battell Stewart in Middlebury, Vermont on November 21, 1860. Father of Emma Stewart and Phillip Stewart. Graduated from Middlebury Academy in Middlebury, Vermont in 1846. Admitted to the Vermont bar in 1850. Attorney in Middlebury, Vermont in 1850. Prosecuting attorney for Addison County, Vermont between 1852 and 1854. Member of the Vermont House of Representatives from Addison County in 1856 and from 1865 to 1867 (also 1876). Director of Middlebury Bank until 1858. Attorney in Middlebury, Vermont in 1860. Served as the Vermont Speaker of the House between 1865 and 1867 (and 1876). </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Vermont, Addison County, Middlebury, p. 256. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Vermont, Addison County, Middlebury, p. 291. <hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Vermont, Addison County, Middlebury, p. 157. “Emma Battelle” in the Vermont, Vital Records, 1720-1908,” (accessed via ancestry.com). <hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;John Wolcott Stewart (November 24, 1825-October 29, 1915),&quot; Memorial #22696, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/22696 (accessed May 15, 2019). “Stewart, John Wolcott (1825-1915),” Biographical Directory of the United States Congress (Courtesy of United States Senate Historical Office)  http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=s000917 (accessed May 15, 2019).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
