<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00012339">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Johnson</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Carl Creason</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Carl Creason</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00012339">
                    <persName>
                      James Johnson
                        (Breathitt County farmhand and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1842"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1842</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Breathitt County, Kentucky, farmhand and soldier. Knox County, Kentucky, native. Son of Elisha Johnson and Julia Johnson. Married to Mary Johnson. Father of Henry Johnson, Laurany Johnson, and Granville Johnson. Resident of Breathitt County in 1850. Farmhand in Breathitt County in 1860. Household owned one enslaved person in Breathitt County in 1860. Farmer in Breathitt County in 1863. Served in the Breathitt County Militia (Kentucky National Legion) as a lieutenant in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Breathitt County, District 1, p. 33B.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Breathitt County, District 1, p. 307.

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Breathitt County, Precinct 7, p. 442B.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Breathitt County, District 1, p. 174A.

<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865 (Civil War Union Draft Records), Breathitt County, KY, August and December 1863, p. 191 (Accessed via ancestry.com).

KYR-0001-008-0002.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
