<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008569">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Joseph Horace Lewis</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008569">
                    <persName>
                      Joseph Horace Lewis
                        (Barren County, KY, attorney and CSA general)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1824-10-29"  ><ab>1824-10-29</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1904-07-06"  ><ab>1904-07-06</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Glasgow, Barren County, Kentucky, attorney and soldier. Kentucky native. Son of John and Elizabeth Reed Lewis. Married Sarah H. Rogers Lewis on November 29, 1845. Father of John Lewis, Sarah Lewis, George R. Lewis, and Eliza Lewis. Married Cassandra Flournoy Lewis in 1860. Graduated from Centre College in Danville, Kentucky, in 1843. Admitted to the bar in 1845. Attorney in Glasgow in 1850. Owned four enslaved persons in Glasgow in 1850. Whig member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky in 1850 and 1852. Unsuccessful candidate for U.S. Congress in 1857 and 1861. Served in the 6th Kentucky Infantry (C.S.A.) as colonel from 1861 to 1863. Served in the 1st Kentucky Brigade (C.S.A.) as brevet brigadier general from September 20, 1863. Member of presidential escort during retreat of Jefferson Davis in 1865.  </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Barren County, Glasgow, p.396A.

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Barren County, Glasgow, p. 565A.

<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Barren County, Glasgow, p. 190.

&quot;Eventful Career of Gen. Joseph H Lewis Finally Closed&quot;, <hi rend="italic">Courier Journal</hi> (Louisville, Kentucky), July 7, 1904, p. 1. 

<hi rend="italic">Journal of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</hi> (Frankfort, KY: A. G. Hodges &amp; Co., State Printers, 1850), 3.

<hi rend="italic">Journal of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</hi> (Frankfort, KY: A. G. Hodges &amp; Co., 1851), 3.

<hi rend="italic">Journal of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</hi> (Frankfort, KY: A. G. Hodges, State Printer, 1853), 3.

Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, ¬<hi rend="italic">Collins’ Historical Sketches of Kentucky: History of Kentucky</hi>, rev. ed., vol. 1 (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co, 1878), 92, 363.

<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky: Confederate Kentucky Volunteers War 1861-65</hi>, vol. 1 (Frankfort: Legislature of Kentucky, 1915), 286-87. 

Bruce S. Allardice and Lawrence Lee Hewitt, <hi rend="italic">Kentuckians in Gray: Confederate Generals and Field Officers  of the Bluegrass State</hi> (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 2015), 173-79. 

Ed Porter Thompson, <hi rend="italic">History of the Orphan Brigade</hi> (Louisville, KY: Lewis N. Thompson, 1898), 387-89, 391 . 

<hi rend="italic">The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 426.

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Joseph Horace Lewis (1824-1904)”Memorial #8928, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/8928/joseph-horace-lewis (accessed April 21, 2018).

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Sarah Hensley Rogers Lewis (1828-1858),&quot; Memorial #105706931 https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/105706931/sarah-hensley-lewis (accessed April 21, 2018).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
