<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00016709">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Thompson Davidson</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00016709">
                    <persName>
                      James Thompson Davidson
                        (Fayette County, Kentucky, bank clerk)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1823-01-24"  ><ab>1823-01-24</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1878-05-06"  ><ab>1878-05-06</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Fayette County, Kentucky, bank clerk. Washington, D.C. native. Married to Catherine “Kate” M. Hull Davidson. Father of Mary Eliza Davidson, Catherine “Kate” A. Davidson, Sarah J. Davidson, Jennie Davidson, Louis Davidson, Nannie Davidson, John H. Davidson, Laura A. Davidson, and Robert B. Davidson. Clerk in Fayette County, Kentucky, in 1850. Owned two enslaved persons in Fayette County in 1850. Clerk of the Northern Bank of Kentucky in Fayette County in 1860. Clerk of the Northern Bank of Kentucky in Fayette County in 1862. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, District 2, p. 217A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, District 2, p. 609.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, Lexington, Ward 2, p. 425.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, Lexington, Ward 2, p. 203 B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, File #3029.<lb/>
&quot;James Thomson Davidson (1823-1878),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #99745168, accessed December 7, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/99745168.<lb/>
KYR-0001-031-0062.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
