<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006232">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William W. Bush</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Samuel T. Whittaker</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006232">
                    <persName>
                      William W. Bush
                        (Simpson County, KY, attorney &amp; private in TN Cav (CSA))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1836-10-09"  ><ab>1836-10-09</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1908-05-20"  ><ab>1908-05-20</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Simpson County, Kentucky, attorney and soldier. Edmonson County, Kentucky, native. Son of Isaac Bush and Matilda Parker Bush. Married to Virginia Huston Bush on January 7, 1864. Father of Mary G. Bush. Secretary of the Kentucky Third District Democratic Convention in Bowling Green in 1859. Attorney in Simpson County in 1860. Served in the 8th Tennessee Cavalry (C.S.A.) and the 4th Tennessee Cavalry (C. S. A.) as a private from September 27, 1862, to September 20, 1864. Attorney in Simpson County in 1864. Captured in Wilson County, Tennessee. Prisoner of war in Louisville, Kentucky. Signed a loyalty oath to the U. S. government on September 26, 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Barren County, Division 1, p. 315A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Simpson County, Franklin, p. 138.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedule, Kentucky, Simpson County, Franklin, p. 9A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Twelfth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1900), Population Schedules, Oklahoma, Canadian County, Valley Township,Enumeration District: 0021, p. 4.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The Louisville Daily Courier</hi>, &quot;Third Congressional District-Nomination of W. W. Sale for Congress,&quot; May 25, 1859, page 1.<lb/>
W. H. Perrin, J. H. Battle, and G. C. Kniffin, <hi rend="italic">Kentucky: A History of the State</hi>, 8th ed. (Louisville and Chicago: F. A. Battey and Company, 1888), 645-46.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Confederate Soldiers who Served in Organizations from the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M319, Roll 0066.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Kentucky, 4th Congressional District, Jefferson County, Vol. 1 of 3, February 1864, p. 29 of 204 of microfilm), (Accessed via ancestry.com on July 20,  2020).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, “William Walter Bush (1808-1883),&quot; Memorial 14991095, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/14991095 (accessed July 20, 2020).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
