<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011960">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Martin Breen</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011960">
                    <persName>
                      Martin Breen
                        (Jefferson County, KY, flour dealer &amp; grocer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1819"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1819</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Jefferson County, Kentucky, grocer and flour dealer. Native of Ireland. Married to Mary Catharine Griffin Breen in Jefferson County on February 1, 1845. Father of Benjamin P. Breen, Mary F. Breen, M. Breen, Martin C. Breen, John H. Breen, and Francis “Frank” Breen. Grocer in Louisville in 1860. Employed M. Fix and M. Doyle as clerks in 1860. Signed a petition in May 1861 to appoint W. G. Timberlake as flour inspector.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 6, p. 322.

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 8, p. 84B.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film #000817889, p. 50 of microfilm.

<hi rend="italic">Birth and Death Records: Covington, Lexington, Louisville, and Newport – Microfilm (before 1911)</hi>, KDLA, Roll #7007128, Louisville Deaths, Books 7-8, 1887-1894, p. 146 of microfilm.

KYR-0001-017-0163.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
