<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018379">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Orlando Bolivar Willcox</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Ian Iverson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Ian Iverson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018379">
                    <persName>
                      Orlando Bolivar Willcox
                        (Detroit, Wayne County, Michigan, attorney and soldier.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1823-04-26"  ><ab>1823-04-26</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1907-05-10"  ><ab>1907-05-10</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Detroit, Wayne County, Michigan, attorney and soldier. Detroit, Wayne County, Michigan, native. Son of Charles Willcox and Almira Rood Willcox. Married to Marie L. Farnsworth Willcox. Father of Mary L. Willcox, Elon F. Willcox, Grace N. Willcox, and Elmira Willcox. Graduated from the United States Mililitary Academy at West Point, Orange County, New York in 1847. Served in the 4th United States Artillery Regiment as a second lieutenant and first lieutenant from July 1, 1847 to September 10, 1857. Served in the Mexican-American and Third Seminole Wars. Attorney in Detroit, Wayne County, Michigan, in 1860. Employed Margarett McDonald and Elisabeth Thompson as domestic servants in Detroit, Wayne County, in 1860. Served in the 1st Michigan Volunteer Infantry Regiment as the colonel from May 1, 1861-July 21, 1861. Wounded at the Battle of First Bull Run, Virginia, on July 21, 1861. Captured at Battle of First Bull Run, Virginia, on July 21, 1861. Prisoner of war at Charleston and Columbia, South Carolina from July 21, 1861 to August 17, 1862. Exchanged on August 17, 1862. Promoted to Brigadier General of Volunteers to date from July 21, 1861. Commanded a Division in the Union Army&#39;s IX Corps from September 1862 to April 1865. Promoted Brevet Major General of Volunteers to date from August 1, 1864. Commanded the District of Washington, North Carolina from April 1865 to July 1865. Commanded the District of Michigan from August1865 through December 31, 1865.  </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Michigan, Wayne County, Detroit Ward 7, p. 556.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, California, Marin County, Sansalito, p. 72A. <lb/>
&quot;Orlando Bolivar Willcox,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Appleton&#39;s Cyclopædia of American Biography</hi>, vol. VI, eds. John Fiske and James Grant Wilson (New York: Appleton, 1889), 516-517.<lb/>
George W. Cullum, <hi rend="italic">Biographical Register of the Officers and Graduates of the U. S. Military Academy</hi>, Third Edition, Vol. II (Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin and Company, 1891), 310-311.<lb/><lb/>
Francis B Heitman, <hi rend="italic">Historical Register and Dictionary of the United States Army, from its Organization, September 29, 1789, to March 2, 1903</hi> vol. I, pt. 2 (Washington, DC: Government Printing Office, 1903), 1038.<lb/>
&quot;Orlando Bolivar Willcox (1823-1907),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #5885540, accessed August 5, 2022, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/5885540.<lb/>
&quot;Marie Farnsworth Willcox (1831-1873),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #59768672, accessed August 5, 2022, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/59768672.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
