<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00012288">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Benoni Mills</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00012288">
                    <persName>
                      Benoni Mills
                        (Wayne County, KY, farmer and sheriff)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1805"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1805</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Wayne County, Kentucky, farmer and sheriff. Kentucky native. Married to Mary (Polly) Jones Mills in Wayne County on February 18, 1833. Father of John F. Mills, Frances Mills, Sarah L. Mills, Eliza Mills, Milton Mills, Jesse Mills, William K. Mills, and Harriet A. Mills. Owned one enslaved person in Wayne County in 1840. Farmer in Wayne County in 1850. Owned two enslaved persons in Wayne County in 1850. Employed Eli Carrell as a day laborer in 1860. Farmer in Wayne County in 1860. Sheriff of Wayne County in 1865.   </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Sixth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1840), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Wayne County, p. 151.

<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Wayne County, Division 2, p. 242B.

<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Wayne County, District 2, p. 566. 

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Wayne County, p. 502

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Wayne County Marriages, Film #000591550, p. 623.

Augusta Phillips Johnson, <hi rend="italic">A Century of Wayne County, Kentucky, 1800-1900</hi> (Louisville: The Standard Printing Co., 1939), 94. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
