<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00019571">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William W. Newell</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>A. J. Blaylock</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00019571">
                    <persName>
                      William W. Newell
                        (Mason County, Kentucky, printer and barkeeper)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1838-05-26"  ><ab>1838-05-26</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1901-05-27"  ><ab>1901-05-27</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Bourbon County, Kentucky, printer. Kentucky native. Son of Hans and Eliza Newell. Married to Sarah Ricketts Newell in Mason County, Kentucky, on June 7, 1860. Father of Elizabeth Newell, Anna D. Newell, and Claud H. Newell. Attended school in Mason County, Kentucky, in 1850. Household owned one enslaved person in Mason County in 1850. Printer in Bourbon County, Kentucky, in 1860. Barkeeper in Mason County in 1863. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mason County, Maysville, p. 107B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Mason County, District 2, p. 757.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bourbon County, Paris, p. 484.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mason County, Maysville p. 429B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Tenth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1880), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mason County, Maysville, p. 351C.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Mason County, KY, Month 1863.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994048, Mason County Deaths.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Mason County Marriages, Film 000281844.<lb/>
&quot;William W. Newell (1838-1901),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 115689720, accessed March 16, 2023, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/115689720.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
