<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018078">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Alexander Logan</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Ian Iverson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Ian Iverson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018078">
                    <persName>
                      John Alexander Logan
                        (Illinois politician and soldier.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1826-02-09"  ><ab>1826-02-09</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1886-12-26"  ><ab>1886-12-26</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Illinois politician and soldier. Illinois native. Son of John Logan and Elizabeth Jenkins Logan. Married to Mary Simmerson Cunningham Logan on November 27, 1855. Father of Mary E. Logan and John A. Logan, Jr. Attended Shiloh College in Randolph County, Illinois, from 1842-1845. Served in the First Illinois Volunteer Infantry as a second lieutenant in the Mexican-American War from June 8, 1847, to October 18, 1848. Attorney in Jackson County, Illinois, in 1850. Graduated from the University of Louisville Law School in Louisville, Kentucky, in February 1851. Member of the Illinois House of Representatives in 1843. Member of the U.S. House of Representatives from 1859 to 1861. Attorney in Benton, Franklin County, Illinois, in 1860. Served in the 31st Illinois Volunteer Infantry (U.S.A.) as colonel from September 18, 1861, to March 21, 1862. Promoted to Brigadier General of Volunteers on March 21, 1862. Promoted to Major General of Volunteers on March 13, 1863 to date from November 29, 1862. Commanded the XV Corps of the Union Army. Resigned on August 17, 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Illinois, Jackson County, Northern District, p. 233A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Illinois, Franklin County, Benton, p. 355.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Illinois</hi>, vol. 2, 1861-1866 (Sprignfield, IL: H.W. Bokker, 1886), p.539.<lb/>
Bryon Andrew<hi rend="italic">A Biography of Gen. John A. Logan</hi>(New York: H.S. Goodspeed &amp; Co., 1884), 362-363, 373, 417, 445<lb/>
Francis Bernard Heitman<hi rend="italic">Historical Register and Dictionary of the United States Army, from its Organization, September 29, 1789 to March 2, 1903</hi> Volume 1, Part 2 (Washington: Government Printing Office, 1903), 638.<lb/>
James Pickett Jones, <hi rend="italic">&quot;Black Jack:&quot; John A. Logan and Southern Illinois in the Civil War Era</hi>2nd ed. (Carbondale, IL: Southern Illinois University Press, 1995), 6, 10-14.<lb/>
&quot;John Alexander Logan Jr. (1865-1899),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #7870105, accessed July 11, 2022, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/7870105/john-alexander-logan.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
