<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00021485">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William B. Acree</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Jeremy Knoll</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00021485">
                    <persName>
                      William B. Acree
                        (Caldwell County, Kentucky, teacher and legislator)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1823"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1823</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Caldwell County, Kentucky, teacher and legislator. Kentucky native. Married to Sarah J. Calvert Acree in Caldwell County, Kentucky, on October 13, 1855. Father of Sarah Ann Acree. Teacher in Caldwell County in 1850. Household owned nine enslaved persons in Caldwell County in 1859. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Lyon County in 1859. Attorney in Russell County, Alabama, in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, District 2, p. 354B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, District 2, p. 778.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Alabama, Russell County, Opelika, p. 1081.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Caldwell County Marriages, Film 000546372, p. 236.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994029, Caldwell County Births, p. 331.<lb/>
&quot;Democratic Meeting in Lyon,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Louisville Daily Courier</hi> (Louisville, Kentucky), December 10, 1859, p. 2.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
