<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00013193">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Lewis Letig Pinkerton</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kristen Bailey</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Kristen Bailey</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00013193">
                    <persName>
                      Lewis Letig Pinkerton
                        (Woodford County, Kentucky minister, school founder, asst surgeon 11th Ky Cav USA)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1812-01-28"  ><ab>1812-01-28</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1875-01-28"  ><ab>1875-01-28</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Woodford County, Kentucky, minister, professor, and surgeon. Baltimore County, Maryland, native. Son of William Pinkerton and Elizabeth Letig Pinkerton. Married to Sarah A. Ball Pinkerton in Butler County, Ohio, on March 19, 1833. Father of William W. Pinkerton, Virginia Pinkerton, Burnett S. Pinkerton, James P. Pinkerton, Samuel D. Pinkerton, Lewis M. Pinkerton, and Mary B. Pinkerton. Resident of Hamilton County, Ohio, from 1836 to 1839. Attended Transylvania University in Lexington, Kentucky, in 1841. Founded the Kentucky Female Orphan School in Woodford County, Kentucky, in 1847. Minister in Woodford County in 1850. Owned five enslaved persons in Woodford County in 1850. Minister in Woodford County in 1860. Household owned four enslaved persons in Woodford County in 1860. Professor at Kentucky University in Mercer County, Kentucky, from 1860 to 1866. Served in the 11th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry Regiment (U.S.A.) as assistant surgeon and surgeon from August 13, 1862, to May 22, 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Woodford County, District 1, p. 447B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Woodford County, District 1.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Woodford County, Midway, p. 843.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Woodford County, Midway, p. 488A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, Lexington Ward 1, p. 195A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0110.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ohio Marriage Records, 1774-1993</hi>, Butler County Marriages, Film 000355779.<lb/>
W. T. Moore, ed., <hi rend="italic">The Living Pulpit of the Christian Church: A Series of Discourses, Doctrinal and Practical, from Representative Men among the Disciples of Christ. With a Brief Biographical Sketch and Steel Portrait of Each Contributor</hi> (Cincinnati, OH: R. W. Carroll &amp; Co., 1868), 103-4.<lb/>
John Shackleford, Jr., ed., <hi rend="italic">Letters and Addresses of Dr. L. L. Pinkerton</hi> (Cincinnati, OH: Chase &amp; Hall, 1876).<lb/>
&quot;Dr Lewis Lettig Pinkerton (1812-1875),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 46581555, accessed November 8, 2023, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/45681555. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
