<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00020240">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Schenk </title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00020240">
                    <persName>
                      William Schenk 
                        (Louisville, Kentucky, upholsterer and saloon proprietor)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1823-01-10"  ><ab>1823-01-10</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1878-11-20"  ><ab>1878-11-20</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, upholsterer and saloon proprietor. Native of Hesse. Married to Alexandra Schenk. Father of Eliza Schenk, George Schenk, and Bertha Schenk. Married to Angeline Kritzky Schenk in Jefferson County, Kentucky, on January 17, 1863. Carpet weaver in Louisville in 1858. Upholsterer in Louisville in 1860. Upholsterer in Louisville in 1861. Upholsterer in Louisville in 1863. Proprietor of the Apollo Hall Saloon in Louisville in 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 1 , p. 71.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994040, Jefferson County Marriages.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Jefferson County, KY, July 1863, p. 225.<lb/>
 <hi rend="italic">Louisville City Directory and Business Mirror for 1858-9,</hi> (Louisville: Hurd &amp; Burrows, 1859), 153.<lb/>
 <hi rend="italic">Tanner’s Louisville Directory and Business Advertiser for 1861</hi> ed. Henry Tanner (Louisville: Directory Publication and Advertising Agency, 1861), 215..<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Edwards&#39; Annual Director to the Inhabitants, Institutions, Incorporated Companies, Manufacturing Establishments, Business firms, Etc., Etc., in the City of Louisville, For 1865-6</hi> (Louisville: Edwards, Greenough &amp; Deved, 1866), 513.<lb/>
&quot;William Schenk (1823-1878),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 136803366 , accessed June 12, 2023, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/136803366.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
