<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008156">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Millbank Delph</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008156">
                    <persName>
                      John Millbank Delph
                        (Louisville, KY, mayor (61-63) and legislator (63-65))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1805-08-18"  ><ab>1805-08-18</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1891-12-16"  ><ab>1891-12-16</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, mayor and legislator. Madison County, Virginia, native. Son of Daniel Delph and Ann Millbank Delph. Married to Eliza F. Spurr Delph. Married to Ellen L. Schwing Delph in 1837. Father of Eliza Delph, Charles Delph, and Louisa Delph. Apprenticed with Matthew Kennedy in Lexington, Kentucky. Worked in real estate in Louisville. Served as the city tax collector in Louisville, and constable, sheriff, and deputy marshal in Jefferson County, Kentucky for ten years. Served on the City Council of Louisville in 1844 and from 1848 to 1849. Mayor of Louisville from 1850 to 1852. Served on the Louisville Board of Aldermen from 1853 to 1854. Mayor of Louisville from 1861 to 1863. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1863 to 1865. Helped found the Walnut Street Baptist Church in Louisville. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, Ward 7, p. 348.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, Ward 7, p. 132.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Springdale, p.17. <lb/>
“Delph, John Millbank,” in <hi rend="italic">The Encyclopedia of Louisville</hi> , ed. John E. Kleber (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 2001), p. 241.<lb/>
“John Millbank Delph (1805-1891),” Find A Grave, Memorial #45292073, accessed August 6, 2017, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/45292073.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
