<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010989">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William A. Nally</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
          </respStmt>        
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010989">
                    <persName>
                      William A. Nally
                        (Louisville, Kentucky, brick maker. )
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1819"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1819</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1878-05-29"  ><ab>1878-05-29</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, brick maker. Kentucky native. Married to Mevinda Nally. Married to Hannah Noel Nally in Bullitt County, Kentucky on November 14, 1866. Father of Edward A. and William Nally. Brick maker in Louisville, Kentucky 1850. Brick maker in Louisville, Kentucky in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson, Louisville District 3, p. 302B.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson, Louisville Ward 6, p. 341.

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson, Louisville Ward 8, p. 94A.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records – Microfilm (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Roll #994029, Bullitt County Deaths, p. 6-7.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Bullitt County Marriages, Film #000812405.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
