<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011930">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William G. Gabbert</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011930">
                    <persName>
                      William G. Gabbert
                        (Clinton County, Kentucky, farmer and Second Lieutenant (U.S.A.))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1827"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1827</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Clinton County, Kentucky, farmer and soldier. Kentucky native. Married Matilda Northrip Gabbert in Clinton County, Kentucky on July 29, 1849. Father of James G Gabbert, Mary E. Gabbert, Luiza C. Gabbert, and Taylor Gabbert. Farmer in Russell County, Kentucky in 1850. Farmer in Clinton County, Kentucky in 1860. Served in 13th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry (U.S.A.) as Second Lieutenant from December 23, 1863 to January 10, 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Russell County, District 2, p. 493. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States_ (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Clinton County, p. 237. <hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), 352. KYR-0002-222-0139. <hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Russell County Marriages, Film 000594312, p. 38. KYR-0002-222-0081.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
