<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007524">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Francis Marshall</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>James N. McAllister</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007524">
                    <persName>
                      Thomas Francis Marshall
                        (Woodford County, Kentucky, attorney, state, and U.S. Representative)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1801-06-07"  ><ab>1801-06-07</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1864-09-22"  ><ab>1864-09-22</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Woodford County, Kentucky, attorney, state, and U.S. representative. Kentucky native. Son of Lewis Marshall. Married to Elizabeth Yost Marshall in Woodford County, Kentucky, on April 1, 1852. Studied law in Virginia. Admitted to the bar in Versailles, Kentucky in 1828. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1832 to 1836. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1838 to 1839. Member of the House of Representatives of the U.S. Congress from 1841 to 1843. Served in the 1st Kentucky Cavalry as Captain during the U.S.-Mexican War. Attorney in Woodford County in 1850. Kentucky Representative from 1854 to 1856. Versailles, Woodford County resident in 1864. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Woodford County,  District No. 1, p. 439A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, X County Marriages, Film #000252320, p. 223 of 279 on microfilm (accessed via Ancestry.com). <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find a Grave Index</hi>, “Thomas Francis Marshall (1801-1864)” https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/7650542 (Accessed February 19, 2017); <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Biographical Directory of the United States Congress, 1774-Present,</hi> “Marshall, Thomas Francis, (1801-1864)” http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=M000162 Accessed February 19, 2017.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Index to Complied Service Records of Volunteer Soldiers Who Served During the Mexican War</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series, M616,  Roll 0023. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
