<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007466">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Rodophil E. Jeter</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007466">
                    <persName>
                      Rodophil E. Jeter
                        (Green &amp; Taylor County, KY, postmaster, provost marshal of Campbellsville, carpenter)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1821-11-30"  ><ab>1821-11-30</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Green County and Taylor County, Kentucky, carpenter, provost marshal, postmaster, and soldier. Kentucky native. Son of Anderson Jeter and Sorrow S. Allen Jeter. Married to Martha A. Jeter. Father of Susan Elizabeth Jeter, Martha A. Jeter, John J. Jeter, and Thomas Rodophil Jeter. House carpenter in Green County, Kentucky, in 1850. House joiner in Green County in 1860. Provost marshal of Campbellsville, Kentucky. Served in the 13th Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment U.S.A.) as captain from December 31, 1861, to his resignation on April 19, 1862. Postmaster of Campbellsville from May 5, 1864, to June 12, 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, District 1, p. 120A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensberg, p. 91.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Taylor County, Campbellsville, p. 231A.<lb/>
&quot;Jeter, the Slayer of an Indianapolis Policeman, Proves to be a Thoroughly Bad Man,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Daily Tribune</hi> (Chicago , IL), August 30, 1882, p. 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Record of Appointment of Postmasters, 1832-1971</hi> Records of the Post Office Department, NARA Series M841, RG 28, Taylor County, Kentucky, vol. 28, p. 182.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), 859.<lb/>
Steven L. Wright, <hi rend="italic">Kentucky Soldiers and Their Regiments in the Civil War: Abstracted From the Pages of Contemporary Newspapers, vol 4-5</hi>, (Lois N. Miller Genealogical Publications, 2009).<lb/>
William Henry Perrin, J.H. Battle, G.C. Kniffin, <hi rend="italic">Sketches From Adair, Boyle, Casey, Cumberland, Garrard, Green, Lincoln, Madison, Marion, Mercer, Nelson, Taylor, Washington Counties</hi> (Genealogical Reference Company, 1970).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
