<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010837">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James T. Applegate</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010837">
                    <persName>
                      James T. Applegate
                        (Pendleton County, Kentucky farmer and soldier.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1819-11-10"  ><ab>1819-11-10</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1892-06-24"  ><ab>1892-06-24</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Pendleton County, Kentucky farmer and soldier. Married to Mary A. K. Colvin Applegate on November 10, 1841. Father of William H. Applegate, John B. Applegate, John B. Applegate, Mary N. Applegate, Lucius A. Apllegate, James B. Applegate, Leslie F. Appleton, and Judith E. Appleton. Farmer in Pendleton County in 1850. Farmer in Pendleton County in 1860. Served in Captain M. Mullins Company, Police Guard Kentucky Central Railroad as Second Lieutenant from October 18, 1861 to November 11, 1861. Served in the 18th Kentucky Infantry (U.S.A.) as Second Lieutenant, First Lieutenant from October 13, 1861 to December 27, 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Pendleton County, First District, p. 363A.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Pendleton County,  p. 444.

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Pendleton County, Precinct No. 1, p. 393A. 

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, X County Marriages, Film 000272800, p. 330.

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;James T. Applegate (Nov 10, 1819-June 24, 1892),&quot; Memorial #92432124, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/92432124 (accessed July 2, 2019).

<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 398.

<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), 2, 854.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
