<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002618">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">J. T. Farris</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002618">
                    <persName>
                      J. T. Farris
                        (Louisville, Kentucky, detective and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, detective and soldier. Served in the 5th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry Regiment (U.S.A.) as first lieutenant and regimental quartermaster from October 1861 to February 1862. Served in the 9th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry Regiment from as major from August 1862 to March 1863. Commander of Barracks No. 1 in Louisville, Kentucky, from March 1863 to October 1863. Detective in Louisville from 1863 to 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0052, 0096.<lb/>
&quot;Contingent Expenses of the War Department,&quot; Executive Document, No. 78, House of Representatives, 41st Congress, 2d Session, p. 29-30.<lb/>
&quot;THE ESCAPE OF JOHN MORGAN.; The Report that He is in Toronto Discredited Recapture of Two of His Companions,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Times</hi> (New York, NY), December 3, 1863.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
