<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018411">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Y. Wiley</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Abigail Stephens</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018411">
                    <persName>
                      William Y. Wiley
                        (Indianapolis, Marion County, Indiana, real estate agent, broker, life insurance salesman, commissioner of deeds, and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1816-03-28"  ><ab>1816-03-28</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1873-01-29"  ><ab>1873-01-29</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Indianapolis, Marion County, Indiana, real estate agent, broker, life insurance salesman, commissioner of deeds, and soldier. Pennsylvania native. Married to Mary C. Wiley. Father of Louisa Wiley. Real estate agent in Indianapolis, Marion County, Indiana, in 1860. Employed Bridget Doud as a domestic servant in Indianapolis, Marion County, Indiana, in 1860. Stock and note broker in Indianapolis in 1861. Commissioner of Deeds for the Commonwealth of Kentucky in Indianapolis in 1861. Served as captain and military storekeeper in the Ordnance Department (U.S.A) from March 10, 1863 to September 30, 1870.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Indiana, Marion County, Second ward, p. 140.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Indianapolis Directory, and Business Mirror, for 1861</hi> ed. James Sutherland (Indianapolis, IN: Bowen, Stewart &amp; Co., Publishers and Booksellers, 1861), 10, 258, 277, 281, 303, 306.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Letters Received by the Commission Branch of the Adjutant General’s Office, 1863-1870</hi> NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M1064, Roll #0063.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Letters Received by the Commission Branch of the Adjutant General’s Office, 1863-1870</hi> NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M1064, Roll #0523.<lb/>
&quot;Mrs. Eliza G. Wiley Dead,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Indianapolis Journal</hi> (Indianapolis, Indiana), February 17, 1902, p. 3.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Indiana</hi>, vol. 1, 1861-1866 (Indianapolis, IN: Alexander H. Conner, State Printer, 1869), Statistics and Documents, p. 183.<lb/>
&quot;Sudden and Mysterious Death,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Evening News</hi> (Indianapolis, Indiana), January 30, 1873, p. 4.<lb/>
&quot;Capt William Y Wiley (1816-1873),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #46048244, Accessed August 17, 2022, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/46048244/william-y-wiley.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
