<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00020980">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William T. Anthony</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Jeremy Knoll</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00020980">
                    <persName>
                      William T. Anthony
                        (Allen County, Kentucky, merchant and politician.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1808-10-30"  ><ab>1808-10-30</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1896-07-24"  ><ab>1896-07-24</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Allen County, Kentucky, merchant and politician. Kentucky native. Merchant in Allen County, Kentucky, in 1850. Owned eight enslaved persons with Joseph G. Anthony in Allen County in 1850. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Allen County from 1855 to 1859. Merchant in Allen County in 1860. Owned four enslaved persons in Allen County in 1860. Household owned an additional seven enslaved persons in Allen County in 1860. Reported member of the Russellville Convention in November 1861. Expelled from the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky on charges of treason on February 15, 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Allen County, p. 121A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Allen County, p. 51.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Allen County, New Roe, p. 260.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Allen County, New Roe, p. 20B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Allen County, New Roe, p. 270A.<lb/>
Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. I (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co., 1877), 34, 770.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Journal of the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky: Begun and Held in the Town of Frankfort, on Monday, the Second Day of September, in the Year of Our Lord 1861, and of the Commonwealth the Seventieth</hi> (Frankfort, KY: Jno. B. Major, 1861), 402-4.<lb/>
&quot;William Thompson Anthony (1808-1896),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 60655286, accessed October 26, 2023, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/60655286.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
