<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011336">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Alexander H. Poston</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011336">
                    <persName>
                      Alexander H. Poston
                        (Trigg Co, Ky, merchant and prov govt)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1820"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1820</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Cadiz, Kentucky, merchant and provisional government convention member. Tennessee native. Married to Mary D. Carson Poston in Trigg County, Kentucky, on October 24, 1848. Father of John D. Poston, Alex B. Poston, Mary A. Poston, and Betty A. Poston. Resident in Trigg County in 1840. Owned one enslaved person in Trigg County in 1840. Merchant in Trigg County in 1850. Employed James R. Richardson as a merchant clerk in Trigg County in 1850. Owned four enslaved persons in Trigg County in 1850. Merchant in Cadiz in 1860. Owned eight enslaved persons in Cadiz in 1860. Member of the convention of the provisional government held at Russellville in November 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Sixth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1840), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Trigg County, p. 286.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Trigg County, District 1, p. 292B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Trigg County, District 1. p. 3 of 18 on microfilm (accesses via Ancestry.com). <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Trigg County, Cadiz, p. 190.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Trigg County, Cadiz, p. 392B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Trigg County Marriages, Film #000321335, p. 123.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
