<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010279">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Prather Linthicum</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010279">
                    <persName>
                      Thomas Prather Linthicum
                        (Nelson County, KY, attorney and politician)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1807-06-06"  ><ab>1807-06-06</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1874-07-30"  ><ab>1874-07-30</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Nelson County, Kentucky, attorney and politician. Kentucky native. Attended St. Joseph’s College. Married to Elizabeth Malone. Father of [Unknown] Linthicum. Store clerk. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky in 1837. County attorney of Nelson County. Member of the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1848 to 1851. Owned eleven enslaved persons in 1850. Nelson County commissioner. Judge of the County Court of Nelson County. President of the Louisville and Bardstown Turnpike. Attorney in Nelson County in 1860. Deacon of the Bardstown Baptist Church. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 1, p. 1. 

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 1, p. 173. 

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, Bardstown, p.78A. 

Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2 (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co., 1882), p. 645. 

<hi rend="italic">The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 581-82.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
