<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00016577">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert Bush</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00016577">
                    <persName>
                      Robert Bush
                        (Clark County, Kentucky, farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1822"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1822</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1898-06-17"  ><ab>1898-06-17</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Clark County, Kentucky, farmer. Kentucky native. Son of Joseph Bush and Elizabeth Bush. Married to Eliza Elkin Bush. Father of Louisa Bush, William F. Bush, Joseph Bush, Nancy M. Bush, Charles C. Bush, and Nanna Bush. Farmer in Clark County, Kentucky, in 1850. Farmer in Clark County in 1860. Owned three enslaved persons in Clark County in 1860. Employed Charles Landon as a day laborer in Clark County in 1860. Farmer in Clark County in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Clark County, District 2, p. 15B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Clark County, District 2, p. 837.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Clark County, District 2, p. 332A<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Clark County, Precinct 5, p. 104A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Clark County, KY, July and June 1863, p. 126.<lb/>
&quot;Death of Robert Bush,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Richmond Climax</hi> (KY), June 22, 1898.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
