<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000757">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Alexander Campbell Ellis</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000757">
                    <persName>
                      Alexander Campbell Ellis
                        (Kenton County, Kentucky, deputy circuit clerk)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1830-08-06"  ><ab>1830-08-06</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1913-07-14"  ><ab>1913-07-14</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Covington, Kentucky, deputy circuit clerk and attorney. Kenton County, Kentucky, native. Son of William G. Ellis and Susan Arnold Ellis. Married to Kate Blackburn Hereford Ellis in Fleming County, Kentucky, on July 8, 1859. Father of Sudie Ellis, Wade H. Ellis, and Woodford L. Ellis. Stepfather of Mary Hereford, Maria Hereford, and Kate Hereford. Laborer in Kenton County, Kentucky, in 1850. Household owned seven enslaved persons in Kenton County in 1850. Deputy clerk of the Kenton Circuit Court from 1856 to 1865. Commissioner of Public Schools in Kenton County in 1858. Employed Ellen Holland as a servant in Covington in 1860. Admitted to the bar 1862. Member of the Board of School Examiners for Covington in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, p. 141B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, Covington Ward 5, p. 800.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, Covington Ward 6, p. 36B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994034, Fleming County Marriages.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, File 19309. <lb/>
“Ellis Resigns as Court Clerk,” <hi rend="italic">The Kentucky Post</hi> (Covington, KY), March 1, 1913, p. 2.<lb/>
“Oldest Member of Kenton Bar, A. C. Ellis, Dead,” <hi rend="italic">The Kentucky Post</hi> (Covington, KY), July 15, 1913, p. 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi> (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 259-60.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
