<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00015581">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert P. Pepper</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00015581">
                    <persName>
                      Robert P. Pepper
                        (Franklin County, Kentucky, farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1832-11-19"  ><ab>1832-11-19</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1895-02-19"  ><ab>1895-02-19</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Franklin County, Kentucky, farmer. Kentucky native. Son of Samuel Pepper and Mahala E. Pepper. Married Anna M. Kinkhead Pepper in Woodford County, Kentucky, on October 7, 1857. Father of Lena Pepper. Farmer in Woodford County in 1850. Household owned six enslaved persons in Woodford County in 1850. Farmer in Franklin County in 1860. Employed Edward Kelley as a laborer in Franklin County in 1860. Owned seven enslaved persons in Franklin County in 1860. Household owned five other enslaved persons in Franklin County in 1860. Farmer in Franklin County in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Woodford County, District 1, p. 456A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Woodford County, District 1, p. 675.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, District 2, p. 296.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, District 2, p. 495A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, p. 141B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Franklin County, KY, July 1863, p. 19.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Woodford County Marriages, Film #000252332, p. 60.<lb/>
&quot;Robert Perry Pepper (1832-1895),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #98393765, accessed September 8, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/98393765.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
