<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011712">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Gabrael Salter</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011712">
                    <persName>
                      Gabrael Salter
                        (Garrard County, Kentucky, farmer and Provisional Congress nominee (C.S.A))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1809"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1809</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Garrard County, Kentucky, farmer and Provisional Congress nominee (C.S.A). Kentucky native. Married Barbara Marksbury Salter in Garrard County, Kentucky on November 26, 1829. Father of Richard Salter, Mary J. Salter, Sally A. Salter, Osa Salter, Michael Salter, Amanda Salter, California Salter, Thomas Salter, Mattie Salter, and Jones Salter. Owned ten enslaved persons in Garrard County in 1840. Farmer in Garrard County in 1850. Farmer in Garrard County in 1860. Deputy nominee to Sixth U.S. Congressional District of the Provisional Congress of the Confederate States in December 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Sixth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1840), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Garrard County, p. 27.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Garrard County, Division 1, p. 518. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Garrard County, p. 648. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Garrard County Marriages, Film #000183256, p. 45. <lb/>
KYR-0004-033-0025. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
