<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004290">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Hugh McCollough</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004290">
                    <persName>
                      Hugh McCollough
                        (Mason County)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1794"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1794</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Mason County, Kentucky, tavern keeper. Native of Ireland. Married to Margaret Thompson McCullough in December 1832. Father of Alexander McCullough, Hugh McCullough, William McCullough, Thomas McCullough, Ann McCullough, Mary McCullough, and Jane McCullough. Employed in commerce, manufacture, and trade in Maysville, Kentucky, in 1840. Owned three enslaved persons in Maysville in 1840. Tavern keeper in Maysville in 1850. Employed Alexander McCullough and Hugh McCullogh as barkeepers in Maysville in 1850. Owned two enslaved persons in Maysville in 1850. Resident of Mason County in 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Sixth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1840), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mason County, Maysville, Ward 1, p. 28.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mason County, Maysville, p. 107A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Mason County, Maysville, p. 757.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, X County Marriages, Film #000281842.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, File #21381.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
