<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00005997">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Peter Horace Conant</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Stephen Powell</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>MontanaWilliamson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Stephen Powell</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00005997">
                    <persName>
                      Peter Horace Conant
                        (farmer, Livingston County)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1809"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1809</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Livingston County, Kentucky, farmer and judge. Massachusetts native. Son of Joseph Conant and Patience Sawyer Conant. Married to Mary Ann Bowers Conant in Leominster County, Massachusetts, on February 9, 1832. Father of Horace Conant, George H. Conant, John H, Conant, Abby M. Conant, Peter A. Conant, Charles W. Conant, and Edward T. Conant. Tannery proprietor in Livingston County, Kentucky, in 1850. Farmer in Livingston County in 1860. Election judge for Precinct No. 1 with Jesse Thompson. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Livingston County, Smithland, p. 384A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Livingston, Division 3, p. 149. KYR-0001-005-0032. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Massachusetts, US., Town and Vital Records, 1620-1988</hi>, Massachusetts Vital and Town Records, Holbrook, MA, Leominster County Marriages, 1620-1988, p. 185.<lb/>
Frederick Odell, <hi rend="italic">A History and Genealogy of the Conant Family in England and America: Thirteen Generations, 1520-1887: Containing also some Genealogical Notes on the Connet, Connett, and Connit Families</hi> (Portland, Maine: Harris &amp; Williams, 1887) 189.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
