<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011014">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert McKee</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011014">
                    <persName>
                      Robert McKee
                        (Louisville, KY, journalist and prov govt sec of state)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1831"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1831</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1909-06-11"  ><ab>1909-06-11</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, newspaper editor and secretary of state of the provisional government of Kentucky. Fleming County, Kentucky, native. Son of William McKee and Abigail McKee. Married to Emily F. Reed McKee in Mason County, Kentucky, on August 16, 1855. Father of Charles McKee and Belle McKee. Clerk in a country store in Fleming County from 1848 to 1852. Laborer in Fleming County in 1850. Bookkeeper in Fleming County from 1852. Writer in 1856. Editor and owner of the Maysville <hi rend="italic">Express</hi> from 1857 to 1859. Editor of the <hi rend="italic">Louisville Daily Courier</hi> from 1859 to October 1861. Secretary at the convention of the provisional government in Russellville in November 1861. Elected secretary of state of the provisional government of Kentucky in 1861. Lived in Jefferson County from 1859 to October 1865. Writer and editor in Dallas County, Alabama, from October 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fleming County, Division 2, p. 391A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 2, p. 454.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Alabama, Dallas County, Selma, p. 650A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Mason County Marriages, Film #000281844, p. 400.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Mason County Marriages, Film #000281846, p. 39.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">California, Death Index, 1905-1939, Surnames L-R</hi>, California Department of Health and Welfare. California Vital Records-Vitalsearch (www.vitalsearch-worldwide.com). The Vitalsearch Company Worldwide, Inc., Pleasanton, California, p. 234 of microfilm (accessed through Ancestry.com on January 9, 2020).<lb/>
Thomas M Owen, <hi rend="italic">History of Alabama and Dictionary of Alabama Biography</hi> Vol. IV (Chicago: S.J. Clarke &amp; Co, 1921), p. 1120.<lb/>
KYR-0004-033-0002.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
