<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002368">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert J. Dyas</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002368">
                    <persName>
                      Robert J. Dyas
                        (Grant County, Kentucky, saddler, presiding judge, and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1819"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1819</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Grant County, Kentucky, saddler, presiding judge, and soldier. Native of Ireland. Married Mary Jane Henderson Dyas in Grant County, Kentucky, on October 27, 1837. Father of Susan Dyas, Henrietta Dyas, Mary A. Dyas, John Dyas, Cyrus Dyas, Henderson Dyas, Blanche Dyas, Fenley Dyas, Norman Dyas, and William Dyas. Saddler in Grant County in 1850. Saddler in Grant County in 1860. Magistrate in Grant County in 1862. Saddler in Grant County in 1864. Served in the 30th Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.) as a lieutenant and captain from August 18, 1863 to April 11, 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Grant County, Crittenden, p. 341A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, <lb/>
Kentucky, Grant County, Crittenden, p. 993. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky,  Grant County, Crittenden, p. 519A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Grant County Marriages, Film #001490815, p. 86.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Grant County, KY, June and July1864, p. 67.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 398.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
