<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00012019">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Burch Musselman</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00012019">
                    <persName>
                      Burch Musselman
                        (Jefferson County, Kentucky, farmer and Provisional Government financial agents)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1818"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1818</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Jefferson County, Kentucky, farmer and Provisional Government financial agent. Pennsylvania native. Married to Mary A. Musselman. Stepfather of Samuel Hammond and Josephine Hammond. Married to Sarah V. Musselman. Father of David Musselman, William Musselman, and Henry Musselman. Tobacconist in Louisville, Kentucky in 1850. Farmer in Jefferson County, Kentucky in 1860. Employed Thomas Esterly and George Greathouse in Jefferson County, Kentucky in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, p. 86.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, District 2, p. 1050. <lb/>
Matthew C. Hulbert, “Grabbing Guns and Breaking Banks: The Short, Ambitious “Reign” of Kentucky’s Provisional Confederate Government,” <hi rend="italic">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</hi> blog, March 9, 2016, http://civilwargovernors.org/grabbing-guns-and-breaking-banks-the-short-ambitious-reign-of-kentuckys-provisional-confederate-government (accessed January 25, 2020).<lb/><lb/>
KYR-0004-033-0030.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
