<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00015315">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">George P. Dunning</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hailey Brangers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Hailey Brangers</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00015315">
                    <persName>
                      George P. Dunning
                        (Caldwell Co, KY / Saline Co. IL, farmer and soldier 42nd US inf.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1814"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1814</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Caldwell County, Kentucky, and Saline County, Illinois, farmer and soldier. Kentucky native. Married to Sarah &quot;Sallie&quot; Ashby Dunning in Caldwell County, Kentucky, on February 21, 1832. Father of Andrew J. Dunning, Damey A. Dunning, John W. Dunning, Mary J. Dunning, James Polk Dunning, Susan R. Dunning, Charles Dunning, and Elijah Dunning. Farmer in Caldwell County in 1850. Farmer in Saline County, Illinois, in 1860. Served in the 42nd United States Volunteer Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.). </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, District 2, p. 358A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Illinois, Saline County, Township 8, Range 6 E, p. 886.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Caldwell County Marriages, Film #000851644, p. 33.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">U.S. Civil War Pension Index: General Index to Pension Files, 1861-1934</hi>, NARA RG 15, Microfilm Series T288, Illinois, Application #1271.101, Certificate #1.249.656.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
