<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00009813">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Freeman F. Runyon. Jr.</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00009813">
                    <persName>
                      Freeman F. Runyon. Jr.
                        (Madison County, medical student, farmer, and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1836-12-28"  ><ab>1836-12-28</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1862-05-05"  ><ab>1862-05-05</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Madison County, Kentucky, medical student, farmer, and soldier. Madison County native. Son of Freeman F. Runyon and Amanda Farris Runyon. Grandson of Absalom Runyon and Mary Runyon. Resident in Todd County, Kentucky, in 1850. Household owned five enslaved persons in Todd County in 1850. Medical student in Madison County in 1860. Owned five enslaved persons in Madison County in 1860. Served in the 3rd Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry Regiment (U.S.A.) as private from December 13, 1861, to May 5, 1862. Died by suicide at Shiloh, Tennessee on May 5, 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Madison County Marriages, Film #000183302, p.142

<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Todd County, District 1, p.232A.

<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Todd County, District 1, p.10 of microfilm.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records – Microfilm (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Rolls ##994027-994058, Madison County Births, p. 6 of microfilm.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Division 1, p. 294.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Division 1, p. 12

<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 34 and 474.

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Freeman F Runyon, Jr (1836-1862),&quot; Memorial #20018997, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/20018997 (accessed December 10, 2018).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
