<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008495">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Courts McFerran</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008495">
                    <persName>
                      John Courts McFerran
                        (Glasgow, KY, U.S. Army officer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1831"  ><ab>1831</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1872-04-25"  ><ab>1872-04-25</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Glasgow, Barren County, Kentucky, U.S. Army officer. Kentucky native. Son of William R. McFerran. Married to Rose H. McFerran. Graduated from the U.S. Military Academy at West Point, New York, in 1843. Brevetted to second lieutenant of the 3rd U.S. Infantry on July 1, 1843. Second lieutenant in the 7th U.S. Infantry from April 1846 to June 1846. Transferred to 3rd U.S. Infantry on June 27, 1846. Veteran of the Mexican-American War. Regimental quartermaster of the 3rd U.S. Infantry from May 1852 to October 1855. First lieutenant of the 3rd U.S. Infantry from October 1847 to December 1856. Captain and assistant quartermaster in the U.S. Quartermaster Department from August 1855 to November 1863. Major in the U.S. Quartermaster Department from November 1863 to August 1864. Colonel in the U.S. Quartermaster Department from August 1864 to June 1865. Chief quartermaster of the Department of New Mexico from September 1862 to July 1865. Chief of staff to General James H. Carleton from 1864 to 1865. Brevetted to brigadier general in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl>“A Kentucky Soldier: Death of General,” <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, Ky.), April 26, 1872, 4. “A Soldier&#39;s Funeral: Obsequies of Brig. Gen. McFerran,” <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, Ky.), April 29, 1872, 4. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Veterans Administration Pension Payment Cards, 1907-1933</hi>, NARA Microfilm Publication, M850, Records of the Department of Veterans Affairs, 1773-2007, Record group 15, Roll 1439 (Accessed via Ancestry.com).<lb/>
 <hi rend="italic">Historical Register and Dictionary of the United States Army: From Its Organization, September 29, 1789, to March 2, 1903</hi>, vol. 1 (Washington: Govt. Print. Off., 1903), 665.<lb/>
John Fiske and James Grant Wilson, ed., <hi rend="italic">Appleton&#39;s Cyclopædia of American Biography</hi>, vol. 4, (New York: Appleton, 1888), 115. <lb/>
United States War Dept., <hi rend="italic">The War of the Rebellion: a Compilation of the Official Records of the Union and Confederate Armies</hi>, vol. 48, pt. 2, (Washington: Govt. Print. Off., 1897), 203, 1089-90, 1245.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
