<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00015473">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Asa B. Gardner</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Rachael Nicholas</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00015473">
                    <persName>
                      Asa B. Gardner
                        (Warren County, Kentucky, soldier and farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1793-02-22"  ><ab>1793-02-22</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1876-10-04"  ><ab>1876-10-04</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Warren County, Kentucky, soldier and farmer. Virginia native. Son of Thomas Gardner and Sarah Wadkins Gardner. Married to Amelia Bowles Gardner. Father of Jemima Day Gardner Smith, Angeline Gardner, Ira T. Gardner, Lewis Gardner, and Elizabeth Gardner. Married to Jane Keel Gardner in Warren County, Kentucky, on February 22, 1847. Married to America R. Elam Batts Gardner in Rutherford County, Tennessee, on March 7, 1850. Father of Minerva Gardner, Asa B. Gardner, Rachel Gardner, and Ella E. Gardner. Served in the 7th Virginia Militia as a private and captain from August 26, 1814, to February 25, 1815. Resident in Warren County in 1820. Owned one enslaved person in Warren County in 1820. Resident in Edmonson County, Kentucky, in 1830. Owned two enslaved persons in Edmonson County in 1830. Farmer in Edmonson County in 1850. Owned two enslaved persons in Edmonson County in 1850. Farmer in Warren County in 1860. Employed H. Shackleford in Warren County in 1860. Owned two enslaved persons in Warren County in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Fourth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1820), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, p. 50.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Fifth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1830), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Edmonson County, p. 212.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Edmonson County, p. 4A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Edmonson County, p. 483.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, District 1, p. 743.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, District 1, p. 427A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, Lucus, p. 226A-B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">War of 1812 Pension Index: General Index to Pension Files, 1812-1815</hi>, NARA RG 15, Microfilm Series M313, Kentucky, Pension #SO 8817, p. 429 of 860 of microfilm.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Warren County Marriages, Film #000339890, p. 94.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Tennessee Marriage Records (1780-2002)</hi>,  Nashville, TN, 1804-1841: Marriage Books, Rutherford County Marriages, p. 72.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, File #19141.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Lineage Book of the Charter Members of the National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution</hi>, eds. Mary S. Lockwood and Susan Riviere Hetzel (Washington, D. C.: National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1891-1939) vol. 74: 1924, p. 51.<lb/>
&quot;Asa B. Gardner (1793-1876),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #187695095, accessed August 25, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/187695095. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
