<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002785">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Griffin Carlisle</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002785">
                    <persName>
                      John Griffin Carlisle
                        (Covington, KY, atty &amp; legislator | Later Sec. Treasury, Speaker House, &amp; Senator)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1834-09-05"  ><ab>1834-09-05</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1910-07-31"  ><ab>1910-07-31</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Kenton County, Kentucky, attorney. Campbell County native. Son of Lilborn H. Carlisle and Mary Reynolds Carlisle. Married to Mary Jane Goodson Carlisle on January 15, 1857. Father of William K. Carlisle and Logan Carlisle. Studied law under John W. Stevenson and William B. Kinkead. Laborer in Kenton County in 1850. Practiced law in partnership with William B. Kinkead in 1857. Admitted to the Kentucky bar in 1858. Elected to the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky in 1859 and 1861. Attorney in Covington in 1860. Ninth Judicial District commonwealth’s attorney pro tem in 1864. Elected to the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky in Kenton County in a special election in 1865 after a defeat by his opponent Mortimer M. Benton was deemed to be illegal. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, p. 293A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, Covington, Ward 2, p. 607. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, Covington, Ward 6, p. 63B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registrations, 1863-1865</hi>, Kentucky, Sixth Congressional District, Kenton County, 1863, p. 85. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;John Griffith Carlisle (1819-1905),&quot; Memorial 11747, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/11747  (accessed January 12, 2017).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Birth and Death Records: Covington, Lexington, Louisville, and Newport – Microfilm (before 1911)</hi>, Film 7015462: Covington, Certificate # 958, p. 1052 of microfilm.<lb/>
John J. McAfee, <hi rend="italic">Kentucky Politicians: Sketches of Representative Corn-Crackers and Other Miscellany</hi> (Louisville: Courier-Journal Job Printing Company, 1886), 44-47. <lb/>
James Barnes, <hi rend="italic">John G. Carlisle, Financial Statesman</hi> (Gloucester, Mass.: P. Smith Co., 1931, reprint 1967).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
