<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011593">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Madison &quot;Matt&quot; Pyles</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Carl Creason</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Carl Creason</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011593">
                    <persName>
                      Madison &quot;Matt&quot; Pyles
                        (Louisville, Kentucky physician)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1820-04-25"  ><ab>1820-04-25</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1866-04-26"  ><ab>1866-04-26</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, physician. Daviess County, Kentucky, native. Son of Samuel Pyles and Elizabeth Calhoun Pyles. Married to Cordelia Lafayette Talbot Pyles in Jefferson County, Kentucky, on April 1, 1847. Father of John Talbot Pyles, Madison Pyles, and Lillie R. Pyles. Graduate of the University of Louisville Medical School in 1846. Physician in Louisville from 1846 to 1866. Resident surgeon of the Marine Hospital in Louisville from 1847 to 1849. Owned four enslaved persons in Louisville in 1850. Attending surgeon at the Marine Hospital in Louisville in 1854. Owned five enslaved persons in Louisville in 1860. Trustee of the Marine Hospital in Louisville in 1861. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 3, p. 333A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, 2nd District, p. 789.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, Ward 4, p. 77.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, 4th Ward, p. 268B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film #000482707, p. 149.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994041, Jefferson County Deaths, p. 19.<lb/>
 <hi rend="italic">Tanner’s Louisville Directory and Business Advertiser for 1861</hi> ed. Henry Tanner (Louisville: Directory Publication and Advertising Agency, 1861), 345.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Annual Report of the Supervising Surgeon-General of the Marine-Hospital Service of the United States for the Fiscal Year 1896</hi>, Treasury Department, (Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, 1896), p. 289. <lb/>
L.J. Frazee, ed. <hi rend="italic">Transylvania Medical Journal</hi>, vol. 2, no. 1. (August 1852), p. 315.<lb/>
Lunsford P. Yandell, <hi rend="italic">History of the Medical Department of the University of Louisville</hi>, (Louisville: Journal Office, 1852), p. 14. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Annual Report of the Auditor of Public Accounts of the State of Kentucky, for the Fiscal Year Ending October 10, 1862</hi>, Legislative Document Series, No. 24 (Frankfort, KY: Wm. E. Hughes, State Printer, 1863), 298-306. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 173.<lb/>
&quot;Dr Madison ‘Matt’ Pyles (1820-1866),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #91985519, accessed December 16, 2019, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/91985519.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
