<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011415">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Samuel R. Mott</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011415">
                    <persName>
                      Samuel R. Mott
                        (Auglaize County, Ohio, attorney and colonel (U.S.A.))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1818-01-26"  ><ab>1818-01-26</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1896-01-15"  ><ab>1896-01-15</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Auglaize County, Ohio, attorney and soldier. Knox County, Ohio native. Son of Gideon Mott and Anne Newell Mott. Married to Caroline Kepner Mott in Auglaize, Kentucky in 1843. Father of John Mott, Thomas Mott, Walter Mott, Willis A. Mott, Mary Mott, Charles W. Mott, and Benjamin Mott. Bricklayer and plasterer in Auglaize County from 1833 to 1836. Bricklayer and plaster in Auglaize County in 1838. Teacher in Auglaize County in the fall of 1838. Student of law in Piqua from 1840 to 1842. Prosecuting attorney in Mercer County, Ohio, in 1846. Prosecuting attorney in Auglaize County, Ohio, in 1848. Elected to the Ohio Legislature as a democrat in 1848. Served in the 20th Ohio Infantry as captain from April 1861 to July 1861. Served in the 31st Ohio Infantry as captain in October 1861. Served as colonel of 118th Regiment of the Ohio Volunteer Infantry (U.S.A.) from October 5, 1861, to February 10, 1864. Honorably discharged from the U.S. Army in March 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Official Roster of the Soldiers of the State of Ohio in the War of Rebellion, 1861-1866, Vol. VIII</hi> (Cincinnati: The Ohio Valley Press, 1888), 217.<lb/>
C. W. Williamson, <hi rend="italic">History of western Ohio and Auglaize County</hi> (Columbus, OH: W.M. Linn &amp; Sons, 1905), p. 682-684.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Ohio, Auglaize, Saint Marys, p. 506B.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
