<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00005065">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John R. B. Watkins</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00005065">
                    <persName>
                      John R. B. Watkins
                        (Dunklin County, Missouri, minister and farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Dunklin County, Missouri, minister and farmer. Tennessee native. Married to Frances Catherine Rice Watkins. Father of Almelda C. Watkins, Robert S. Watkins, R.S.S. Watkins, and Lucinda M. Watkins. Methodist minister and farmer in McNairy County, Tennessee, in 1850. Minister in Marshall County, Kentucky, in 1858. Farmer in Dunklin County, Missouri, in 1860. Convicted of violation of the laws of war by a U.S. military commission in Cape Girardeau, Missouri, on December 15, 1863. Imprisoned at Myrtle Street Prison in Scott County, Missouri, from April 3, 1863, to December 15, 1863. Imprisoned at the Alton, Illinois, Military Prison from December 15, 1863. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Tennessee, County, District 8, p. 89A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Missouri, Dunklin County, Union, p. 910.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records – Microfilm (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Roll #994048, Marshall County Births, p. 9-10, p. 646 of 741 of microfilm. <lb/>
_Union Provost Marshals’ File of Papers Relating to Individual Civilians, 1861-1867. NARA RG 109. Microfilm series M0345.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
