<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00015723">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Joshua Barnes Fitch</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Rachael Nicholas</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00015723">
                    <persName>
                      Joshua Barnes Fitch
                        (Lewis County, Kentucky, postmaster, farmer, justice of the peace, carpenter, and county sheriff)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1823-07-24"  ><ab>1823-07-24</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1886-08-10"  ><ab>1886-08-10</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Lewis County, Kentucky, postmaster, farmer, justice of the peace, carpenter, and sheriff. Kentucky native. Married to Mahala Ruggles Fitch in Lewis County, Kentucky, on October 11, 1846. Father of Thomas C. Fitch, William L. Fitch, Horatio B. Fitch, Laura F. Fitch, Elijah H. Fitch, and Mary H. Fitch. Postmaster at Clarksburg in Lewis County from October 24, 1854, to March 17, 1856. Farmer in Lewis County in 1860. Justice of the peace in Clarksburg in 1862. Carpenter in Lewis County in 1863. County sheriff in Lewis County in 1864. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Lewis County, p. 894.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Lewis County, Vanceburg, p. 532A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Annual Report of the Auditor of Public Accounts of the State of Kentucky, for the Fiscal Year Ending October 10, 1863</hi>, Legislative Document Series, No. 10 (Frankfort, KY: Wm. E. Hughes, State Printer, 1864), 149.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Lewis County, KY, October 1863, p. 48.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll #994045, Lewis County Births.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Lewis County Marriages, Film #000344051, p. 15.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Record of Appointment of Postmasters, 1832-1971</hi> Records of the Post Office Department, NARA Series M841, RG 28, Lewis County, Kentucky, vol. 14.<lb/>
&quot;Joshua Barnes Fitch (1823-1886),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #44819898, accessed September 20, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/44819898.<lb/>
KYR-0001-031-0033. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
