<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003203">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John W. Cardwell</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003203">
                    <persName>
                      John W. Cardwell
                        (Mercer County, Kentucky, bank cashier and merchant)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1809-02-01"  ><ab>1809-02-01</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1882-02-09"  ><ab>1882-02-09</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Mercer County, Kentucky, bank cashier and merchant. Shelbyville, Kentucky, native. Married to Sophia Bledsoe Taylor Cardwell in March 1830. Father of John T. Cardwell, Telulia Cardwell, James M. Cardwell, Susan L. Cardwell, Thomas M. Cardwell, Samuel Creed Cardwell, Wesley K. Cardwell, Nannie Cardwell, and Llewellyn Davis Cardwell. Apprentice in a printing house. Trustee for the Harrodsburg Methodist Episcopal Church in Harrodsburg, Kentucky, in 1842. Notary Public in Mercer County in 1847. Co-founder of Monadelphian Society of Industrial Education in 1849. Dry goods clerk in 1850. Partner and, later, full owner of Capt. Bull’s Corner dry goods business. Owned three enslaved persons in Mercer County in 1850. Cashier of Harrodsburg Savings Institution in 1860 and 1863. Served in the Mercer County Home Guard as captain in June 1861. Provost marshal in Mercer County.  </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, District 1, p. 271B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, District 1, p. 837.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, District 1, pp. 685-86.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, Harrodsburg, p. 581A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Passed at the December Session, 1841</hi> (Frankfort, KY: A. G. Hodges &amp; Co., State Printer, 1842), 174.<lb/>
Taliaferro P. Shaffner, ed., _ The Kentucky State Register, for the Year 1847_ (Louisville: Morton &amp; Griswold, 1847), 133. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Passed at the December Session, 1848</hi> (Frankfort, KY: A. G. Hodges &amp; Co., State Printer, 1849), 409-10. <lb/>
Thomas W. Westerfield, ed., <hi rend="italic">Kentucky Genealogy and Biography: Sketches from Adair, Boyle, Casey, Cumberland, Garrard, Green, Lincoln, Madison, Marion, Mercer, Nelson, Taylor, Washington Counties</hi>, vol. 5 (Owensboro, Ky.: Genealogical Reference Company, 1975), 74. Reprint of W. H. Perrin, J. H. Battle, and G. C. Kniffin, <hi rend="italic">Kentucky: A History of the State</hi>, 4th ed. <lb/>
&quot;John Wesley Cardwell (1809-1882),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #100176979, accessed April 23, 2018, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/100176979.<lb/>
KYR-0002-022-0123.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
