<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00021271">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">George P. Albert</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Jeremy Knoll</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00021271">
                    <persName>
                      George P. Albert
                        (Louisville, KY, carpenter and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1830-01-18"  ><ab>1830-01-18</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1921-06-25"  ><ab>1921-06-25</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, carpenter and soldier. Kentucky native. Son of May C. Albert. Married to Louisa Gregory Albert in Jefferson County, Kentucky, on March 28, 1851. Father of Ella Albert and Mary Albert. Served in the 4th Kentucky Volunteer Regiment as a corporal in the U.S.-Mexican War. Carpenter in Louisville, Kentucky, in 1850. Served in the Citizen&#39;s Artillery of Louisville, Kentucky State Militia, as third lieutenant in 1860. Carpenter in Louisville in 1861. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 1, p. 98B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 2, p. 148B.<lb/>
&quot;Albert, George,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Carded Records Showing Military Service of Soldiers Who Fought in Volunteer Organizations During the Mexican War, complied 1899-1927, documenting the period 1846-1848</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M638, Roll 0001.<lb/>
“George P. Albert,” <hi rend="italic">Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, File 12604. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film 000482707, p. 93.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Tanner’s Louisville Directory and Business Advertiser for 1861</hi> ed. Henry Tanner (Louisville: Directory Publication and Advertising Agency, 1861), 18.<lb/>
KYR-0001-025-0021
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
