<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018678">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Berryman Hurt</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018678">
                    <persName>
                      Berryman Hurt
                        (Bath County, Kentucky, farmer and iron worker)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1804-04-10"  ><ab>1804-04-10</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1887-07-15"  ><ab>1887-07-15</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Bath County, Kentucky, farmer and iron worker. South Carolina native. Father of Mary W. Hurt and William True Hurt. Married to Elizabeth L. Berry Hurt in Bath County, Kentucky, on May 18, 1846. Father of James G. Hurt, Alice J. Hurt, Julia Hurt, Fannie Hurt, Catharine W. Hurt, Elizabeth L. Hurt, and John S. Hurt. Farmer in Bath County, Kentucky, in 1850. Owned ten enslaved persons in Bath County in 1850. Iron worker in Bath County in 1860. Owned three enslaved persons in Bath County in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bath County, District 2, p. 1A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Bath County, District 2, p. 294.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bath County, Owingsville, p. 4.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Bath County, Owingsville, p. 74A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Illinois, Sangamon County, Cartwright, p. 54A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Bath County Marriages, Film 000273005.<lb/>
&quot;Berryman Hurt (1804-1887),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 24292724, accessed September 27, 2022, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/24292724.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
