<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00015239">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Warren Nye</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00015239">
                    <persName>
                      James Warren Nye
                        (Carson City, Nevada, governor, police commissioner)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1815-06-10"  ><ab>1815-06-10</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1876-12-25"  ><ab>1876-12-25</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Carson City, Nevada, governor, judge, senator, and commissioner. Madison County, New York, native. Son of James Nye and Thankful Crocker Nye. Married to Elsie Benson Nye. Father to Mary Nye and Charles Nye. Attended Homer Academy in New York. District attorney in Madison County, New York, in 1839. Judge of Madison County Court in New York from 1840-1848. County Court Judge in Madison County in 1850. Boarder in New York City in 1855. First commissioner of the Metropolitan Board of Police in New York City from 1857 to 1860. Governor of the Nevada Territory from March 22, 1861, to October 31, 1864. Governor of the State of Nevada from October 31, 1864, to December 5, 1864. Member of the United States Senate from Nevada from February 1, 1865, to March 3, 1873. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, New York, Madison County, Hamilton, p. 103B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Census of the State of New York</hi> (1855), New York County, City New York, Ward 20, District 5, p. 45.<lb/>
&quot;Gov. James Warren Nye,&quot; National Governors Association, accessed August 4, 2021, https://www.nga.org/governor/james-warren-nye/.<lb/>
&quot;James Warren Nye, (1815-1876),&quot; Biographical Directory of the United States Congress, 1774-Present, accessed August 4, 2021, https://bioguideretro.congress.gov/Home/MemberDetails?memIndex=n000177.<lb/>
John R. Totten, <hi rend="italic">Thacher-Thatcher Genealogy, Part I: Coat-of-Arms</hi>, (New York: New York Genealogical and Biographical Society, 1910), 292, 295-96.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
