<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011684">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Walter De B. Morrill (Richard Baxter Morrill)</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Carl Creason</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011684">
                    <persName>
                      Walter De B. Morrill (Richard Baxter Morrill)
                        (Kentucky, notary, soldier (U.S.A.))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1822-10-10"  ><ab>1822-10-10</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Kentucky, notary, soldier. Meriden, New Hampshire native. Married to Mary J. Nutter Morrill in Wells River, Vermont, on October 11, 1845. Father of Daniel Morrill, Lettie Morrill, Edd Morrill, Paul Morrill, and John Morrill. Attended Kimball Union Academy in Plainfield, New Hampshire, from 1839 to 1843. Served as quartermaster of the 74th Illinois Infantry from 1863 to 1865. Served as colonel and military agent at Louisville, Kentucky, in 1864. Nominated notary public for Kentucky at large on September 7, 1865. Appointed a special agent to visit sick and wounded soldiers in Kentucky on September 27, 1865. Real estate broker in Kentucky in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">The General Catalogue and a Brief History of Kimball Union Academy..., 1815-1880</hi>, (Claremont, N.H.: The Claremont Manufacturing Company, 1880),126.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson, Louisville Ward 6, p. 588A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Journal of the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</hi>, (Frankfort: State Printing Office, 1865), 94.<lb/>
KYR-0001-004-2333.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
