<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00009694">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Richard Montgomery Gano</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>        
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00009694">
                    <persName>
                      Richard Montgomery Gano
                        (Confederate brigadier general)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1830-06-17"  ><ab>1830-06-17</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1913-03-27"  ><ab>1913-03-27</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Physician and soldier. Bourbon County, Kentucky, native. Son of John Allen Gano and Mary Catherine Conn. Attended Bacon College in Harrodsburg, Kentucky, and Bethany College in Bethany, Virginia. Graduated from the medical college in Louisville, Kentucky, in 1849. Married to Martha Jones Welch on March 15, 1853. Father of William. B. Gano, John T. Gano,  Clarence W. Gano, Sam W. Gano, Kate M. Gano, Fannie Gano, and Maurice Gano. Physician in Bourbon County in 1850. Farmer and physician in Texas in 1860. Member of the Texas legislature from Tarrant County in 1860 and 1861. Colonel in the 7th Kentucky Cavalry (C.S.A.). Appointed brigadier general March 17, 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bourbon County, District 2, p. 240A.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Texas, Dallas County, Dallas, p. 389.

<hi rend="italic">Tenth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1880), Population Schedules, Texas, Dallas County, Dallas, p. 108B.

<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Confederate General and Staff Officers, and Nonregimental Enlisted Men</hi>, RG 109, Microfilm Series M331, Roll 0101 (accessed via fold3.com). 

Lindsey Apple, “Richard Montgomery Gano,” in <hi rend="italic">Kentuckians in Gray: Confederate Generals and Field Officers of the Bluegrass State</hi>, Bruce S. Allardice and Lawrence Lee Hewitt, eds. (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 2015), 96-102.

Charles David Grear, <hi rend="italic">Why Texans Fought in the Civil War</hi> (College Station: Texas A &amp; M University Press, 2010), 92-93.

<hi rend="italic">Memorial And Biographical History of Dallas County, Texas</hi> (Chicago: The Lewis Publishing Company, 1892), 999-1001.

<hi rend="italic">Texas, Death Certificates, 1890-1976</hi>, Texas State Library, Dallas County, March 27, 1913 (accessed via fold3.com). 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
