<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010076">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Ebenezer Dumont</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Louise Jones</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Emily D. Moses</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010076">
                    <persName>
                      Ebenezer Dumont
                        (Indiana, Bank President, Union Army general, US Representative)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1814-11-23"  ><ab>1814-11-23</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1871-04-16"  ><ab>1871-04-16</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Marion County, Indiana, bank president and soldier. Vevay, Switzerland County, Indiana native. Son of John and Julia Dumont. Married to Mary A. Cheek Dumont on April 18, 1839.  Father of Mary Fannie Dumont, Julia L. Dumont, Cornelia Cory Dumont, John F. Dumont, Martha E. Dumont, Emma Dumont, Clinton Charles Dumont, Isabella Dumont, Anna Dumont, Jessie Dumont. Graduate of the University of Indiana. Served in the Indiana State House of Representatives in 1838 and from 1850 to 1853.  Served as a Lieutenant Colonel in the Mexican War. Bank President in Marion County, Indiana in 1860. Appointed Colonel in the 7th Regiment Indiana Volunteer Infantry on April 27, 1861; promoted to brigadier general in September 1861.  Commander of the 17th Brigade in 1862; Commander of the 12th Division of the Army of the Ohio in 1862. Resigned from the army in 1863. Served in the United States House of Representatives from 1863 until 1867.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">United States. Congress. 1998. Biographical Directory of the United States Congress, 1774-Present</hi> Washington, D.C.: United States Congress. http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=D000524.

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Ebenezer Dumont (1814-1871),&quot; Memorial #5888321, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/5888321 (accessed January 3, 2019).

Warner, Ezra J. 1964. Generals in Blue : Lives of the Union Commanders. Baton Rouge, La.: Louisiana State University Press, p. 132-133.

Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States_ (1850), Population Schedules, Indiana, Dearborn County, City of Lawrenceburg, p. 331B. 

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Indiana, Marion County, Second Ward, p. 161. 

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Indiana, Marion County, Center Township, p. 10.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
