<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00017449">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Andrew Jackson Gorham</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>MontanaWilliamson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>MontanaWilliamson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00017449">
                    <persName>
                      Andrew Jackson Gorham
                        (Fayette County, Kentucky, farmer. )
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1832-12-17"  ><ab>1832-12-17</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1914-05-09"  ><ab>1914-05-09</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Fayette County, Kentucky, farmer.  Fayette County, Kentucky, native. Son of George Gorham and Nancy Graves Gorham. Married to Sarah E. Wallace Gorham in Fayette County, Kentucky, in February 1860. Father of John Breckenridge Gorham. Farmer in Fayette County in 1850. Farmer in Fayette County in 1860. Owned one enslaved person in Fayette County in 1860. Household owned seventeen other enslaved persons in Fayette County in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, District 1, p. 155A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, District 2, p. 332.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, District 2, p. 440A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, File #12015.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Fayette County Marriages, Film #007897103, p. 819.<lb/>
&quot;Mr. A.J. Gorham Dies After Long Illness,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Lexington Herald</hi> (Lexington, KY), May 10, 1914, p. 1.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
