<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00009121">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Horatio Fleming Simrall</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00009121">
                    <persName>
                      Horatio Fleming Simrall
                        (Jefferson County, KY, attorney and law professor, offered VP of prov govt)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1818-02-16"  ><ab>1818-02-16</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1901-08-15"  ><ab>1901-08-15</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, attorney and law professor. Shelby County, Kentucky, native. Son of James Simrall and Rebecca Graham Simrall. Attended Hanover College in Hanover, Indiana, and Transylvania University in Lexington, Kentucky. Married Lydia Ann Newell Simrall in Mississippi on February 22, 1842. Father of Graham H. Simrall, James Simrall, Horatio F. Simrall, Joseph Simrall, and George B. N. Simrall.  Served in the Mississippi state legislature from 1846 to 1848. Attorney in Wilkinson County, Mississippi, in 1850. Law professor at the University of Louisville from 1857 to 1861. Attorney in Louisville in 1860. Owned five enslaved persons in Jefferson County in 1860. Attorney in Louisville in 1861. Offered vice-presidency of the Kentucky provisional government under George Johnson in 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Mississippi, Wilkinson County, p. 295A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 5, p. 119.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, p. 272B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Mississippi, Jackson County, Hinds , p. 746B.<lb/>
Henry Tanner, ed., <hi rend="italic">Tanner’s Louisville Directory and Business Advertiser for 1861</hi> (Louisville: Directory Publication and Advertising Agency, 1861), 227. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Biographical and Historical Memoirs of Mississippi</hi>, vol. 2, (Chicago: The Goodspeed Publishing Co., 1881), 772-775.<lb/>
G. Glenn Clift, <hi rend="italic">Governors of Kentucky, 1792-1942</hi> (Cynthiana, Ky: Hobson Press, 1942), 142-43.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Judge Horatio Fleming Simrall (1818-1901),&quot; Memorial 26780638, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/26780638  (accessed May 14, 2020).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
