<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00020435">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Edward Gorman</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00020435">
                    <persName>
                      Edward Gorman
                        (Louisville, Kentucky, laborer and shoemaker)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1831-02-08"  ><ab>1831-02-08</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1888-08-31"  ><ab>1888-08-31</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, laborer and shoemaker. Native of Ireland. Married to Catherine Beaty Gorman in Jefferson County, Kentucky, on September 4, 1862. Father of John Gorman. Laborer in Louisville, Kentucky, in 1860. Proprietor of the Eagle Shoe Store in partnership with Michael Gorman in Gorman &amp; Brother in Louisville in 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 2, p. 914.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 8, p. 138A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Tenth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1880), Population Schedules, Kentucky,  Jefferson County, Louisville, District 101, p. 303A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film 000819615.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Edwards&#39; Annual Director to the Inhabitants, Institutions, Incorporated Companies, Manufacturing Establishments, Business firms, Etc., Etc., in the City of Louisville, For 1865-6</hi> (Louisville: Edwards, Greenough &amp; Deved, 1866), 323.<lb/>
&quot;Edward J. Gorman (1831-1888),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 218904558, accessed July 17, 2023, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/218904558.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
