<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00019908">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Mooney, Jr.</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniel Farrell</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00019908">
                    <persName>
                      Thomas Mooney, Jr.
                        (Peoria County, Illinois, farmer and court clerk.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1820"  ><ab>1820</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1901-05-01"  ><ab>1901-05-01</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Peoria County, Illinois, farmer and court clerk. New York native. Son of Thomas Mooney, Sr., and Helena Stagg Mooney. Married to Frances Neal Mooney in Peoria County, Illinois, on March 9, 1845. Father of Thomas Mooney, Helena Mooney, and Angeletta Mooney. Married to Roseanna C. Brady Mooney in Peoria County, Illinois, in August 1856. Father of John Mooney, Ellen Mooney, and Rose Mooney. Farmer in Peoria County in 1850. Farmer in Peoria County in 1860. Clerk of the Peoria Circuit Court from November 1864 to November 1868.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Illinois, Peoria County, p. 214A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Illinois, Peoria County, Medina, p. 415.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Missouri, Barton County, Nashville Township, p. 838B.. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Illinois County Marriage Records, 1800-1940</hi>, Peoria County Marriages, Peoria County Courthouse, Peoria, IL, Marriage Register 1825-1855, p. 99.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Illinois County Marriage Records, 1800-1940</hi>, Peoria County Marriages, Peoria County Courthouse, Peoria, IL, Marriage Register 1855-1859, p. 59.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Peoria County Deaths, 1878-1915</hi>, Peoria County Courthouse, Peoria, IL, Death Registers: 1889-1902, p. 139.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The History of Peoria County Illinois</hi> (Chicago: Johnson &amp; Company, 1880), 349, 676.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
