<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010669">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Abraham B. Gardner</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
          </respStmt>        
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010669">
                    <persName>
                      Abraham B. Gardner
                        (Bennington County, Bennington, Vermont, attorney and politician )
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1819-09-02"  ><ab>1819-09-02</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1881-11-28"  ><ab>1881-11-28</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Bennington County, Bennington, Vermont, attorney and politician. Vermont native. Son of David Gardner and Eunice Gardner. Married to Mary J. Gardner c.1850. Father of Anna Gardner and Isaac T.W. Gardner. Graduated from Union College in Schenectady, New York in 1841. Admitted to Vermont bar in Bennington County, Vermont in February 1847. Attorney in Bennington, Vermont in 1850. Served as State Attorney for Bennington County, Vermont between 1855 and 1857. Served as Vermont Banking Commissioner between 1855 and 1867. Attorney in Bennington, Vermont in 1860. Employed Ann Tynan and Margaret Lonnegan in Bennington, Vermont in 1860. Member of the Vermont House of Representatives from Bennington County between 1860 and 1865. Enrolled for military duty in First District of Vermont on May 1, 1863 (U.S.A). Served as the Vermont Speaker of the House between 1863 and 1865. President of the senate in 1865. Appointed Lieutenant Governor of Vermont between 1865 and 1867. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Vermont, Bennington County, Bennington, p. 455. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Vermont, Bennington County, Bennington, p. 650. <hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Abraham Brookins Gardner (September 2, 1819-November 28, 1881),&quot; Memorial #26870630, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/26870630 (accessed May 15, 2019). <hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865 (Civil War Union Draft Records), Bennington County, VT, May 1863, p. 70, (Accessed via ancestry.com)._Vermont, Wills and Probate Records, 1749-1999. Probate Place: Bennington, Vermont, “David Gardner,”  Probate Estate Files, Gardner, Abraham-Gibbs, Caleb, 1784-1884, p. 194, 196Centennial Catalog, New York Alpha of the Phi Beta Kappa, Union College (Schenectady, N.Y., 1922), 38. “Abram B. Gardner,” _Report of the Fifth Annual Meeting of the American Bar Association, Held At Saratoga Springs, New York, August 8th, 9th, 10th, and 11th, 1882 (Philadelphia, PA: Press of George S. Harris &amp; Sons, 1883), 164. Samuel B. Hand, The Star That Set: The Vermont Republican Party, 1854-1974 (New York, NY: Lexington Books, 2002), 41, 54. KYR-0001-009-0055. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
