<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010847">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William W. Ireland</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010847">
                    <persName>
                      William W. Ireland
                        (Boone County and Pendleton County, KY, attorney)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1835"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1835</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1907-07-10"  ><ab>1907-07-10</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Boone County and Pendleton County, Kentucky, attorney. Gallatin County, Kentucky, native. Son of James Ireland and Elizabeth Oliver Ireland. Married to America J. Anderson Ireland in Boone County on August 30, 1859. Father of Sallie M. Ireland and H. D. Ireland. Law student in Boone County in 1860. Attorney in Pendleton County in 1863. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eight Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Boone County, Verona District, p. 466.<lb/><lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Pendleton County, Falmouth, p. 411A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Boone County Marriages, Film #000216817, p. 17-8.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865 (Civil War Union Draft Records), Pendleton County, KY, June-July 1863, p. 219 (accessed via Ancestry.com).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Indiana State Board of Health, Death Certificates, 1899–2011</hi>, Indiana Archives and Records Administration, Indianapolis, IN, Death Certificates, 1907, Roll 14, Certificate #479, p. 107, p. 564 of 2564 of microfilm (accessed via Ancestry.com).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
