<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007507">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Bennett McCreary</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>James N. McAllister</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007507">
                    <persName>
                      James Bennett McCreary
                        (Madison County, KY, attorney and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1838-07-08"  ><ab>1838-07-08</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1918-10-18"  ><ab>1918-10-18</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Madison County, Kentucky, attorney and soldier. Son of Dr. Edmund R. and Sabrina McCreary. Graduated from Centre College in Danville in 1857. Earned a law degree from Cumberland University in Tennessee in 1859. Attorney in Madison County in 1860. Household owned eleven enslaved persons in Madison County in 1860. After the Battle of Richmond in August 1862, joined the newly formed Confederate 11th Kentucky Cavalry as a Major. Promoted to lieutenant colonel in July 1863. Captured at the Battle of Buffington Island, Ohio. Prisoner of war in Cincinnati, Ohio; Fort Delaware, Delaware; and Morris Island, South Carolina. Released in August 1863 as part of a prisoner exchange. Resumed command of a Confederate battalion in late 1863, and served in that capacity until the end of the war.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Richmond, p. 145.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Richmond, p. 474B. 

<hi rend="italic">Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</hi> “McCreary, James Bennett (1838-1918) http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=m000382 (Accessed February 12, 2017).

Nicholas C. Burckel, &quot;From Beckham to McCreary, The Progressive Record of Kentucky Governors,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Register</hi> 76 (Oct. 1978): 285-307.

<hi rend="italic">U.S., Find a Grave Index, 1600s-Current,</hi> “James Bennett McCreary (1838-1918)” https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/7909094 (Accessed February 12, 2017).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
