<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003088">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Todd</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003088">
                    <persName>
                      Thomas Todd
                        (Shelby County, Kentucky, farmer, soldier, and politician)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1820-12-20"  ><ab>1820-12-20</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1909-04-29"  ><ab>1909-04-29</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Shelby County, Kentucky, farmer, soldier, and politician. Lincoln County, Kentucky, native. Son of Charles S. Todd and Letitia Shelby Todd. Married to Jane Smith Todd on January 14, 1841. Father of Charles S. Todd and Henry S. Todd. Married to Susie H. Jacobs Todd in 1851. Married to Elizabeth D. Bonney Todd in 1860. Father of Katherine S. Todd, C. D. Bonney Todd, Bessie V. Todd, Charles S. Todd, and Letitia S. Todd. Captain in the 3rd Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.) in the Mexican-American War in 1847. Member of the Masonic Order in Kentucky from 1842 to 1909. Farmer in Shelby County in 1850. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Shelby County in 1850. Owned eight enslaved persons in Shelby County in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Shelby County, District 1, p. 59. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Shelby County, District 1, p. 27. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Shelby County, Shelby County, Precinct 1, p. 1. <lb/>
E. Polk Johnson, <hi rend="italic">A History of Kentucky and Kentuckians: The Leaders and Representative Men in Commerce, Industry, and Modern Activities</hi>, vol. 3 (Chicago, IL: Lewis Publishing Company, 1912), p. 1501-03. <lb/>
Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">History of Kentucky, Volume II</hi> (Covington, KY: Collins and Company, 1878), p. 709. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Henry County Marriages, Film #000259288.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Capt Thomas Steward Todd (1820- 1909),&quot; Memorial #81020374, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/81020374 (accessed August 2, 2018).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
