<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000827">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Samuel McKee</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000827">
                    <persName>
                      Samuel McKee
                        (Montgomery County, Kentucky, attorney, captain (U.S.A.), and US Representative)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1833-11-05"  ><ab>1833-11-05</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1898-12-11"  ><ab>1898-12-11</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Montgomery County, Kentucky, attorney, soldier, and politician. Montgomery County, Kentucky, native. Son of James McKee and Sally McKee. Married to Sophia Brainard McKee in Butler County, Ohio, on October 4, 1859. Father of Frank McKee. Attended school in Montgomery County, Kentucky, in 1850. Household owned two enslaved persons in Montgomery County in 1850. Graduate of Miami University in Butler County, Ohio, in 1857. Graduate of the Cincinnati Law School in Cincinnati, Ohio, in 1858. Admitted to the bar in June 1858. Served in the 14th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry (U.S.A.) as captain from August 21, 1862, to May 5, 1864. Captured in Mount Sterling, Kentucky, on March 22, 1863. Prisoner of war in Knoxville, Tennessee, from March 1863 to April 9, 1863. Prisoner of war at Libby Prison in Richmond, Virginia, from April 9, 1863, to April 30, 1864. Paroled to Camp Parole in Annapolis, Maryland, on May 2, 1864. Member of the House of Representatives of the United States from the Ninth Congressional District of Kentucky from 1865 to 1867. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Montgomery County, District 1, p. 9B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Montgomery County, District 1, p. 33.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Montgomery County, Mount Sterling, p. 314.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky,  Jefferson County, Louisville, District 7, p. 63A-B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ohio Marriage Records, 1774-1993</hi>, Butler County Marriages, Film 000355779, p. 25.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers Who Served in Organizations From the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0131.<lb/>
H. Charles Ulman, <hi rend="italic">Lawyers&#39; Record and Official Register of the United States</hi>, (New York: A.S. Barnes &amp; Company, 1872), p. 527.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The Alumni and Former Student Catalogue of Miami University, Including the Board of Trustees and Faculty</hi>, (Oxford, OH: Press of the Oxford News, 1892), p. 72.<lb/>
&quot;Samuel McKee (1833-1898),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 7095889, accessed October 10, 2023, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/7095889.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
