<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00015535">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Perry Wherritt </title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00015535">
                    <persName>
                      Perry Wherritt 
                        (Harrison County, Kentucky, tanner and county court clerk)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1807-11-24"  ><ab>1807-11-24</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1883-05"  ><ab>1883-05</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Harrison County, Kentucky, tanner and county court clerk. Jessamine County, Kentucky, native. Son of Thomas Wherritt and Margaret King Wherritt. Married to Zerelda A. Morrison Wherritt in Harrison County, Kentucky, on February 24, 1831. Father of Sarah Wherritt, Ann Wherritt, Margaret Wherritt, David H. Wherritt, Mary Hannah Wherritt, Thomas Wherritt, and Ellen Wherritt. Student in Danville, Kentucky, in 1823. Tanner in Cynthiana from 1829 to 1840. Deputy marshal for the U.S. Census in Harrison County in 1840. Assignee in bankruptcy from 1842 to 1849. Postmaster at Cynthiana from September 1845 to September 5, 1849. Merchant in Cynthiana in 1844. Tanner in Harrison County in 1850. Elected clerk of the Harrison County Court in 1851. Clerk for the Harrison County Court in 1860. Owned four enslaved persons (including Sally and Mally) in Harrison County in 1860. Clerk for the Harrison County Court in 1861. Imprisoned at Camp Chase in Columbus, Ohio, from July 26, 1862, to October 31, 862. Signed a oath of allegiance to the U.S. government on October 31, 1862. Imprisoned at the Louisville Military Prison in Louisville, Kentucky, from August 1864 to September 3, 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, District 1, p. 56B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, Cynthiana, p. 580.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, Cynthiana, p.122B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll #994037, Harrison County Births.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Harrison County Marriages, Film #000216893.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Lineage Book of the Charter Members of the National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution</hi>, eds. Mary S. Lockwood and Susan Riviere Hetzel (Washington, D. C.: National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1891-1939) vol. 16: 1896, p. 218-219.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Record of Appointment of Postmasters, 1832-1971</hi> Records of the Post Office Department, NARA Series M841, RG 28, Harrison County, Kentucky, 634-645.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Selected Records of the War Department Relating to Confederate Prisoners of War 1861-1865</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M598, Roll 0025.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Union Provost Marshals’ File of Paper Relating to Individual Civilians</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M345, Roll 0268.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, vol. I (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 624-625.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">History of Bourbon, Scott, Harrison, and Nicholas Counties, Kentucky</hi>, ed. William Henry Perrin (Chicago: O.L. Baskin &amp; Co. Historical Publishers, 1882) 250.<lb/>
&quot;Perry Wherritt (1807-1833),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #43077942, accessed September 6, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/43077942.<lb/>
KYR-0001-017-0192
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
