<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006448">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Russell Hallam</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Samuel T. Whittaker</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Emily D. Moses</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006448">
                    <persName>
                      James Russell Hallam
                        (Kenton Co/Campbell Co Lawyer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1818-10-16"  ><ab>1818-10-16</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1895-02-15"  ><ab>1895-02-15</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Newport, Kentucky, attorney and politician. Washington County, Pennsylvania native. Son of Charles Hallam and Rosanna Hagen Hallam. Married to Clarina M. Bailey Hallam on January 21, 1841 in Fayetteville, Tennessee. Married to Martha P. Robinson Hallam on January 6, 1863. Father of Henry C. Hallam, Theodore Hallam, James R. Hallam, Jr., Orrin Hallam, and Frank Hallam. Read law at Nashville in 1836. Admitted to the bar in 1842. Delegate from Grant County to the Whig Party Convention of Kentucky in 1852. Assistant elector for the presidential election of 1852 in Kentucky&#39;s tenth congressional district. Attorney in Newport, Kentucky in 1860. Sent to Camp Chase in 1862. Commonwealth&#39;s attorney pro tempore from c1864 to 1865 in the Kenton Circuit Court. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedule, Kentucky, Owen County, District 1, p. 49.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedule, Kentucky, Campbell County, Newport, p. 103.<lb/>
&quot;Whig State Convention,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Louisville Daily Courier</hi>, February 26, 1852, p. 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The Louisville Daily Courier</hi>, October 15, 1861, p. 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Tennessee State Marriages, 1780-2002</hi>. Nashville, TN: Tennessee State Library and Archives. Microfilm.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), p. 460.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Judge James Russell Hallam (October 16, 1818-February 15, 1895),&quot; Memorial #33728805, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/33728805/j-hall (accessed May 22, 2017).<lb/>
KYR-0001-004-1393.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
