<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00016308">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert William Henry </title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Rachael Nicholas</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00016308">
                    <persName>
                      Robert William Henry 
                        (Christian County, Kentucky, farmer, justice of the peace, and 1st lieut &amp; maj 8th KY Mtd Inf (C.S.A.))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1825-06-06"  ><ab>1825-06-06</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1862-02-28"  ><ab>1862-02-28</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Christian County, Kentucky, farmer, justice of the peace, and soldier. Kentucky native. Son of William Henry, Jr., and Cornelia V. Gano Henry. Married to Martha Douglas Cocke Henry on November 16, 1847. Father of Martha &quot;Patty&quot; Douglas Henry. Married to Fannie S. Bell Henry in Christian County, Kentucky, on January 26, 1854. Father of Margaret Henry and William Henry. Farmer in Christian County in 1850. Owned fifteen enslaved persons in Christian County in 1850. Farmer in Christian County in 1860. Owned twelve enslaved persons in Christian County in 1860. Justice of the peace in Christian County in 1861. Served in the 8th Kentucky Mounted Infantry (C.S.A.) as first lieutenant and major from September 26, 1861, to February 28, 1862. Captured at Fort Donelson. Prisoner of war at Camp Morton, Indiana, until February 28, 1862. Died at Camp Morton from congestion of the brain on February 28, 1862. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, District 1, p. 435B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, District 1, p. 9.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, Hopkinsville, p. 789-90.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, Hopkinsville, p. 276B.<lb/>
&quot;Col Robert William Henry (1825-1862),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #36189446, accessed November 7, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/36189446.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Confederate Soldiers who Served in Organizations from the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M319, Roll 0066.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Christian County Marriages, Film #000465562, p. 248.<lb/>
&quot;Major R. W. Henry,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Courier-Journal</hi> (KY), March 4, 1862, Newspapers.com, https://www.newspapers.com/clip/88549069/obituary-for-r-w-henry/.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Sons of the American Revolution Membership Applications, 1889-1970</hi>, National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, Louisville, Ky, National #73416, State #391.<lb/>
KYR-0001-031-0081.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
