<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007499">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thomas S. Bronston, Jr.</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>James N. McAllister</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007499">
                    <persName>
                      Thomas S. Bronston, Jr.
                        (Madison County, KY, merchant)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1817"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1817</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1890-12-17"  ><ab>1890-12-17</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Richmond, Madison County, Kentucky, merchant. Kentucky native. Married Sally Ann Bronston in Madison County in June 1846. Father of Charles Bronston. Married Elizabeth Ballard Bronston in Madison County on December 24, 1850. Father of Thomas B. Bronston. Married Henrietta Bronston. Father of Joseph S. Bronston, Mattie Bronston, Nettie Bronston, Elen Bronston, Bettie Bronston, and Nannie Bronston. Merchant in Madison County in 1850. Merchant in Madison County in 1860. Enslaved eight persons in Madison County in 1860. Imprisoned at Camp Chase, Ohio in June 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, District 1, p. 203B.  

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Richmond, p. 139. 

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Richmond, p. 473A-B. 

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Richmond, p. 254B.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Madison County Marriages, Film #000183314, p. 977.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Madison County Marriages, Film #000183302, p. 282.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, X County Marriages, Film #, p.

<hi rend="italic">Selected Records of the War Department Relating to Confederate Prisoners of War, 1861-1865</hi> (National Archives Microfilm Publication M598, 145 rolls); War Department Collection of Confederate Records, Record Group 109; National Archives, Washington, D.C., p. 82 (22459 of 54896 of microfilm). 

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Thomas S. Bronston (1817-1890),&quot; Memorial #59093283, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/59093283 (accessed March 19, 2020).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
