<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00017740">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John T. Maphet</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Abigail Stephens</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Abigail Stephens</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00017740">
                    <persName>
                      John T. Maphet
                        (Newport, Kentucky, clerk and insurance agent.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1822"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1822</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Campbell County, Kentucky, clerk and insurance agent. Newport, Kentucky, native. Married to Emily Shattuch Maphet. Father of Josephine Maphet, John Maphet, William H. Maphet, Douglass Maphet, and Anna Maphet. Carpenter in Newport, Kentucky, in 1850. Insurance agent in Newport in 1860. Unsuccessful applicant for the post of paymaster of Newport in 1862. Clerk in Newport in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Campbell County, Newport, p. 130A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Campbell County, Newport, p. 227.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Campbell County, Newport, p. 462B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Arkansas Death Certificates, 1914-1969</hi>, Arkansas Department of Vital Records, Little Rock, Arkansa, Vol. #019-038.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Campbell County, KY, June and July 1863, p. 160.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Letters Received by the Commission Branch of the Adjutant General’s Office, 1863-1870</hi>, NARA RG 94, Kentucky, Microfilm Series M1095, p. 2.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
