<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00015096">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Owen Ross Baker</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hailey Brangers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00015096">
                    <persName>
                      Owen Ross Baker
                        (Caldwell County, Kentucky, farmer.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1831-05-23"  ><ab>1831-05-23</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1894-04"  ><ab>1894-04</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Caldwell County, Kentucky, farmer. Kentucky native. Son of John Baker and Mary Baker. Married to Julia F. Lindsay Baker in Christian County, Kentucky, on November 17, 1853. Father of Franklin Baker, Cora Baker, Eugenia Baker, Peter R. Baker, John M. Baker, and Gertrude Baker. Attended Georgetown College in Georgetown, Kentucky, in 1848. Farmer in Caldwell County, Kentucky, in 1850. Household owned nine enslaved persons in Caldwell County in 1850. Farmer in Burnesville in 1860. Employed Alonzo Beardin as a farm laborer in Burnesville in 1860. Owned two enslaved persons in Burnesville in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, District 2, p. 377A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, District 2, p. 799.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Burnesville, p. 20.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Burnesville, p. 208B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Tenth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1880), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Princeton, 159, p. 459B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Christian County Marriages, Film #001942963, p. 242.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Catalogue of the Officers and Students of Georgetown College for the Year 1848-49</hi> (Cincinnati: E. Shepard, 1849), 5. <lb/>
&quot;Owen Ross Baker (1831-1894),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #180754281, accessed July 20, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/180754281.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
