<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006413">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Elisha Logan Cockrell</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006413">
                    <persName>
                      Elisha Logan Cockrell
                        (Estill County, Kentucky, farmer and county judge)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1822-12-04"  ><ab>1822-12-04</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1876-11-02"  ><ab>1876-11-02</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Estill County, Kentucky, farmer and county judge. Breathitt County, Kentucky, native. Son of Simon Cockrill and Mary Smith Cockrill. Married to Rebecca A. McMonigal Cockrill on July 1, 1845. Father of Mary P. Cockrill, Belle F. Cockrill, Madison Cockrill, and Amanda Cockrill. Legislator in the Kentucky House of Representatives from 1847 to 1848. Farmer in Estill County in 1860. Judge of Estill County Court in Estill County from c1848 to 1866.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Estill County, p. 90. <hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865 (Civil War Union Draft Records), Estill County, KY, July 1863, p. 27, (Accessed via ancestry.com).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Journal of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, Begun and Held in the Town of Frankfort, on Friday the Thirty First Day of December, in the Year of our Lord, 1847, and of the Commonwealth, the Fifty Sixth</hi> (Frankfort, KY: A. G. Hodges, 1847), p. 4. W. H. Perrin, J. H. Battle, and G. C. Kniffin, <hi rend="italic">Kentucky: A History of the State</hi>, 8th ed. (Louisville and Chicago: F. A. Battey and Company, 1888), 774. <hi rend="italic">Kentucky Vital Statistics Original Death Certificates (1911-1955)</hi>, Ancestry, 1914, Rockcastle County, file no. 5452. <hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, “Elisha Logan Cockrell (December 4, 1822-November 2, 1876),” Memorial #165885580, http://findagrave.com/memorial/165885580 (accessed February 26, 2018).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
