<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00014190">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Reddick Nichols</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Rachael Nicholas</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Rachael Nicholas</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00014190">
                    <persName>
                      Reddick Nichols
                        (Caldwell County, Kentucky, farmer and)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1824"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1824</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Caldwell County, Kentucky, farmer and soldier. Kentucky native. Son of Eli Nichols, Sr. Married to Elizabeth J. Blanks Nichols in Caldwell County, Kentucky, in December 1852. Father of Angeline Nichols, Mildred A. Nichols, and Joana Nichols. Farmer in Caldwell County in 1850. Served in the 10th Kentucky (Johnson&#39;s) Cavalry Regiment (C.S.A.) as private from June 29, 1862, to August 1, 1862. Served in Captain Byrne&#39;s Company, Kentucky Horse Artillery (C.S.A.) as private from August 1, 1862, to June 6, 1863. Reported as deserted and captured at Glasgow, Kentucky, on June 6, 1863. Prisoner of war at Camp Chase, Ohio, and Fort Delaware, Delaware, from July 8, 1863, to February 10, 1864, when he was transferred to Kentucky to stand trial on a charge of robbery in Crittenden County. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, District 2, p. 355B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Tennessee, p. 523A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Confederate Soldiers who Served in Organizations from the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M319, Roll 0066.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Caldwell County Marriages, Film #000546372, p. 28.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
