<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00016868">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Henderson Guthrie</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00016868">
                    <persName>
                      Thomas Henderson Guthrie
                        (Marion County, Kentucky, student, farmer, and merchant)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1832-11-27"  ><ab>1832-11-27</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1917-10-14"  ><ab>1917-10-14</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Marion County, Kentucky, student, farmer, and merchant. Boyle County, Kentucky, native. Son of William Guthrie and Chinese Thorpe Guthrie. Married to Elizabeth J. &quot;Lizzie&quot; Biggens Guthrie in Marion County, Kentucky, on November 3, 1857. Father of Lydia Guthrie and Mary W. Guthrie. Student and farmer in Boyle County, Kentucky, in 1850. Household owned two enslaved persons in Boyle County in 1850. Farmer in Marion County in 1860. Owned one enslaved person in Marion County in 1860. Merchant in Daviess County in 1863. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Boyle County, District 1, p. 327 A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Boyle County, District 1, p. 336.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Marion County, District 2, p. 653.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Marion County, District 2, p. 490 B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Daviess County, Owensboro, Ward 2, p. 287 B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll #994047, Marion County Marriages.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, File #27199.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Daviess County, KY, July 1863, p. 311.<lb/>
&quot;Schools to Close for the Funeral of T.H. Guthrie.&quot; <hi rend="italic">Owensboro Messenger.</hi> (Owensboro, KY.) Oct. 16, 1917. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
