<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00013869">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Edward Richard Sprigg Canby</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>AaronMPhillips</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Hailey Brangers</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00013869">
                    <persName>
                      Edward Richard Sprigg Canby
                        (U.S. Army brigadier general)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1817-11-09"  ><ab>1817-11-09</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1873-04-11"  ><ab>1873-04-11</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>U.S. Army brigadier general. Kentucky native. Married to Louisa Hawkins Canby. Father of Mary Paul Canby. Graduated from the U.S. Military Academy at West Point, New York, in 1839. Served as quartermaster and commissary of subsistence in the Florida war from October 1839 to 1842. Breveted as major and lieutenant colonel during the Mexican-American War. U.S. Army officer in Monterey County, California, in 1850. Employed John Hammell as a servant in Monterey County in 1850. Promoted to major of the 10th U.S. Infantry in 1855. Commanding officer at Fort Crittenden, Utah, and Fort Defiance, New Mexico, in 1860. Appointed colonel of the 19th U.S. Infantry and commanding officer of the Department of New Mexico on May 14, 1861. Served as brigadier general of U.S. Volunteers from May 31, 1862, to May 7, 1864. Promoted to major general of U.S. Volunteers and served as commander of the Military Division of West Mississippi from May 7, 1864, to May 17, 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, California, Monterey County, Monterey, p. 106A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Returns from U.S. Military Posts, 1800-1916</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M617, Utah, Fort Crittenden, 1857 Jan - 1861 May, p. 84 of microfilm (accessed via Ancestry.com on December 21, 2020).<lb/>
Ezra J. Warner, Jr., <hi rend="italic">Generals in Blue: Lives of the Union Commanders</hi> (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1964), 67-8.<lb/>
John H. Eicher &amp; David J. Eicher, eds., <hi rend="italic">Civil War High Commands</hi> (Stanford: Stanford University Press, 2001), 161-62.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Edward Richard Sprigg Canby (1817-1873),&quot; Memorial #5888328, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/5888328 (accessed December 21, 2020).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
