<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003959">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Jeremiah W. South</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003959">
                    <persName>
                      Jeremiah W. South
                        (Franklin County, Kentucky, farmer and keeper of the State Penitentiary)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1805-07-10"  ><ab>1805-07-10</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1880-04-15"  ><ab>1880-04-15</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Franklin County, Kentucky, farmer and keeper of the state penitentiary. Kentucky native. Married to Mary M. South. Father of Eliza South, Ellen South, Samuel South, John South, Martin Van Buren South, Celia South, William T. B. South, James K. Polk South, Patsy South, Lewis Cass South, Moore South, Thomas I. South, Spicey South, and Narcissa South. Member of the Disciples of Christ. Justice of the peace in Breathitt County, Kentucky. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky for Breathitt County in 1840. Member of the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky for Breathitt County from 1843 to 1847. Farmer in Breathitt County in 1850. Charter stockholder of the Lexington and Kentucky Railroad Company. Owned ten enslaved persons in Breathitt County in 1860. Keeper of the State Penitentiary of the Commonwealth of Kentucky in Frankfort, Kentucky, from 1859 to 1863. Owned sixteen enslaved persons in Frankfort in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Breathitt County, District No. 1, p. 33A. 

<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Breathitt County, District No. 1, p. 31. 

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, District No. 1, p. 116. 

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, District No. 1, p. 26. 

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Forks of Elkhorn District, p. 23. 

William C. Sneed, <hi rend="italic">A Report on the History and Mode of Management of the Kentucky Penitentiary from its Origin, in 1798, to March 1, 1860</hi> (Frankfort: Senate of Kentucky, 1860), 553. 

<hi rend="italic">Report of the Special Committee on the Penitentiary to the Senate of Kentucky, February 26, 1880, Legislative Document No. 18</hi> (Frankfort: E. H. Porter, 1880). 

Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi> (Louisville: Richard H. Collins, 1877), 772. 

T. R. C. Hutton, <hi rend="italic">Bloody Breathitt: Politics and Violence in the Appalachian South</hi> (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 2013), 24-26, 76, 141. 

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Jeremiah Weldon &#39;Jere&#39; South (1805-1880),&quot; Memorial #7648523, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/7648523/jeremiah-weldon-south (accessed January 24, 2018).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
