<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00021296">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John B. Harris</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>A. J. Blaylock</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>A. J. Blaylock</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00021296">
                    <persName>
                      John B. Harris
                        ()
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1811"  ><ab>1811</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1874-04-03"  ><ab>1874-04-03</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Floyd County, Kentucky, farmer. Kentucky native. Married to Tabitha Graham Harris in Floyd County, Kentucky, on June 24, 1835. Father of Andrew Harris, Edwin Harris, William Jefferson Harris, Thomas Monroe Harris, James P. Harris, John Q. Harris, California Harris, Buenavista Harris, and Newton P. Harris. Farmer in Floyd County, Kentucky, in 1850. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Floyd County, My District, p. 418B-419A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Floyd County, Prestonburg, p. 6.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Floyd County, District 6, p. 581B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Sons of the American Revolution Membership Applications, 1889-1970</hi>, National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, Louisville, KY, National 90110, State 5387.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Floyd County Marriages, Film 007747400.<lb/>
KYR-0001-020-0499.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
