<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000812">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">George Helm Yeaman</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000812">
                    <persName>
                      George Helm Yeaman
                        (Daviess County, Kentucky, attorney, judge, and statesman)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1829-11-01"  ><ab>1829-11-01</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1908-02-23"  ><ab>1908-02-23</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Daviess County, Kentucky, attorney, judge, and statesman. Hardin County, Kentucky, native. Married to Lillia Pegram Triplett Yeaman in 1855. Father of Robert T. Yeaman, Stephen M. Yeaman, Lelia P. Yeaman, Jr., Virginia L. Yeaman Remnitz, and Anna H. Yeaman. Studied law and admitted to the bar in 1851. Practiced law in Owensboro, Kentucky. Daviess County Court judge from 1854 to 1858. Elected as a member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky in 1861. Unionist member of the 2nd Congressional District of Kentucky to the United States House of Representatives from December 1861 to March 1865. United States minister to Denmark from 1865 to 1870.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Daviess County, District No 1, p. 35-36.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Tenth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1880), Population Schedules, New York, New York County, New York City, p. 13.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</hi>, s.v. “George Helm Yeaman,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=Y000015) (accessed December 5, 2016).<lb/>
“George Helm Yeaman Dies in New York,” <hi rend="italic">The Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, Ky.), February 23, 1908.<lb/>
Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1 (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co., 1877), 153.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
