<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018238">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Amelia H. Clay</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Ian Iverson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018238">
                    <persName>
                      Amelia H. Clay
                        (Henderson County, Kentucky, resident.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1787"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1787</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="F"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Henderson County, Kentucky, resident. Virginia native. Married to Charles V. Clay. Resident of Henderson County, Kentucky, in 1860. Mother of Mary Ann Clay Dixon, Isabella P. Clay Dixon, and Henrietta P. Clay Ball. Resident of Henderson County, Kentucky, in 1840. Household owned nine enslaved persons in Henderson County in 1840. Resident of Henderson County in 1850. Owned two enslaved persons in Henderson County in 1850. Household owned an additional five enslaved persons in Henderson County in 1850. Resident of Henderson County in 1860. Household owned eight enslaved persons in Henderson County in 1860. Household owned eight enslaved persons in Henderson County in 1860. Owned Tom [Unknown] in Henderson County in December 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Sixth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1840), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, p. 249.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, District 2, p. 356B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, District 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, Division 1, p. 85.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, Division 1, p. 145A-B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky, Wills and Probate Records, 1774-1989</hi>, Kentucky County, District, and Probate Courts, Henderson County Wills, vol. A-C, 1799-1875, vol. C, pp. 39-40.<lb/>
KYR-0001-020-1155.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
