<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018462">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James William Finnie</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>MontanaWilliamson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Ian Iverson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018462">
                    <persName>
                      James William Finnie
                        (Union County, Kentucky, farmer, judge, soldier, and politician. )
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1808"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1808</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Union County, Kentucky, farmer, soldier, and politician. Kentucky native. Father of Sarah Attaway Finnie and Eliza Finnie. Trustee of Caseyville, Union County, Kentucky, in 1839. Farmer in Union County in 1850. Owned ten enslaved persons in Union County in 1850. County judge in Union County in 1851. Town commissioner in Caseyville, Union County, in 1858. Resident of Union County in 1860. Owned one enslaved person in Union County in 1860. Served  in the United States Army as a captain and assistant provost marshal for Kentucky&#39;s 1st Congressional District from 1863 to July 1865. Police judge of Caseyville, Union County, in 1865. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Union County in 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Union County, District 2, p. 515A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Union County, District 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky,Union County, Caseyville, p. 561.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Union County, Caseyville, p. 420A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Union County, Caseyville, p. 265B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky (1858)</hi>December 7 1857 - February 17, 1858, vol 2 (Frankfort: A.G. Hodges, 1858), 119.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Union County Marriages, Film #000562200.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Journal of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky (1839)</hi>, December 17, 1838 - February 23, 1839 (Frankfort: A.G. Hodges, 1839), 225.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Journal of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky (1866)</hi>, December 4, 1865 -  February 19, 1865 (Frankfort: George D. Prentice, 1866), 5, 150.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Letters Received by the Adjutant General&#39;s Office, 1861-1870</hi> NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M619, Roll 0369. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">History of Union County, Kentucky</hi>(Evansville, IN: Courier Company, 1886), 83. <lb/>
James E. Jacobsen<hi rend="italic">Illinois/Kentucky Ohio River Civil War Heritage Trail Historic Corridor Survey</hi>(Report of the Illinois Historic Preservation Agency and the Kentucky Heritage Council, 1998), 346, 398, 411-412
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
