<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00009817">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Archibald W. Kavanaugh</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00009817">
                    <persName>
                      Archibald W. Kavanaugh
                        (Madison County, farmer and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1828-12-16"  ><ab>1828-12-16</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1911-03-29"  ><ab>1911-03-29</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Madison County, Kentucky, farmer and soldier. Madison County native. Son of Charles Kavanaugh and Margaret Kavanaugh. Married to Sarah &quot;Sallie&quot; W. Maupin Kavanaugh on January 3, 1860. Father of Nancie Kavanaugh. Farmer in Madison County in 1850. Household owned seven enslaved persons in Madison County in 1850. Farmer in Madison County in 1860. Household owned twenty-seven enslaved persons in Madison County in 1860. Household employed Henry Coldiron as farm laborer in 1860. Served in the 11th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry Regiment (C.S.A.) as private from July 22, 1862, to November 18, 1864. Captured near Buffington Island, Ohio, on July 19, 1863. Prisoner of war at Camp Morton, Indianapolis, Indiana on July 23, 1863. Prisoner of war at Camp Douglas, Illinois, from August 22, 1863, to November 18, 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, District 2, p. 270A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, District 2, p. 10.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Division 1, p. 340.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Division 1, p. 443, p. 13 of microfilm.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Richmond, p. 232A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Marriage Records: Kentucky Marriages</hi>, (Richmond, KY: Madison County Courthouse), film no. 000183302, p. 197.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Confederate Soldiers who Served in Organizations from the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M319, Roll 60.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Archibald Woods Kavanaugh (1828-1911),&quot; Memorial #22643846, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/22643846# (accessed December 10, 2018).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
