<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011407">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Hardy S. Sypert</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011407">
                    <persName>
                      Hardy S. Sypert
                        (Christian County, KY, merchant, postmaster, and prov govt conv rep)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1802"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1802</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Christian County, Kentucky, merchant and postmaster. Tennessee native. Married to Ann C. Sypert. Father of Stephen G. Sypert, Hannibal Sypert, Leonidas A. Sypert, Henrietta Sypert, Sally Sypert, Demetrius F. Sypert, and Teresa N. Sypert. Postmaster of LaFayette, Christian County, from April 29, 1847, to October 1, 1853. Merchant in Christian County in 1850. Owned three enslaved persons in Christian County in 1850. Postmaster of LaFayette from November 5, 1853, to December 23, 1856. Postmaster of LaFayette from December 30, 1857, to May 20, 1862. Merchant in Christian County in 1860. Owned three enslaved persons in Christian County in 1860. Member of the convention of the provisional government held at Russellville in November 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, District 1, p. 432B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, District 1, p. 6 of 41 on microfilm (accessed via Ancestry.com).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, p. 767-8.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, p. 307A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Record of Appointment of Postmasters, 1832-1971.</hi> Records of the Post Office Department, NARA Series M841, RG 28, Christian County, Kentucky, Volume 14, p. 588-9.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Record of Appointment of Postmasters, 1832-1971.</hi> Records of the Post Office Department, NARA Series M841, RG 28, Christian County, Kentucky, Volume 14, p. Volume 28, p. 42. <lb/>
KYR-0004-033-0001.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
