<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00014444">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Dennison Jr. </title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00014444">
                    <persName>
                      William Dennison Jr. 
                        (Franklin County, Ohio, Governor of Ohio and Postmaster General)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1815-11-23"  ><ab>1815-11-23</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1882-06-15"  ><ab>1882-06-15</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Franklin County, Ohio, governor and postmaster general. Ohio native. Son of William Dennison, Sr. Married to Ann Eliza Seil Dennison in Franklin County, Ohio, on December 22, 1840. Father of William N. Dennison, Tallmadge Dennison, Elizabeth Dennison, Erasmus Dennison, Mary Dennison, Anna Dennison, Herman Dennison, Lucy G. Dennison, Mary Dennison, Jenny P. Dennison, and Allan N. Dennison. Graduated from Miami University in Oxford, Ohio, in 1835. State senator from Franklin County from 1848 to 1850. Attorney in Franklin County in 1850. Employed Mary Cassidy and Catherine O&#39;Brien as servants in 1850. Delegate to the Republican National Convention in 1856. Republican governor of Ohio from January 9, 1860, to January 13, 1862. Employed Lena Lohr, Mary Lohr, Mary Schart, Jane Poland, and Henry Johnson as servants in Franklin County in 1860. Delegate to the Republican National Convention in 1864. United States postmaster general from 1864 to 1866. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Ohio, Franklin County, Columbus Ward 2, p. 327A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Ohio, Franklin County, Columbus Ward 1, p. 16.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Ohio, Franklin County, Columbus Ward 1, p. 73A-73B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Appletons&#39; Cyclopædia of American Biography</hi>, vol. 2, eds. James Grant Wilson and John Fiske, (New York: D. Appleton and Company, 1888), 142.<lb/>
&quot;Gov. William Dennison,&quot; National Governors Association, accessed May 13, 2021, https://www.nga.org/governor/william-dennison/.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ohio Marriage Records</hi>, Franklin County Courthouse, Columbus, Ohio, Franklin County Marriages, Film #000285143, p. 31.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
