<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00012240">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thomas A. Ireland</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Carl Creason</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Carl Creason</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00012240">
                    <persName>
                      Thomas A. Ireland
                        (Owen County sheriff, court clerk, and CSA soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1827"  ><ab>1827</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1888"  ><ab>1888</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Owen County, Kentucky, sheriff, court clerk, and soldier. Kentucky native. Married to Susan M. Black Ireland in Owen County, Kentucky, on February 26, 1851. Father of Sallie B. Ireland. Sheriff in Owen County in 1856. Court clerk in Owen County in 1860. Served in the 1st Kentucky Cavalry (C.S.A.) as a captain from November 1862 to March 1863. Reported as deserted in the summer of 1863. Capitulated to federal authorities in the summer of 1863. Found guilty by court martial for violating loyalty oath. Prisoner of war at Louisville Military Prison in Jefferson County, Kentucky, from July 26, 1863 to January 14, 1864. Transferred to Camp Chase in Columbus, Franklin County, Ohio on January 14, 1864. Signed a loyalty oath to the U.S. government on October 12, 1864. Released from Camp Chase on October 12, 1864. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Owen County, District 1, p. 161.

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Owen County, Owenton, p. 282A.

<hi rend="italic">Tenth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1880), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Owen County, Owenton, p. 116D.

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Thomas A. Ireland (1827-1888),&quot; Memorial #16602621, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/16602621 (accessed March 13, 2020).

<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Confederate Soldiers who Served in Organizations from the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M319, Roll 0002.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Owen County Marriages, Film #000272769, p. 182.

<hi rend="italic">Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, Passed</hi> (Frankfort, KY: A. G. Hodges State Printer, 1856), 190. 

Ed Porter Thompson, <hi rend="italic">History of the Orphan Brigade</hi> (Louisville, KY: Lewis N. Thompson Printers, 1898), 1024, 1055.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
