<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006536">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">David Glass Venable</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Samuel T. Whittaker</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006536">
                    <persName>
                      David Glass Venable
                        (Frankfort, Kentucky, student and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1838"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1838</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1881-03-17"  ><ab>1881-03-17</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Franklin County, Kentucky, laborer, merchant, soldier, student, and agent of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. Shelby County, Kentucky, native. Son of John C. Venable and Margaret J. Venable. Married to Mary C. Reading Venable in Franklin County, Kentucky, on January 23, 1861. Father of Mittie S. Venable. Attended school in Shelby County in 1850. Household owned seven enslaved persons in Shelby County in 1850. Laborer in Shelby County in 1860. Household owned twelve enslaved persons in Shelby County in 1860. Merchant in Franklin County in 1861. Served in the 30th Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.) as first lieutenant and quarter master from August 11, 1862, to October 4, 1862. Student in Franklin County in 1863. Agent of the Commonwealth of Kentucky in the requisition of Alexander Burke in 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Shelby County, District 1, p. 289A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Shelby County, District 1.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Shelby County, District 2, p. 27.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Shelby County, District 2, p. 281A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, p. 98B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers Who Served in Organizations From the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0400.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Franklin County, KY, July 1863, p. 27.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994034, Franklin County Marriages.<lb/>
&quot;Denison: Prominent Citizen Accidentally Killed,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Galveston Daily News</hi> (Galveston, TX), March 18, 1881, p. 1.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
