<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011544">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Joseph B. Champion</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011544">
                    <persName>
                      Joseph B. Champion
                        (Livingston County, Kentucky, farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1812"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1812</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Livingston County, Kentucky, farmer. Kentucky native. Married to P. S. Pemberton Champion in Livingston County on April 2, 1838. Father of Robert C. Champion, Pinkiney Champion, Mary Champion, David Champion, and Joseph Champion. Farmer in Livingston County in 1850. Farmer in Livingston County in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Livingston County, Livingston County, p. 354B. 

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Livingston County, Division 1, p. 207.

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Livingston County, Diershill, p. 211B. 

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Livingston County Marriages, Film #000318176, p. 222 of 257 on microfilm (accessed via Ancestry.com)
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
