<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002275">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Andrew Galbraith Kyle</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Samuel T. Whittaker</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Samuel T. Whittaker</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002275">
                    <persName>
                      Andrew Galbraith Kyle
                        (Mercer County, Kentucky, farmer; president of Harrodsburg Savings Institution)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1796"  ><ab>1796</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1872"  ><ab>1872</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Mercer County, Kentucky, farmer and president of Harrodsburg Savings Institution. Washington County, Kentucky, native. Son of Thomas Kyle. Married to Jane H. Glover Kyle. Father of John G. Kyle and Thomas Kyle. Justice of the Peace in Mercer County, Kentucky in 1847. Chairman of meeting of the Friends of Emancipation and Colonization in Mercer County in April 1849. Farmer in Mercer County in 1850. Commissioner of the Harrodsburg Savings Institution in 1850. Owned fourteen enslaved persons in Mercer County in 1850. Commissioner of Lexington, Harrodsburg, and Bowling Green Railroad Company in 1851. Farmer in Mercer County in 1860. Owned eighteen enslaved persons in Mercer County in 1860. President of the Harrodsburg Savings Institution in 1864. Colonel in the state militia. Member of the board of curators of Kentucky University in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, District No. 2, p. 347A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, District No. 2, pp. 907-8.<lb/>
 <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, Harrodsburg, p. 715.<lb/>
 <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, Harrodsburg, pp. 49A-B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, Harrodsburg, p. 583B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Andrew Galbraith Kyle (1796-1872),&quot; Memorial 100136706,<lb/>
https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/100136706  (accessed December 23, 2019).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Mercer, Will Books, 1865, 1916</hi>, Mercer County, October 19, 1871, p. 127 (Accessed via Ancestry.com).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Vital Statistics Original Death Certificates – Microfilm (1911-1964)</hi>, KDLA, Roll #7016150, Mercer County Deaths, File #2448.<lb/>
Taliaferro P. Shaffner, ed., <hi rend="italic">The Kentucky State Register, for the Year 1847</hi> (Louisville: Morton &amp; Griswold, 1847), 132.<lb/>
&quot;Public Meeting in Mercer,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Louisville Daily Courier</hi> (Louisville, Ky.), April 19, 1849, p. 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky: Passed at December Session 1849</hi> (Frankfort: A. G. Hodges &amp; Co., State Printers, 1850), 623-24.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky: Passed at the November Session, 1850</hi>, vol. 2 (Frankfort: A. G. Hodges &amp; Co., State Printers, 1850), 561.<lb/>
Thomas W. Westerfield, ed., <hi rend="italic">Kentucky Genealogy and Biography: Sketches from Adair, Boyle, Casey, Cumberland, Garrard, Green, Lincoln, Madison, Marion, Mercer, Nelson, Taylor, Washington Counties</hi>, vol. 5 (Owensboro, Ky.: Genealogical Reference Company, 1975), p. 173. Reprint of W. H. Perrin, J. H. Battle, and G. C. Kniffin, <hi rend="italic">Kentucky: A History of the State</hi>, 4th ed.<lb/>
KYR-0001-009-0038.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
