<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00009779">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John E. Newman</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Emily D. Moses</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Emily D. Moses</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00009779">
                    <persName>
                      John E. Newman
                        (Bardstown, Nelson County, attorney and judge)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1819"  ><ab>1819</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1873-04-02"  ><ab>1873-04-02</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Nelson County, Kentucky, attorney and judge. Spencer County, Kentucky native. Son of Thomas Newman and Susan Prewitt Newman. Married to Marion Olin Newman in Livingston County on May 22, 1847. Father of Susan Newman, Thomas Newman, Richard Newman, William Newman, Mary Newman, and John Newman. Studied law under Martin McHenry in Taylorsville, Kentucky. Began legal practice in Spencer County in 1842. Attorney in Nelson County in 1850. Owned one enslaved person in Nelson County in 1850. Attorney in Nelson County in 1860. Owned two enslaved persons in Nelson County in 1860. Judge of Nelson Circuit Court from 1862 to 1868.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 2, p. 386A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 2, p. 237. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 1, p. 175.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 1, p.110B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville p. 199A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Livingston County Marriages, Film #000318176, p. 193.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Birth and Death Records: Covington, Lexington, Louisville, and Newport – Microfilm (before 1911)</hi>, KDLA, Film 7007126: Louisville, Books 1-4, p. 480 of microfilm.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Judge John E. Newman (1819-1873),&quot; Memorial 133570536, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/133570536/john-e<hi rend="italic">-newman  (accessed April 14, 2020).<lb/>
H. Levin, _The Lawyers and Lawmakers of Kentucky</hi> (Chicago: The Lewis Publishing Company, 1897), 770-71.<lb/>
Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1 (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co., 1874), 246.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
