<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000241">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William R. Kinney</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000241">
                    <persName>
                      William R. Kinney
                        (Henderson County, Kentucky, attorney, soldier, and politician)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1835"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1835</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Henderson County, Kentucky, attorney, soldier, and politician. Kentucky native. Son of john Kinney and Maria M. Kinney. Married to Fannie Allen Kinney in Grayson County, Kentucky, in 1856. Father of Willis J. Kinney and William A. Kinney. Law student in Ohio County, Kentucky, in 1850. Attorney in Henderson County in 1860. Major in the 12th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry Regiment from  November 1862 to February 1863.  Resigned on February 21, 1863. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Henderson County from 1863 to 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Ohio County, District 1, p. 48A. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, Division 1, p. 3. Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records – Microfilm (1852-1910), Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives, Frankfort, Kentucky, Roll #994036, Grayson County Marriages, p. 6. <hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0118. &quot;Stories of Dixon and His Times,&quot; Courier-Journal (Louisville, Ky.), December 8, 1895, p. A8. Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol I. (Covington, Ky.: Collins &amp; Co, 1877), 335.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
