<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00014404">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Anthony Joseph Drexel </title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00014404">
                    <persName>
                      Anthony Joseph Drexel 
                        (Philadelphia County, Pennsylvania, banker and philanthropist)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1826-09-13"  ><ab>1826-09-13</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1893-06-30"  ><ab>1893-06-30</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Philadelphia County, Pennsylvania, banker and philanthropist. Pennsylvania native. Son of Francis Martin Drexel. Married to Ellen B. Roset Drexel in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, in 1850. Father to Emile Drexel, Francis Drexel., May Drexel, Sally Drexel, John Drexel, and Anthony Drexel, Jr. Senior partner in Drexel &amp; Co. investment firm. Exchange broker in Philadelphia in 1850. Employed Matilda Brown and Ellen Fee as domestic workers in Philadelphia in 1850. Banker in Philadelphia in 1860. Employed Margaret McCarty, Eliza Blake, Helen Murphy, Ann Mullen, and Charles Brent as servants in Philadelphia in 1860. Co-owner, with George W. Childs, of the <hi rend="italic">Philadelphia Public Ledger</hi> in 1864. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Pennsylvania, Philadelphia County, Philadelphia South Mulberry Ward, p. 300B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Pennsylvania, Philadelphia County, Philadelphia Ward 24, Precinct 9, p. 1082-83.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Pennsylvania, Philadelphia County, Philadelphia Ward 27, District 89, p. 119B.<lb/>
Dan Rottenberg, <hi rend="italic">The Man Who Made Wall Street: Anthony J. Drexel and the Rise of Modern Finance</hi>, (University of Pennsylvania Press, 2006), 46.<lb/>
John L. Puckett, &quot;Anthony J. Drexel,&quot; West Philadelphia Collaborative History, https://collaborativehistory.gse.upenn.edu/stories/anthony-j-drexel (accessed May 6, 2021).<lb/>
&quot;Anthony Joseph Drexel,&quot; ed. Amy Tikkanen, Encyclopedia Britannica, https://www.britannica.com/biography/Anthony-Joseph-Drexel (accessed May 6, 2021).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Pennsylvania and New Jersey, U.S., Church and Town Records, 1669-2013</hi>, Historic Pennsylvania Church and Town Records, Historic Society of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, p. 2549 of microfilm (accessed via Ancestry.com).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Anthony J. Drexel (1826-1893),&quot; Memorial #9204051, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/9204051 (accessed May 6, 2021).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
