<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000811">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Streshly Jackson</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James N. McAllister</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000811">
                    <persName>
                      James Streshly Jackson
                        (Hopkinsville, Kentucky attorney, soldier, and politician)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1823-09-27"  ><ab>1823-09-27</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1862-10-08"  ><ab>1862-10-08</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Hopkinsville, Kentucky attorney, soldier, and politician. Kentucky native. Married to Martha Buford Jackson. Father of David Jackson, James Berryman Jackson, Etta Jackson, and Juliet Jackson. Educated at Centre College. Graduated from Jefferson College in 1844. Graduated from Transylvania University in 1845 with a law degree and admitted to the bar. Practiced law in Greenupsburg, Kentucky, and Hopkinsville, Kentucky. Served in the 1st Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry Regiment  as a private and third lieutenant in the U.S.-Mexican War. Resigned on October 10, 1846, fearing a court martial as the result of a duel. Unionist member of the House of Representatives of the United States from the second Congressional District of Kentucky from March 1861 to December 1861. Resigned and joined the U.S. Army. Served in the 3rd Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry Regiment as colonel from December 1861 to July 1862. Promoted to brigadier general of U.S. Volunteers in July 1862. Killed at the Battle of Perryville on October 8, 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Greenup County, District No 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, Town of Hopkinsville, p. 35-36. <lb/>
“Jackson, James Streshly,” Biographical Directory of the United States Congress, accessed December 2, 2016, http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=J000019. <lb/>
William B. Allen, <hi rend="italic">A History of Kentucky, embracing Gleanings, Reminiscences, Antiquities, Natural Curiosities, Statistics, and Biographical Sketches...</hi> (Louisville, KY: Bradley &amp; Gilbert, Publishers, 1872).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
