<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00009709">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John L. Zeigler</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00009709">
                    <persName>
                      John L. Zeigler
                        (Wayne County, West Virginia, farmer and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1813"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1813</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Wayne County, West Virginia, farmer and soldier. Pennsylvania native. Married to Susan Zeigler. Father of Hiram C. Zeigler, William A. Zeigler, Elizabeth M. Zeigler, John H. Zeigler, Helen M. Zeigler, Joseph P. Zeigler, Caroline E. Zeigler, and Amanda H. Zeigler. Farmer in Wayne County, Virginia in 1850 and 1860. Served in the 5th West Virginia Volunteer Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.) as colonel from September 14, 1861 to April 14, 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Virginia, Wayne County, District 66, p. 232B.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Virginia, Wayne County, p. 22.

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Boyd County, Catlettsburg, p. 1.

<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of West Virginia</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M508, Roll 131.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
