<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00017394">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Alfred Wallace Rutherford Harris</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>MontanaWilliamson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00017394">
                    <persName>
                      Alfred Wallace Rutherford Harris
                        (Jefferson County, Kentucky, merchant and Louisville city assessor.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1804"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1804</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1880-08-13"  ><ab>1880-08-13</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Jefferson County, Kentucky, merchant and city assessor.  Mason County, Kentucky, native.  Son of Edward Harris and Elizabeth Campbell Harris. Married to Mary Jane Dorothy Johnson Harris in Jefferson County, Kentucky, on August 19,1826. Father of Josette Sophia Harris Moore, William M. Harris, Charles H. Harris, Alfred Wallace Harris, Henry William Harris, and John E. Harris. Married to Martha Buckman Harris in Jefferson County on July 26, 1849.  Married to Emily T. Day Harris in Jefferson County on June 4, 1861. Merchant in Louisville  in 1850. Louisville city assessor in Louisville from 1860 to 1873. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, District 1, p. 58A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, First Ward, p. 382.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, File #21081.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film #000482706.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film #005553516, p. 3.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film #000482709, p. 58.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Lineage Book of the Charter Members of the National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution</hi>, eds. Mary S. Lockwood and Susan Riviere Hetzel (Washington, D. C.: National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1891-1939) vol. 50: 1904, p. 489.<lb/>
&quot;Board of Aldermen,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY), April 22, 1861, p. 1.<lb/>
&quot;Board of Aldermen,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY), January 2, 1862, p. 1.<lb/>
&quot;Board of Aldermen,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY), January 7, 1864, p. 1.<lb/>
&quot;Notice,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY), May 11, 1867, p. 2.<lb/>
&quot;Assessor&#39;s Department&quot; &quot; <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY), April 17, 1868, p. 2.<lb/>
&quot;Another Reply to Dr. Graham&#39;s First Communication.&quot; <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY), December 2, 1873, p. 3.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
