<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00020566">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Joseph Wolf</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00020566">
                    <persName>
                      Joseph Wolf
                        (Louisville, Kentucky, tavernkeeper)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1805"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1805</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, tavernkeeper. Native of Baden. Married to Catherina Schmidt Wolf in Jefferson County, Kentucky, on May 20, 1837. Father of Malinda Wolf, Louisa Wolf, Julia Wolf, and Amelia Wolf. Tavernkeeper in Louisville, Kentucky, in 1850. Tavernkeeper in Louisville from 1858 through 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 2, p. 221B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 2, p. 66.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 5, p. 460B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film 000482706.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky, Wills and Probate Records, 1774-1989</hi>, Kentucky County, District, and Probate Courts, Jefferson County Wills, vol. 8-9, 1861-1879, p. 590.<lb/>
&quot;Official: Board of Common Council,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Louisville Daily Journal</hi>, (Louisville, KY), March 31, 1862, p. 4. <lb/>
&quot;Official: Board of Common Council,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Louisville Daily Journal</hi>, (Louisville, KY), March 31, 1863, p. 4.<lb/>
&quot;Official: Board of Common Council,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Louisville Daily Journal</hi>, (Louisville, KY), April 1, 1864, p. 4<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Louisville City Directory and Business Mirror for 1858-9,</hi> (Louisville: Hurd &amp; Burrows, 1859), 301. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Tanner’s Louisville Directory and Business Advertiser for 1861</hi> ed. Henry Tanner (Louisville: Directory Publication and Advertising Agency, 1861), 267.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Edwards&#39; Annual Director to the Inhabitants, Institutions, Incorporated Companies, Manufacturing Establishments, Business firms, Etc., Etc., in the City of Louisville, For 1865-6</hi> (Louisville: Edwards, Greenough &amp; Deved, 1866), 601.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
