<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00005324">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">David Rice Haggard</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00005324">
                    <persName>
                      David Rice Haggard
                        (Colonel 5th Ky Cavalry; Cumberland Co, KY, physician and farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1817"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1817</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1887-04-29"  ><ab>1887-04-29</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Cumberland County, Kentucky, physician, farmer, businessman, and soldier. Kentucky native. Married to Jane M. Haggard. Father of Ben Rice Haggard, Thomas P. Haggard, Henry B. Haggard, Mary B. Haggard, Clarence R. Haggard, and Irene S. Haggard. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1844 to 1847. Physician in Cumberland County in 1850. Owned five enslaved persons in 1850. Assistant marshal of the slave census of the Cumberland Division in 1850. Farmer and physician in Cumberland County in 1860. Owned seven enslaved persons in 1860. Colonel of the 5th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry Regiment (U.S.A.) from January 1862 to February 1863. President of the Indian Creek and Jack&#39;s Knob, Iron, Coal, Salt, Lead, Lumber, Oil, and Manufacturing Company in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Cumberland County, Cumberland Division, p. 345A. 

<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Cumberland County, Cumberland Division, p. 19 of microfilm. 

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Cumberland County, District No. 2, p. 581. 

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Cumberland County, District No. 2, p. 11 of microfilm. 

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Cumberland County, Burkesville, pp. 4A-4B.

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Col David Rice Haggard (1817-1887),&quot; 95439725, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/95439725  (accessed December 4, 2019).

Roger D. Hunt, <hi rend="italic">Colonels in Blue–Indiana, Kentucky and Tennessee: A Civil War Biographical Dictionary</hi> (Jefferson, NC: McFarland, 2014), 161-162. 

<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1 (Frankfort: John H. Harney, Public Printer, 1866), 108-109. 

&quot;An Act to incorporate the Indian Creek and Jack&#39;s Knob Iron, Coal, Salt, Lead, Lumber, and Oil Manufacturing Company,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</hi> (Frankfort, Ky.: George D. Prentice, State Printer, 1865), 78-80. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
