<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00012748">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Theron Edmund Hall</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kristen Bailey</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Kristen Bailey</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00012748">
                    <persName>
                      Theron Edmund Hall
                        (Worcester County, MA, manufacturer, Ass&#39;t QM &amp; superintendent of refugees in Camp Nelson)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1821-11-08"  ><ab>1821-11-08</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1880-08-04"  ><ab>1880-08-04</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Worcester County, Massachusetts, manufacturer and soldier. Massachusetts native. Son of Edmund Trobridge Hall and Abigail Slocomb Hall. Married to Jemima W. Mann Hall in Holden, Massachusetts, on May 8, 1844. Father of Mary E. Hall, Edmund B. Hall, and Abbie F. Hall. Manufacturer in Worcester County in 1860. Employed Ellen Marsh and Michal Morson as domestic servants in Worcester County in 1860. Served in the 21st Massachusetts Volunteer Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.) as lieutenant and adjutant in July 1861. Served in the U.S. Volunteer Quartermaster Department with the rank of captain in July 1862. Transferred to Camp Nelson, Kentucky, where he was appointed assistant quartermaster and superintendent of the large numbers of African-American refugees who traveled with enlisting African-American soldiers to Camp Nelson. Resigned his military commission on December 5, 1864, continuing his work with refugees until  August 16, 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Massachusetts, Worcester County, Holden, p. 616. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Daughters of the American Revolution, Lineage Book of the Charter Members of the DAR</hi>Volume 084, p. 307.<lb/>
Francis B Heitman, <hi rend="italic">Historical Register and Dictionary of the United States Army, from its Organization, September 29, 1789, to March 2, 1903</hi> vol. 1, pt. 2 (Washington, DC: Government Printing Office, 1903), 342.<lb/>
&quot;Holden,&quot; Massachusetts Civil War Monuments, accessed May 31, 2020, https://macivilwarmonuments.com/2018/12/21/holden/.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Letters Received by the Office of the Adjutant General, Main Series, 1861-1870</hi>, NARA RG 94, Publication M619, Roll #0106.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Massachusetts Compiled Birth, Marriage, and Death Records</hi>, Holden, p. 140.<lb/>
Richard Sears, <hi rend="italic">A Utopian Experiment in Kentucky: Integration and Social Equality at Berea, 1866-1904</hi> (Westport, CT: Greenwood Press, 1996).<lb/>
&quot;Theron E. Hall (1821-1880),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #134225877, accessed May 31,  2020), http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/134225877. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
