<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003867">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Winfrey B. McConnell</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003867">
                    <persName>
                      Winfrey B. McConnell
                        (Fulton County, Kentucky, farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1809"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1809</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Fulton County, Kentucky, farmer. Tennessee native. Married to Martha McConnell. Father of William McConnell, Caroline McConnell, Emeline McConnell, James McConnell, Robert McConnell, Mary McConnell, Samuel McConnell, Alice McConnell, Alvey McConnell, and Celina McConnell. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Fulton County from 1848 to 1849. Farmer in Fulton County in 1850. Farmer in Fulton County in 1860. Owned eight enslaved persons in Fulton County in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fulton County, p. 119B. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fulton County, p. 35. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Fulton County, p. 5. <hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fulton County, District No. 2, p. 30. Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, (Louisville: Richard H. Collins, 1877), 281.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
