<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00013897">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Middleton Hewett</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>AaronMPhillips</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Hailey Brangers</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00013897">
                    <persName>
                      John Middleton Hewett
                        (Jefferson County, Kentucky, photographer and U.S. Army captain)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1813-07-08"  ><ab>1813-07-08</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1904-06-07"  ><ab>1904-06-07</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Jefferson County, Kentucky, photographer and soldier. Kentucky native. Married to Ruth Potter Hewett in Jefferson County, Kentucky, on January 9, 1839. Father of Marian Hewett, Alfred B. Hewett, and Ellen Hewett. Daguerreotypist in Louisville, Kentucky, in 1850. Ambrotypist in Louisville in 1860. Served in the 1st Kentucky Light Artillery Regiment (U.S.A.) as a captain from October 8, 1861, to November 16, 1864. Captured at Murfreesboro, Tennessee, on July 13, 1862. Prisoner of war at Richmond, Virginia, on October 11, 1862. Paroled at Aiken&#39;s Landing, Virginia, on October 12, 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 3, p. 252B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, Ward 5, p. 151.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, Ward 8, p. 89A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film #000817878, p. 110.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0146.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">U.S. Civil War Pension Index: General Index to Pension Files, 1861-1934</hi>, NARA RG 15, Microfilm Series T288, Illinois, Application #435976, Certificate #467072.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Capt John Middleton Hewett (1813-1904),&quot; Memorial #15152625, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/15152625 (accessed January 10, 2021).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
