<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011184">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Garth M. Kimbrough</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011184">
                    <persName>
                      Garth M. Kimbrough
                        (Robertson County, Tennessee, farmer and provisional government convention member)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1820"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1820</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Robertson County, Tennessee, farmer and provisional government convention member. Kentucky native. Married to Meredith A.M. Terry Kimbrough. Father of Thomas R. Kimbrough, Rebecca S. Kimbrough, Underwood Kimbrough, L.F. Kimbrough, P.A. Kimbrough, and J.W. Kimbrough. Farmer in Todd County, Kentucky, in 1850. Owned thirteen enslaved persons in Todd County in 1850. Farmer in Robertson County, Tennessee, in 1860. Owned twenty-five enslaved persons in Robertson County, Tennessee in 1860. Member of the convention of the provisional government held at Russellville, Kentucky, in November 1861. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Todd County, p. 282B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Todd County, District 2, p. 197.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Tennessee, Robertson County, Western Division, p. 487.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Tennessee, Robertson County, Western District, p. 42B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Tennessee, Robertson County, 17th District, p. 215A.<lb/>
KYR-0004-033-0001.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
