<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00014199">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James E. Cantrell</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Hailey Brangers</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00014199">
                    <persName>
                      James E. Cantrell
                        (Caldwell County, Kentucky, farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1794"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1794</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1876"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1876</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Caldwell County, Kentucky, farmer. South Carolina native. Married to Hannah Wadlington Cantrell in Golconda, Illinois, on August 15, 1819. Father of Bradford Cantrell, Wade O. Cantrell, Mildred S. Cantrell Martin, Sarah Cantrell, and Oscar Cantrell. Served in Captain Samuel Henderson&#39;s Company of South Carolina Militia from January 22, 1814, to August 3, 1814. Farmer in Caldwell County, Kentucky, in 1850. Owned sixteen enslaved persons in Caldwell County in 1850. Farmer in Caldwell County in 1860. Employed William Mason as an overseer in Caldwell County in 1860. Employed Mrs. P. Reynolds and Mary Reynolds as domestics in Caldwell County in 1860. Owned twenty-nine enslaved persons in Caldwell County in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, District 2, p. 349B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, District 2, p. 775.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Princeton, p. 63.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Princeton, p. 221B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Harmony, p. 463A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">U.S., War of 1812 Pension Application Files Index, 1812-1815</hi>, NARA RG 15, Microfilm Series M313.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, File #3553.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky, Wills and Probate Records, 1774-1989</hi>, Kentucky County, District, and Probate Courts, Caldwell County Administrators Bonds, 1830-1869, p. 473.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
