<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00017738">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Greenup Remington</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Matthew Roberts</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Ian Iverson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Matthew Roberts</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00017738">
                    <persName>
                      Greenup Remington
                        (Harrison County, Kentucky, carpenter)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1804-10-11"  ><ab>1804-10-11</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1891-10-03"  ><ab>1891-10-03</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Harrison County, Kentucky, carpenter. Kentucky native. Married to Sarah Hamilton Remington in Harrison County, Kentucky on February 9, 1826. Father of Louise Remington, Benjamin F. Remington, Elizabeth H. Remington, and Caroline S. Remington. Married to Elizabeth A. Remington. Father of Mary A. Remington, Sarah Remington, Eliza Remington, James A. Remington, and Greenup Remington. Resident of Harrison County in 1830. Owned one enslaved person in Harrison County in 1830. Resident of Harrison County in 1840. Owned two enslaved persons in Harrison County in 1840. Carpenter in Harrison County in 1850. Owned two enslaved persons in Harrison County in 1850. Resident of Harrison County in 1860. Owned four enslaved persons in Harrison County in 1860. Household owned an additional ten enslaved persons in Harrison County in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Fifth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi>(1830), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, Cynthiana, p. 166.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Sixth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi>(1840), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, Cynthiana, p. 147.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, District 1, p. 60A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi>(1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, District 1.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, Cynthiana, p. 584.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi>(1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, Cynthiana, p. 123A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, Cynthiana, p. 170A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, File #31312.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Harrison County Marriages, Film #000216892.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Nicholas County Marriages, Film #000252407. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky, Wills and Probate Records, 1774-1989</hi>, Kentucky County, District, and Probate Courts, Harrison County Wills, vol. L-O, 1882-1942, p. 469-471.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Lineage Book of the Charter Members of the National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution</hi>, eds. Mary S. Lockwood and Susan Riviere Hetzel (Washington, D. C.: National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1891-1939) vol. XVI: 1896, p. 215.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Sons of the American Revolution Membership Applications, 1889-1970</hi>, National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, Louisville, Ky, National #88262, State #1304.<lb/>
&quot;Greenup Remington (1804-1891),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #43077482, accessed June 20, 2022, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/43077482.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
