<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018683">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Alpheus Washington Bascom</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018683">
                    <persName>
                      Alpheus Washington Bascom
                        (Bath County, Kentucky, student, clerk, private and first lieutenant (C.S.A.))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1840-05-16"  ><ab>1840-05-16</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1912-02-22"  ><ab>1912-02-22</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Bath County, Kentucky, student, clerk, and soldier. Kentucky native. Son of Sylvanus Clark Bascom and Mary Nicholas Owings Bascom. Married to Nancy Jane Dawson Bascom in Bath County, Kentucky, on April 15, 1863. Father of William J. Bascom and Mary N. Bascom. Student in Bath County, Kentucky, in 1850. Household owned one enslaved person in Bath County in 1850. Clerk in Lafayette County, Missouri, in 1860. Household owned one enslaved person in Lafayette County in 1860. Served in the 5th Kentucky Mounted Infantry (C.S.A.) as private and first lieutenant from October 21, 1861 to November 29, 1862. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bath County, District 2, p. 16A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Bath County, District 2, p. 302.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Missouri, Lafayette County, Lexington, p. 591.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Missouri, Lafayette County, Lexington, p. 426B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bath County, Owingsville, p. 58 A-B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994028, Bath County Marriages, p. 137.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky: Confederate Kentucky Volunteers War 1861-65</hi>, vol. 1 (Frankfort: Legislature of Kentucky, 1915), p. 260-261.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Confederate Soldiers Who Served in Organizations from the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M319, Roll 0106.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Lineage Book of the Charter Members of the National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution</hi>, eds. Mary S. Lockwood and Susan Riviere Hetzel (Washington, D. C.: National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1891-1939) vol. 150: 1919, p. 119.<lb/>
&quot;Alpheus Washington Bascom (1840-1912),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 44098858, accessed September 27, 2022, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/44098858.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
