<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008538">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">George Robertson</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Brianna Kirk</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008538">
                    <persName>
                      George Robertson
                        (Fayette County, Kentucky, congressman and attorney)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1790-11-18"  ><ab>1790-11-18</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1874-05-16"  ><ab>1874-05-16</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Fayette County, Kentucky, congressman and attorney. Mercer County, Kentucky native. Son of Alexander Robertson and Margaret Robertson. Married to Eleanor Bainbridge Robertson in Garrard, Kentucky on November 28, 1809. Father of Alexander Robertson, James Robertson, and George Robertson. Admitted to the bar in 1809. Served in the United States House of Representatives from 1817 to 1821. Served in the Kentucky House of Representatives from 1822 to 1827, 1848, 1851, and 1852.  Speaker of the Kentucky House of Representatives in 1823, 1825 through 1827, and 1851 and 1852. Served as Secretary of State for Kentucky in 1828. Served as Chief Justice of the Kentucky Court of Appeals from 1829 to 1843. Law professor at the Transylvania University from 1834 to 1857. Attorney in Lexington, Kentucky in 1860. Served as justice of the court of appeals for the second district of Kentucky from 1864 to 1871.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette, District 2, p. 210A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette, Lexington, p. 550.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, X County Marriages, Film #000183256, p. 92.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Appleton&#39;s Cyclopaedia of American Biography, Volume V</hi>, ed. James Grant Wilson, John Fiske (New York: D. Appleton and Company, 1888): 277, 278.   
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
