<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00015448">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John McLean, Jr.</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hailey Brangers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00015448">
                    <persName>
                      John McLean, Jr.
                        (Covington, clerk for the US circuit and district court )
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1815"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1815</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Jefferson County and Kenton County, Kentucky, manufacturer and clerk for the U. S. Court. Ohio native. Married to Mildred Jane Taylor McLean in Jefferson County, Kentucky, on December 1, 1835. Father of Hancock McLean, John McLean, and Nathaniel McLean. Manufacturer in Jefferson County in 1850. Employed W. Mitchell as a merchant in Jefferson County in 1850. Clerk for the U. S. Court in Covington in 1860. Employed Fanny Harvey and Mary DeVinney as servants in Covington in 1860. Clerk for the U. S. Circuit and District Court in Covington in 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, District 1, p. 219A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, Covington Ward 4, p. 701-02.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film #000482706, p. 166.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Williams&#39; Cincinnati Directory for 1862</hi> (Cincinnati: Williams &amp; Co., 1862), 224.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
