<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00017281">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Beverly D. Williams</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00017281">
                    <persName>
                      Beverly D. Williams
                        (Boyle County, Kentucky, sheriff, pioneer, attorney, politician, and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1822"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1822</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1907-02-22"  ><ab>1907-02-22</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Boyle County, Kentucky, sheriff, explorer, attorney, politician, and soldier. Boyle County, Kentucky, native. Married to Narcissa B. McHill Williams in Mercer County, Kentucky, in December 1840. Father of Parthernia B. Williams, Harriet D. Williams, Hammond O. Williams, and S. Emily Williams. Sheriff in Boyle County in 1850. Owned four enslaved persons in Boyle County in 1850. Led the Pike&#39;s Peak Expedition from Leavenworth, Kansas Territory, to Denver, Colorado Territory, in 1859. Attorney in Boyle County in 1860. Elected as the United States Congressional delegate for the Jefferson Territory in Denver, Colorado Territory, in 1860. Served in the 4th Kentucky Mounted Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.) as first lieutenant from 1862 to 1863. Served as captain and aide de camp of United States Volunteers from 1863 to 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Boyle County, District 2, p. 383B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Boyle County, District 2, p. 627.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Boyle County, p. 885.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0192.<lb/>
&quot;Crossed Plains in First Stage Coach,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Daily Capital</hi> (Topeka, KS), March 31, 1907.<lb/>
&quot;Election in Jefferson Territory,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Daily Courier, (Louisville, KY), Oct. 17, 1859.<lb/>
Francis Ramaley, ed. _University of Colorado Studies,</hi> vol. 4, no. 1 (Boulder: University of Colorado, 1907), 71. <lb/>
Frederic L. Paxson, &quot;The Territory of Colorado,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The American Historical Review,</hi> 12, no. 1 (Oct. 1906): 59-61.<lb/>
&quot;Jefferson Territory,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Daily Courier,</hi> (Louisville, KY), Nov. 16, 1859. <lb/>
&quot;Jefferson Territory,&quot; Encyclopedia Britannica, accessed January 31, 2022,<lb/>
https://www.encyclopedia.com/reference/encyclopedias-almanacs-transcripts-and-maps/jefferson-territory.<lb/>
Jerome Constant Smiley, <hi rend="italic">Semi-Centennial History of the State of Colorado,</hi> vol. 1, no. 4  (Madison: University of Wisconsin, 1913), 299. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Mercer County Marriages, Film #000191857.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Letters Received by the Commission Branch of the Adjutant General&#39;s Office, 1863-1870,</hi> NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M1064, Roll 0067.<lb/>
&quot;Pike&#39;s Peak Gold Region,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Louisville Daily Courier,</hi> (Louisville, KY), April 08, 1860.<lb/>
&quot;Rode the First Stage Coach,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Leavenworth Times,</hi> (Leavenworth, KS), Feb. 25, 1907.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">U.S. Civil War Pension Index: General Index to Pension Files, 1861-1934</hi>, NARA RG 15, Microfilm Series T288, Kentucky, Application #1890500, Certificate #930904.<lb/>
KYR-0001-017-0121. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
