<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002782">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Lafayette Montgomery Flournoy</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002782">
                    <persName>
                      Lafayette Montgomery Flournoy
                        (Paducah, Kentucky, attorney, banker, and entrepreneur)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1820-09-19"  ><ab>1820-09-19</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1900-06-14"  ><ab>1900-06-14</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Paducah, Kentucky, attorney, banker, and entrepreneur. Born in Powhatan County, Virginia. Married to Elizabeth C. Anderson Flournoy in 1850. Father of Richard C. A. Flournoy. Graduated from Cumberland College at Princeton, Kentucky, in 1840. Studied law with William P. Fowler. Admitted to the bar in 1841. Moved to Paducah, Kentucky, and opened practice. Attorney in Paducah from 1841 to 1849. Practiced with Judge James Campbell. Editor of the <hi rend="italic">West Kentuckian</hi> in Paducah from 1844 to 1849. President of the Commercial Bank of Kentucky branch at Paducah from 1853 to 1865. President of the Paducah Gaslight Company. Established the Paducah and Nashville Telegraph Company extending from Paducah to Nashville, Tennessee, with J. W. Jones in 1856. President of the New Orleans and Ohio River Railroad Company in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, McCracken County, Paducah, 1st District, p. 62. <hi rend="italic">The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 470. &quot;An Act to Incorporate the Paducah and Nashville Telegraph Company,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2 (Frankfort, Ky.: A. G. Hodges, State Printer, 1856), 96-98. John E. L. Robertson and Ann E. Robertson, <hi rend="italic">Paducah Kentucky: A History</hi> (Charleston: The History Press, 2014). <hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Lafayette Montgomery Flournoy (1820-1900),&quot; Memorial #101813958, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/101813958/lafayette-montgomery-flournoy (accessed March 20, 2018).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
