<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007501">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Cary Allen Hawkins</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>James N. McAllister</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007501">
                    <persName>
                      Cary Allen Hawkins
                        (Madison County, KY, farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1807-05-11"  ><ab>1807-05-11</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1877-08-01"  ><ab>1877-08-01</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Madison County, Kentucky, farmer. Kentucky native. Married Celia P. Walker Hawkins in Madison County in September 1829. Father of Jasin Hawkins, Lucy Hawkins, Nicholas Hawkins and Malissa Hawkins. Owned ten enslaved people in Madison County in 1830. Owned nine enslaved persons in Madison County in 1840. Farmer in Madison County in 1850. Owned twenty enslaved persons in Madison County in 1850. Farmer in Madison County in 1860. Owned fourteen enslaved persons in Madison County in 1860.    </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Fifth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1830), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Western Division, p. 159.

<hi rend="italic">Sixth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1840), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Eastern Division, p. 235. 

<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, District 1, p. 206A. 

<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, District 1, p. 477-478.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Western Subdivision 2, p. 215. 

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Western Subdivision 2, p. 465A.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Madison County Marriages, Film #000183311, p. 156.

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Cary A. Hawkins (1807-1877),&quot; Memorial #57645104, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/57645104 (Accessed February 11, 2017)
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
