<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002647">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Edwin McMasters Stanton</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002647">
                    <persName>
                      Edwin McMasters Stanton
                        (US attorney general and secretary of war)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1814-12-19"  ><ab>1814-12-19</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1869-12-24"  ><ab>1869-12-24</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Ohio attorney, statesman, and secretary of war (U.S.A.). Steubenville, Ohio, native. Son of David Stanton and Lucy Latham Norman Stanton. Married to Mary A. Lamson Stanton in Franklin County, Ohio, on December 31, 1836.   Father of Lucy Lamson Stanton and Edwin Lamson Stanton. Married to Ellen Maria Hutchison Stanton on June 25, 1850. Father of Eleanor A. Stanton, Lewis Hutchinson Stanton, and Bessie B. Stanton. Attended Kenyon College in Gambier, Ohio. Studied law with Daniel L. Collier. Admitted to the bar in Ohio in 1836. Attorney in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, from 1847 to 1856. Attorney in Washington, District of Columbia, from 1856 to 1860. Attorney general of the United States under President James Buchanan from December 1860 to March 1861. Secretary of war of the United States under President Abraham Lincoln and President Andrew Johnson, from January 1862 to May 1868.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Ohio, Jefferson County, Steubenville City, p. 57B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, District of Columbia, Washington, Ward 4, p. 375.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, District of Columbia, Washington, Ward 2, p. 270A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Marriage Records. Ohio Marriages.</hi> Various Ohio County Courthouses. Franklin County, Ohio, 1803-1840, p. 163. Film #000285142, p. 283 of microfilm.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Sons of the American Revolution Membership Applications, 1889-1970</hi>. Louisville, Kentucky: National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution. Application for Gideon Townsend Stanton, 1960. ID#397, p. 501 of microfilm.<lb/>
Walter Stahr, <hi rend="italic">Stanton: Lincoln&#39;s War Secretary</hi> (New York: Simon &amp; Schuster, 2017).<lb/>
William L. Barney, <hi rend="italic">The Oxford Encyclopedia of the Civil War</hi> (New York: Oxford University Press, 2011), 301-302.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
