<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00019893">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Charles Emerson Marsh</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>A. J. Blaylock</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00019893">
                    <persName>
                      Charles Emerson Marsh
                        (Vanderburgh County, Indiana, attorney )
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1835-04-08"  ><ab>1835-04-08</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1883-06-23"  ><ab>1883-06-23</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Vanderburgh County, Indiana, attorney. Ohio native. Son of Emerson Marsh and Caroline Marsh. Married to Mary E. Denny Marsh in Knox County, Indiana, on November 19, 1863. Father of Convus Marsh. Farmer in Morrow County, Ohio in 1850. Attended school in Morrow County, Ohio in 1850. Attended school in Posey County, Indiana, in 1860. Admitted to the bar in September 1861. Attorney in Vanderburgh County in 1861 through 1865. Prosecuting attorney in Vanderburgh County from May 21, 1863, to November 12, 1864. Notary public in Vanderburgh County in 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Ohio, Morrow County, Westfield, p. 7B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Indiana, Posey County, Mount Vernon, p. 681.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Indiana, Vanderburgh County, Evansville, District 7, p. 349B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Indiana Marriage Records, 1801-1952</hi>, Indiana Archives and Record Administration, Office of the Knox County Clerk. Knox County, Indiana, Marriage Records, volume F, 1860-1866, p. 336.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Vanderburgh County, IN, June 1863.<lb/>
H. Charles Ulman, <hi rend="italic">Lawyers&#39; Record and Official Register of the United States</hi>, (New York: A.S. Barnes $ Company Publishers, 1872), p. 468. <lb/>
Leander J. Monks, et al. ed. <hi rend="italic">Courts and Lawyers of Indiana</hi>, (Indianapolis: Federal Publishing Company, 1916), vol. 2, p. 1055.<lb/>
&quot;Court Notice,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Daily Journal</hi>, (Evansville, IN), 9 Aug 1862, p. 1.<lb/>
&quot;U.S. Sanitary Commission Army &amp; Navy Claim Agency,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Daily Journal</hi>, (Evansville, IN), 9 Nov 1865, p. 2.<lb/>
&quot;Charles Emerson Marsh (1835-Death 1883),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 80922132, accessed May 3, 2023, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/80922132.<lb/>
KYR-0001-006-0060. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
