<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004328">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thomas J. Farley</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004328">
                    <persName>
                      Thomas J. Farley
                        (Mason County, Kentucky, engineer and city marshal)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1822"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1822</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Mason County, Kentucky, engineer and city marshal. Virginia native. Married to Elizabeth Lilliston Farley. Father of James Farley, John Farley, Winfield Scott Farley, Queen Dorah Kansas Farley, and Elizabeth S. Farley. Engineer in Bath County, Kentucky, in 1850. Resident of Maysville, Kentucky, in 1855. Resident of Maysville, Kentucky, in 1859. Resident of Mason County in 1861. City marshal in Mason County in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bath County, p. 223.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Robertson County, Kentontown,  p. 400B-401A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records – Microfilm (1852-1914)</hi>, KDLA, Film 994027-994058: Mason County Births, 1855, p. 7, p. 7 of 7 microfilm (accessed via Ancestry.com).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records – Microfilm (1852-1914)</hi>, KDLA, Film 994027-994058: Mason County Births, 1859, p. 721, p. 5 of 8 of microfilm (accessed via Ancestry.com).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865 (Civil War Union Draft Records), Mason County, Subdistrict 6, KY, October 1863, p. 53 of 175 of microfilm (accessed via Ancestry.com).<lb/>
KYR-0001-020-1574. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
