<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000881">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Leslie Combs</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Emily D. Moses</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000881">
                    <persName>
                      Leslie Combs
                        (Clerk of the Court of Appeals)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1793-11-29"  ><ab>1793-11-29</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1881-08-22"  ><ab>1881-08-22</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Kentucky soldier, attorney, politician, and public servant. Clark County native. Son of Benjamin Combs and Sarah Richardson Combs. Married to Margaret Trotter Combs in 1819. Married to Mary Elizabeth Brownell Combs in 1849. Father of Lizzie B. Combs, Leslie Combs, and F. H. Combs. Educated by the Reverend John Lysle. Deputy clerk of the Courts of Jessamine County, Kentucky. Cadet in the 1st Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment under General James Winchester and in various capacities under General William Henry Harrison, General Green Clay. Completed education in 1816 and read law with Samuel Q. Richardson in Lexington, Kentucky. Admitted to the bar in 1818. Attorney in Lexington, Kentucky. Member of the Whig Party. Raised a regiment in response to the Texas Revolution in 1836. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1827 to 1829, in 1833, from 1845 to 1847, and from 1857 to 1859. Delegate to the Whig Party Convention, supporting the nomination of Henry Clay, in 1840. Canvassed for William Henry Harrison in the Presidential Election of 1840. Unsuccessful candidate for the House of Representatives of the United States against John C. Breckinridge in 1851. Clerk of the Court of Appeals of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1860 to 1866.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, Lexington, Ward 4, p. 102.

<hi rend="italic">The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 79-80. 

Lewis Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins’ Historical Sketches of Kentucky: History of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2 (Collins &amp; Company, 1878), 170. 

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Gen Leslie Combs (November 29, 1793-August 22, 1881),&quot; Memorial #8875416, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/8875416 (accessed February 9, 2017). 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
