<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010030">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Lucius B. Desha</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Emily D. Moses</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010030">
                    <persName>
                      Lucius B. Desha
                        (Harrison County, Kentucky, farmer and politician)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1812-04-25"  ><ab>1812-04-25</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1885-07-10"  ><ab>1885-07-10</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Harrison County, Kentucky, politician. Mason County, Kentucky, native. Son of Joseph Desha and Peggy Bledsoe Desha. Married to Julia Ann Moore in Harrison County on August 9, 1832. Father of Joseph Desha, Ben Desha, and Julia Desha. Married Eliza Moore in Harrison County on June 9, 1840. Father of Ada Desha, Ann Desha, Lucius Desha, Cave Desha, Bettie Desha, Jack Desha, Claude Desha, and Fanny Desha. Served in the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1844 to 1863. Delegate to the Democratic Party National Conventions in 1844 at Baltimore, Maryland. Member of the state Constitutional Convention in 1849. Farmer in Harrison County in 1850. Owned twenty-seven enslaved persons in Harrison County in 1850. Served as a brigadier general in the Kentucky State Militia. Delegate to the Democratic Party National Convention in 1856 at Cincinnati, Ohio. Farmer in Harrison County in 1860. Owned thirty-three enslaved persons in Harrison County in 1860. Arrested on July 26, 1862 for treason. Prisoner at Camp Chase, Ohio, from July 1862 to November 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, Louisville, District 1, p. 104B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, Louisville, District 1, p. 357.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, p. 719-720.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, p. 129A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, Cynthiana, p. 38.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Harrison County Marriages, Film #000216884, p. 543.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Harrison County Marriages, Film #000216896, p. 111.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Lucius Desha (April 25, 1812-July 10, 1885),&quot; Memorial #8041135, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/8041135 (accessed December 30, 2018).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The Biographical Encyclopedia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 37-38.<lb/>
Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2 (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co., 1874), 323.<lb/>
William A. Penn, <hi rend="italic">Kentucky Rebel Town: The Civil War Battles of Cynthiana &amp; Harrison County</hi> Lexington, KY: University Press of Kentucky, 2016. p, 85, 95. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
