<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011400">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Waddy W. Thompson</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011400">
                    <persName>
                      Waddy W. Thompson
                        (Hart County, KY, farmer and prov govt conv rep)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1814-11-15"  ><ab>1814-11-15</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1862-07"  ><ab>1862-07</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Hart County, Kentucky, farmer. Kentucky native. Married to Sarilda Magdalene Parrish Thompson in Barren County on November 14, 1847. Father of Flemming T. Thompson, William Henry Thompson, and Mary Victoria Thompson. Farmer in Barren County in 1840. Owned one enslaved person in Barren County in 1840. Farmer in Hart County in 1850. Owned six enslaved persons in Hart County in 1850. Employed Edmond Murray in 1850. Farmer in Hart County in 1860. Owned twenty enslaved persons in Hart County in 1860. Member of the convention of the provisional government held at Russellville in November 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Sixth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1840), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Barren County, East of Barren, p. 118.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, p. 263A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, p. 16 of 17 on microfilm (accessed via Ancestry.com).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, District 1, p. 721.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, District 1, p. 130A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Barren County Marriages, Film #000209756, p. 428.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records – Microfilm (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Rolls #994027-994058, Hart County Births, 1854, p. 5. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;W W Thompson (1814-1862),&quot; Memorial 135764530, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/135764530  (accessed November 13, 2019).<lb/>
KYR-0004-033-0001.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
