<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011014">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert McKee</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011014">
                    <persName>
                      Robert McKee
                        (Louisville, KY, journalist and prov govt sec of state)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1830"  ><ab>1830</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, newspaper editor and provisional government secretary of state. Fleming County, Kentucky, native. Son of William McKee and Abigail McKee. Married to Emily Reed McKee in Mason County, Kentucky, on August 15, 1855. Father of Charles McKee and Belle McKee. Laborer in Fleming County in 1850. Editor and owner of the Maysville <hi rend="italic">Express</hi> in Maysville from 1857 to 1859. Editor of the <hi rend="italic">Louisville Daily Courier</hi> in Louisville from 1859 to October 1861. Secretary at the convention of the provisional government in Russellville in November 1861. Elected secretary of state of the Confederate provisional government of Kentucky in 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fleming County, Division 2, p. 391A.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson, Louisville Ward 2, p. 454.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Mason County Marriages, Film #000281846, p. 39.

Thomas M Owen, <hi rend="italic">History of Alabama and Dictionary of Alabama Biography</hi> Vol. IV (Chicago: S.J. Clarke &amp; Co, 1921), p. 1120.

KYR-0004-033-0002.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
