<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00017692">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Barrett Allen</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>MontanaWilliamson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00017692">
                    <persName>
                      William Barrett Allen
                        (Green County, Kentucky, attorney.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1803-05-19"  ><ab>1803-05-19</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1882-04-22"  ><ab>1882-04-22</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Green County, Kentucky, bank cashier and attorney. Kentucky native. Married Huldah Wilcox Allen in 1836. Father of Jane Allen, Harriet Allen, Edward Allen, Mary Allen, and Ella M. Allen. Married to Milley N. Baker Allen in Adair County, Kentucky, on June 19, 1856. Father of Fanny B. Allen. Bank cashier in Green County, Kentucky, in 1850. Owned fourteen enslaved persons in Green County in 1850. Attorney in Green County in 1860. Owned ten enslaved persons in Green County in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, District 2, pp. 153B-154A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, District, p. 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensburg, p. 626.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensburg, p. 77A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Precinct 1, p. 420A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994027, Adair County Marriages.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Lineage Book: National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution</hi>, eds. Flora Myers Gillentine (Washington, D. C.: Press of Judd &amp; Detweiler, Inc., 1930) vol. CXIV: 1930, p. 136.<lb/>
&quot;COL William Barrett Allen (1803-1882),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 106115556, accessed November 23, 2022, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/106115556.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
