<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008639">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William P. D. Bush</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008639">
                    <persName>
                      William P. D. Bush
                        (Hancock County, KY, attorney)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1823-03-14"  ><ab>1823-03-14</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1904-06-26"  ><ab>1904-06-26</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Hancock County, Kentucky, attorney. Hardin County, Kentucky, native. Son of Christopher Bush. Attended the seminary of Elizabethtown. Married to Carrie V. Ghiselin Bush on July 22, 1852. Father of Carrie Bush, Finlay Bush, Sidney J. Bush, and Susan G. Bush. Teacher in Hodgenville, Kentucky. Appointed deputy clerk of the county and circuit courts of Hancock County in 1845. Admitted to the bar in 1846. Served in the 4th Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment during the U.S.-Mexico War as second lieutenant from October 6, 1847, to July 25, 1848. Attorney in Hancock County in 1850. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky in Hancock County from 1853 to 1854, 1861 to 1862, and 1865 to 1866. Farmer and attorney in Hancock County in 1860. Owned four enslaved persons in Hancock County in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hancock County, p. 271B.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hancock County, p. 980.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hancock County, p. 85B. 

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Frankfort, Franklin County, p. 137A.

<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Hancock County Marriages, Film #000495729, p. 119. 

Anderson Chenault Quisenberry, “History by Illustration: Gen. Zachary Taylor, and the Mexican War,” <hi rend="italic">Register of Kentucky State Historical Society</hi> 9, no. 26 (1911): 38. 

<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky: Mexican War Veterans</hi> (Frankfort: John D. Woods, Public Printer, 1889), 132.

H. Levin, <hi rend="italic">The Lawyers and Lawmakers of Kentucky</hi> (Chicago: The Lewis Publishing Company, 1897), 287-90.

<hi rend="italic">Journal of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, Begun and Held in the City of Frankfort, on Saturday, the Thirty First Day of December, in the Year of Our Lord, 1853, and of the Commonwealth, the Sixty-Second</hi> (Frankfort: A. G. Hodges, State Printer, 1853), 4. 

<hi rend="italic">Journal of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, Begun and Held in the Town of Frankfort, on Monday, the Second Day of September, in the Year of Our Lord 1861, and of the Commonwealth the Seventieth</hi> (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1861), 4. 

<hi rend="italic">Journal of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, Begun and Held in the City of Frankfort, on Monday, the Fourth Day of December, in the Year of Our Lord 1865, and of the Commonwealth the Seventy-Fourth</hi> (Frankfort: State Printing Office, 1865), 4. 

“Death’s Hand Laid Upon Judge William P. D. Bush,” <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, Ky.), June 27, 1904, p. 10.  
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
