<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00014280">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Littleberry Baker Andrews</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00014280">
                    <persName>
                      Littleberry Baker Andrews
                        (Maury County, Tennessee, farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1832"  ><ab>1832</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1921"  ><ab>1921</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Maury County, Tennessee, farmer. North Carolina native. Son of William Andrews and Parmelia J. Andrews. Married Martha J. Thurmond in Maury County, Tennessee, on July 21, 1850. Father to Alice Andrews, J. W. Andrews, Mary Andrews, Rosine Andrews, Virginia Andrews, Parmelia Andrews, and James Andrews. Farmer in Maury County in 1850. Farmer in Maury County in 1860. Employed William Harris as a farm laborer in Maury County in 1850. Owned four enslaved persons in Maury County in 1860. Charged with harboring an enslaved man named Friday (owned by William Biffle) and fleeing from justice to Kentucky in 1861. Farmer in Graves County, Kentucky, in 1863. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Tennessee, Maury County, District 14, p. 167B-168A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Tennessee, Maury County, District 13, p. 426.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Tennessee, Maury County, District 13, p. 106.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Graves County, Farmington, p. 57B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Tennessee State Marriages, 1780-2002</hi>, Tennessee State Library and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee, Marshall and Maury Counties, p. 293.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865 (Civil War Union Draft Records), Graves County, KY, June 1863, p. 583.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Littleberry Baker Andrews (1832-1921),&quot; Memorial #145095217, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/145095217 (accessed April 14, 2021).<lb/>
KYR-0001-022-0005.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
