<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004777">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Hunt Morgan</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004777">
                    <persName>
                      John Hunt Morgan
                        (Lexington, Kentucky, hemp manufacturer, Capt Lex Rifles, Col  &amp; Brig Gen&#39; 2nd KY Cav CSA)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1825-06-01"  ><ab>1825-06-01</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1864-09-04"  ><ab>1864-09-04</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Fayette County, Kentucky, hemp manufacturer and soldier. Huntsville, Alabama, native. Son of Calvin Morgan and Henrietta Hunt Morgan. Married to Rebecca Bruce Morgan on November 21, 1848. Married to Martha O. Ready Morgan on December 14, 1862. Father of Johnnie Hunt Morgan. Attended Transylvania University in Lexington from 1842 to 1844. Served in the Kentucky Mounted Volunteers as first lieutenant in the U.S.-Mexican War from 1846 to 1847. Member of the Masonic Order at Daviess Lodge #22 in Lexington from 1846 to 1864. Manufacturer in Lexington in 1850. Served in a state militia artillery company in Lexington as captain from 1852 to 1854. Served in the Lexington Rifles of the Kentucky State Guard as captain from 1857 to 1861.  Manufacturer in Lexington in 1860. With C. C. Morgan, owned thirty enslaved persons in Lexington in 1860. Employed one enslaved person in Lexington in 1860. Served in the 2nd Kentucky Cavalry Regiment (C.S.A.)  as colonel and brigadier general from 1861 to 1864. Killed at Greeneville, Tennessee, on September 4, 1864. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, Lexington, District 1, p. 146B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, County, Lexington Ward 2, p. 433.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, County, Lexington Ward 2, p. 452B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, County, Lexington Ward 4, 461B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;John Hunt Morgan (1825-1864),&quot; Memorial #4433, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/4433 (accessed September 6, 2019).<lb/>
James A. Ramage, “Morgan, John Hunt,” in <hi rend="italic">The Kentucky Encyclopedia</hi>, ed. John E. Kleber (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 2015), pp. 650-651.<lb/>
James A. Ramage, <hi rend="italic">Rebel Raider: The Life of General John Hunt Morgan</hi> (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 1986).John Fiske and James Grant Wilson, ed., <hi rend="italic">Appleton&#39;s Cyclopædia of American Biography</hi>, vol. 4, (New York: Appleton, 1889), 402.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
