<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002589">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Mortimer O. H. Norton</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002589">
                    <persName>
                      Mortimer O. H. Norton
                        (New Orleans, Louisiana, cotton merchant and railroad executive)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1816-06-19"  ><ab>1816-06-19</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1872-08-30"  ><ab>1872-08-30</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>New Orleans, Louisiana, cotton merchant and railroad executive. New York native. Father of George Norton, Clara Norton, Permellia Norton, Henrietta Norton, and Hewett Norton. Cotton merchant in New Orleans in 1850. Member of the executive committee of the New Orleans and Opelousas Railroad in 1852. Partner of Hewitt, Norton &amp; Co., with James Hewitt and John M. Wisdom, in 1855. Member of the Louisiana Secession Convention and voted for secession. Director of the New Orleans, Jackson and Great Northern Railway in New Orleans in 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Louisiana, Orleans Parish, 3rd Representatives District, p. 470. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Louisiana, Orleans Parish, New Orleans, 4th Ward, p. 38. <hi rend="italic">Low&#39;s Railway Directory for 1861; And Official List of Officers and Directors of the Railroads in the United States and Canadas</hi>, James W. Low, comp. (New York: E. R. Bennet &amp; Co., 1861), 137. <hi rend="italic">Cohen&#39;s New Orleans Directory for 1855</hi> (New Orleans: Office of the Picatune, 1855), 273. &quot;New Orleans and Opelousas Rail-road: Engineer&#39;s Report,&quot; <hi rend="italic">De Bow&#39;s Review of the Southern and Western States</hi>, J. D. B. De Bow, ed., vol. 12 (New Orleans: Exchange Place, 1852), 435-438. Henry Rightor, ed., <hi rend="italic">Standard History of New Orleans, Louisiana</hi> (Chicago: The Lewis Publishing Company, 1900), 151. <hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Mortimer Oliver Hubbard Norton (1816-1872),&quot; Memorial #14838684, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/14838684/mortimer-oliver_hubbard-norton (accessed March 13, 2018).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
