<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003207">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William A. Hooe</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003207">
                    <persName>
                      William A. Hooe
                        (Mercer County, KY, attorney, state rep &amp; state senator)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1821"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1821</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1869"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1869</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Harrodsburg, Kentucky, attorney and politician. Virginia native. Married to Nancy McAfee Hooe. Father of Joseph A. Hooe, Mary Jennie Hooe, Edward B. Hooe, Robert M. Hooe, William A. Hooe Jr., Emmet M. Hooe, Frank Hooe, and Nannie Hooe. Married to Sue Burford Hooe. Father of Willie Hooe and John A. Hooe. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky in 1843 and 1849. Attorney in Mercer County, Kentucky, in 1850. Owned three enslaved persons in Mercer County in 1850. Member of the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1851 to 1853. Attorney in Harrodsburg in 1860. Owned two enslaved persons in Harrodsburg in 1860. Mayor of Harrodsburg in 1861. Organized the Mercer Home Guard with Christopher Chinn in June 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, District 1, p. 273A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, District 1, p. 18 of microfilm.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, Harrodsburg, pp. 711-12.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, Harrodsburg, p. 6.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Birth and Death Records: Covington, Lexington, Louisville, and Newport – Microfilm (before 1911)</hi>, KDLA, Roll #7020659: All Counties, Mercer County Deaths, p. 514, File #24006.<lb/>
Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend="italic">Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2 (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co., 1882), 603-04.<lb/>
KYR-0001-004-0368.<lb/>
KYR-0002-022-0125.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
