<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00014967">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Charles James Brenham</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00014967">
                    <persName>
                      Charles James Brenham
                        (San Francisco, California, notary public and commissioner of deeds)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1817-11-06"  ><ab>1817-11-06</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1875-05-10"  ><ab>1875-05-10</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>San Francisco, California, mayor, notary public, and commissioner of deeds. Kentucky native. Married to Elizabeth &quot;Betty&quot; Adair Brenham. Father of Louisa Brenham, Robert Brenham, Mary Brenham, and Betty Brenham. Mayor of San Francisco from May 5, 1851, to December 31, 1851. Mayor of San Francisco from November 10, 1852, to October 2, 1853. Notary public in San Francisco, California, in 1860. Employed Margaret Mulkeen as a nurse in San Francisco in 1860. Employed Kate Nicholston as a cook in San Francisco in 1860. Notary public and commissioner of deeds in San Francisco from 1861 to 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, California, San Francisco County, San Francisco, District 2, p. 673.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870),  Population Schedules, California, San Francisco County, San Francisco, Ward 11, p. 561A.<lb/>
William F. Heintz, <hi rend="italic">San Francisco&#39;s Mayors: 1850–1880, From the Gold Rush to the Silver Bonanza</hi>, (Woodside, CA: Gilbert Roberts Publications, 1975).<lb/>
&quot;Notice of Sale of Real Estate at Private Sale&quot; <hi rend="italic">Placer Herald</hi>, (Rocklin, CA) June 23, 1900, p. 7.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">San Francisco Directory and Business Guide, 1861-1862</hi>, ed. Henry G. Langley (San Francisco: Henry G. Langley, 1861), 77.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">San Francisco Directory and Business Guide, 1862-1863</hi>, ed. Henry G. Langley (San Francisco: Henry G. Langley, 1862), 444.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The San Francisco Directory for the Year Commencing October, 1863</hi>, ed. Henry G. Langley (San Francisco: Henry G. Langley, 1863), 77.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The San Francisco Directory for the Year Commencing October, 1864</hi>, ed. Henry G. Langley (San Francisco: Henry G. Langley, 1864), 451.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The San Francisco Directory for the Year Commencing October, 1865</hi>, ed. Henry G. Langley (San Francisco: Henry G. Langley, 1865), 92.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Sons of the American Revolution Membership Applications, 1889-1970</hi>, National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, Louisville, Ky, Adair, National #7304, State #104.<lb/>
&quot;Charles James Brenham (1817-1875),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #106709339, accessed July 8, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/106709339. <lb/>
&quot;San Francisco Mayors,&quot; City and County of San Francisco, accessed July 8, 2021.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
