<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018924">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Albert N. Jett</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018924">
                    <persName>
                      Albert N. Jett
                        (Carroll County, Kentucky, engineer apprentice and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1840"  ><ab>1840</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1932-04-30"  ><ab>1932-04-30</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Carroll County, Kentucky, student, apprentice, and soldier. Kentucky native. Son of Richard Henry V. Jett and Elizabeth Badney Jett. Attended school in Carroll County, Kentucky, in 1850. Engineer apprentice in Carroll County in 1860. Served in the 13th Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.) as a second sergeant, first lieutenant, and captain from December 31, 1861 to January 12, 1865. Wounded at the Battle of Huff&#39;s Ferry, Roane County, Tennessee, on November 14, 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Carroll County, District 1, p. 188A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Carroll County, Carrollton, p. 3.<lb/>
Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers Who Served in Organizations From the State of Kentucky<hi rend="italic">, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0265.<lb/>
_Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, File 8181.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), p.869-71.<lb/>
&quot;Albert N. Jett (1840-1932),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 13016138, accessed November 28, 2022, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/13016138.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
