<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011627">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Edwin A. Keeble</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Peter R. Thomas Jr.</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011627">
                    <persName>
                      Edwin A. Keeble
                        (Murfreesboro, Tennessee, attorney and politician)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1808"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1808</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1868"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1868</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Murfreesboro, Tennessee, attorney and politician. Tennessee native. Married Mary W. Maney in Rutherford, Tennessee on November 30, 1836. Father of J. M. Keeble, Sallie Keeble, E. A. Keeble, Thomas Keeble, W. B. Keeble, and M. B. Keeble. Attorney in Murfreesboro, Tennessee in 1850. Mayor of Murfreesboro, Tennessee between 1838 and 1855. Attorney in Murfreesboro, Tennessee in 1860. Owned thirty-two enslaved persons in Murfreesboro, Tennessee in 1860. Member of the Tennessee House of Representatives between 1861 and 1862. Speaker of the Tennessee House of Representatives between 1861 and 1862. Representative from Tennessee in the Confederate Congress between 1864 and 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Tennessee, Rutherford County, City/District, p. 350.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Tennessee, Rutherford County, Murfreesboro, p. 164.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Tennessee, Rutherford County, Murfreesboro, p. 74. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Tennessee Marriage Records</hi>, Tennessee State Library and Records, Nashville, Tennessee, p. 132.<lb/>
Lawrence Kestenbaum, The Political Graveyard http://politicalgraveyard.com/bio/keathley-keena.html.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
