<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008199">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Albert Sidney Johnston</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008199">
                    <persName>
                      Albert Sidney Johnston
                        (Commander Dept of Pacific, US Army and general &amp; commander western dept CSA)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1803-02-02"  ><ab>1803-02-02</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1862-04-06"  ><ab>1862-04-06</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Kentucky soldier. Washington, Kentucky, native. Married to Henrietta Preston Johnston in Jefferson County, Kentucky, on January 14, 1829. Father of William Preston Johnston and Henrietta Preston Johnston. Married to Eliza Griffin Johnston in Shelby County on October 3, 1843. Father of  Albert Sidney Johnston, Jr, Hancock Johnston, Margaret Johnston, Griffin Johnston, and Alberta Johnston. Attended Transylvania University. Graduated from the United States Military Academy at West Point, New York, in 1826. Veteran of the Black Hawk War. Veteran of the Texas Revolution. Served in the Texas army as a senior brigadier general and commander in 1837. Secretary of war for the Republic of Texas from 1838 to 1840. Veteran of the U.S.-Mexican War. Served in the U.S. Army as paymaster in 1849. Brevetted brigadier general in 1859. Resident of Louisville, Kentucky, in 1860. Employed Bridget Barey as a servant in Louisville in 1860. Commanded the Department of the Pacific of the U.S. Army in 1861. Resigned from the U.S. Army in 1861. Appointed full general in the Confederate Army in 1861. Commanded the Western Department of the Confederate Army. Died at the Battle of Shiloh on April 6, 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 7, p. 530.<lb/>
Charles P. Roland, <hi rend="italic">Albert Sidney Johnston: Soldier of Three Republics</hi> (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 2001).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records, 1783-1965</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, 1785-1842, Film #000482706, p. 29, p. 111 of 577 of microfilm (accessed via Ancestry.com).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, “Henrietta Preston Johnston (1832-1908),&quot; Memorial #86489849, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/86489849/henrietta-preston-johnston (accessed May 3, 2021).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records, 1783-1965</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Shelby County Marriages, 1833-1938, Film #000259288, p. 43 of 1209 of microfilm (accessed via Ancestry.com).<lb/>
Wright, John D., <hi rend="italic">The Routledge Encyclopedia of Civil War Era Biographies</hi>, (New York: Routledge, 2013), 318. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
