<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00016860">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thacker Quisenberry </title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Rachael Nicholas</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00016860">
                    <persName>
                      Thacker Quisenberry 
                        (Clark County, Kentucky, farmer and justice of the peace)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1816"  ><ab>1816</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1898"  ><ab>1898</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Clark County, Kentucky, farmer and justice of the peace. Kentucky native. Son of Tandy Quisenberry. Married to Frances G. McMurtry Quisenberry in Clark County, Kentucky, on August 17, 1836. Father of William P. Quisenberry and Orvilia Quisenberry. Married to Elizabeth Brockman Quisenberry in Clark County on February 6, 1843. Father of Elizabeth Quisenberry. Married to Permelia Mitchell Quisenberry in 1845. Father of Susan Quisenberry, Johnson Quisenberry, Ann E. Quisenberry, Matilda Quisenberry, Margaret Quisenberry, Jerusha Quisenberry, Thacker Quisenberry, and Roger Quisenberry. Farmer in Clark County in 1850. Owned three enslaved persons in Clark County in 1850. Farmer in Clark County in 1860. Owned five enslaved persons in Clark County in 1860. Justice of the peace in Clark County in 1862. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Clark County, District 2, p. 13A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Clark County, District 2, p. 287-8.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Clark County, District 2, p. 832-3.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Clark County, District 2, p. 341B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Clark County, Precinct 4, p. 49A-B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Clark County Marriages, 1793-1911, Film #001943687, p. 40.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Clark County Marriages, Film #001943687, p. 92.<lb/>
&quot;Thacker Colby Quisenberry Sr. (1816-1898),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #82276843, accessed December 23, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/82276843; <lb/>
&quot;Was a Native of Fayette,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Lexington Herald-Leader</hi> (KY), November 9, 1900, Newspapers.com, https://www.newspapers.com/clip/91072021/.<lb/>
KYR-0001-031-0047. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
