<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00017166">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Holeman, Jr.</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00017166">
                    <persName>
                      John Holeman, Jr.
                        (Caldwell County, Kentucky, farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1826-05-31"  ><ab>1826-05-31</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1921-09-25"  ><ab>1921-09-25</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Caldwell County, Kentucky, farmer. Caldwell County, Kentucky, native. Married to Jane B. Morse Holeman in Caldwell County, Kentucky, on October 16, 1848. Father of John A. Holeman, William F. Holeman, James M. Holeman, Jesse Holeman, Daniel K. Holeman, and Pantiler G. Holeman. Married to Alcy Holeman. Father of Martha Holeman. Farmer in Caldwell County in 1850. Farmer in Caldwell County in 1860.Owned five enslaved persons in Caldwell County in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, District 1, p. 283A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Princeton, p. 96.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Princeton, p. 226A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Williams Mill, p. 546A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Caldwell County Marriages, Film #000851644.<lb/>
&quot;John Holeman (1826-1921),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #47186682, accessed January 24, 2022, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/47186682.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
