<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00019250">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Lyman Lewis Parks</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Rachael Nicholas</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Rachael Nicholas</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00019250">
                    <persName>
                      Lyman Lewis Parks
                        (Jefferson County, Kentucky, law student)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1849-50"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1849-50</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1911"  ><ab>1911</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Jefferson County, Kentucky, law student. Kentucky native. Son of Lyman Parks and Elizabeth Jane Lewis Parks. Resident in Jefferson County, Kentucky, in 1850. Household owned two enslaved persons in Jefferson County in 1850. Attended school in Jefferson County in 1860. Household employed Sallie Hayes as a servant in Jefferson County in 1860. Law student in the office of Logan Adams Wood in Jefferson County. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 7, p. 355A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 7, p. 69. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 8, p. 748.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film 000482706, p. 68. <lb/>
&quot;Mrs. Lizzie Parks Dies at Greenville,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The State</hi> (Columbia, SC), November 28, 1948, p. 1, 8. <lb/>
KYR-0001-004-3172. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
