<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00013001">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Alexander Hammond</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kristen Bailey</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Kristen Bailey</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00013001">
                    <persName>
                      William Alexander Hammond
                        (Maryland soldier and Surgeon General of the U.S. Army)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1828-08-28"  ><ab>1828-08-28</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1900-01-05"  ><ab>1900-01-05</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Maryland soldier and surgeon general of the United States Army. Maryland native. Married to Helen Nisbit Hammonds in 1849. Father of Summerville Hammond, Clarra Nesbit Hammond, and Graham Mansol Hammond. Served in the U.S. Army as assistant surgeon from 1849 to 1860. Employed Debora Davis and Issabella Fisher as domestic servants in Mackinac County, Michigan, in 1860. Chair of the departments of anatomy and physiology at the University of Maryland in 1860. Served in the United State Army as surgeon general from April 1862 to August 1864. Tried by court-martial and dismissed from service in August 1864.  </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Michigan, Mackinac County, Mackinac Island, p. 994. <lb/>
&quot;Noted Marylander Dead, Former Surgeon-General Hammond Suddenly Expires,&quot;<hi rend="italic">The Baltimore Sun</hi>(Baltimore, Maryland), January 6, 1900, p. 2.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
