<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00019131">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Nathaniel Green Henderson</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00019131">
                    <persName>
                      Nathaniel Green Henderson
                        (Hickman County, Kentucky, farmer and private (U.S.A.))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1823"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1823</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1864-09-17"  ><ab>1864-09-17</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Hickman County, Kentucky, farmer and solider. Tennessee native. Married to Mary A. Henderson. Father of Julia Ann Henderson, Mary J. M. Henderson, Louisa E. Henderson, Lea A. Henderson, Joel P. Henderson, and James D. Henderson. Farmer in Weakley County, Tennessee, in 1850. Farmer in Hickman County, Kentucky, in 1860. Owned one enslaved person in Hickman County in 1860. Farmer in Hickman County in 1863. Served in the 13th Tennessee Cavalry (U.S.A.) as private from December 7, 1863 to September 17, 1864. Captured at Fort Pillow, Tennessee, on April 12, 1864. Prisoner of war at Andersonville Prison, Georgia, until September 17, 1864. Died from disease in Andersonville Prison Hospital on September 17, 1864. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Tennessee, Weakley County, District 5, p. 454A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hickman County, Hays, p. 561.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hickman County, Columbus, p. 203B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Hickman County, KY, June 1863, p. 9.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">U.S. Civil War Pension Index: General Index to Pension Files, 1861-1934</hi>, NARA RG 15, Microfilm Series T288, Tennessee, Roll 211, Application 161145, Certificate 122829.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers Who Served in Organizations From the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0109.<lb/>
&quot;Nathaniel G. Henderson Jr. (Unknown-1864),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 51137294, accessed January 2, 2023, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/51137294.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
