<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00019627">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Charles Bridges Pearce</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>A. J. Blaylock</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00019627">
                    <persName>
                      Charles Bridges Pearce
                        (Mason County, Kentucky, merchant and banker)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1823-05-07"  ><ab>1823-05-07</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1905-05-14"  ><ab>1905-05-14</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Mason County, Kentucky, merchant and banker. Fleming County, Kentucky native. Son of William Pearce and Mary Bridges Pearce. Married to Maria Shultz Pearce in Mason County, Kentucky on October 26, 1848. Father of Lewis Edward Pearce, Charlotte Pearce, Christian Pearce, Charles Pearce, Lottie Pearce, and Mary Pearce. Dry goods merchant in partnership with Lewis C. Pearce and Hiram T. Pearce in Mason County from 1840 to 1844. Merchant in Mason County in 1850. Owned three enslaved persons in Mason County in 1850. Merchant in partnership with Joseph Wallingford in Mason County from 1860 to 1866. Owned five enslaved persons in Mason County in 1860. Broker in Mason County in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mason County, Maysville, p. 33A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Mason County, Maysville.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mason County, Maysville, p. 364.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Mason County, Maysville, p. 3B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mason County, Maysville, p. 402B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Mason County Marriages, Film 000281843.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky, Wills and Probate Records, 1774-1989</hi>, Kentucky County, District, and Probate Courts, Mason County Wills, vol. Z, 1900-1924, p. 293.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Internal Revenue Assessment Lists for Kentucky, 1862-1866</hi> NARA RG 58, Microfilm Series M768, Roll 15, Mason County, Kentucky, 1862, p. 10.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Mason County, KY, October 1863.<lb/>
&quot;Merchants&#39; Cards, Etc,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi>, (Louisville, KY), 5 Jan 1844, p. 1. <lb/>
&quot;Charles Bridges Pearce,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Public Ledger</hi>, (Louisville, KY), 15 May 1905, p. 1.<lb/>
&quot;Charles Bridges Pearce,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Biographical Cyclopedia of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</hi>(1896), p. 458-9.<lb/>
&quot;Charles Bridges Pearce (1823-1905),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 134353453, accessed March 28, 2023, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/134353453.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
