<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011553">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Augustus Williams</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011553">
                    <persName>
                      John Augustus Williams
                        (Mercer County, KY, educator, Daughters College, curator KY Univ)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1824-09-25"  ><ab>1824-09-25</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1903-11-07"  ><ab>1903-11-07</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Mercer County, Kentucky, educator and administrator. Kentucky native. Son of Charles Edwin Williams and Arabella Dodge Williams. Married to Mary Louise Hathaway Williams in 1848. Father of Bell Shannon Williams, Augustus Edwin Williams and Bowman Williams. Attended Bacon College in Georgetown, Kentucky, which relocated to Harrodsburg and became Kentucky University. Graduate of Kentucky University. Received LL. D. from Masonic University at LaGrange, Kentucky. Administrator of Prospect Hill Seminary from 1848 to 1850. Founder and teacher at Bourbon Institute and Clay Seminary in Bourbon County in 1850. Owned nine enslaved persons in Bourbon County in 1850. Established Christian College in Columbia, Missouri, in 1851. Returned to Kentucky in 1856 to establish Daughters College with his father from July 25, 1856, to 1893. Owned one enslaved person in Mercer County in 1860. Secretary of the Board of Curators of Kentucky University in 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bourbon County, District 1, p. 306A.

<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Bourbon County, District 1, p. 525 (p. 35 of microfilm).

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, p. 794.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, p. 60B (p. 25 of microfilm).

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, Harrodsburg, p. 596A.

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;John Augustus Williams (1824-1903),&quot; Memorial 45691310, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/45691310  (accessed December 17, 2019).

<hi rend="italic">Vital Statistics Original Death Certificates – Microfilm (1911-1964)</hi>, KDLA, Roll#7016188, All County Deaths, File #23938, p. 843 of microfilm.

Harp, Scott, “John Augustus Williams,” <hi rend="italic">History of the Restoration Movement</hi>, <lb/>
https://www.therestorationmovement.com/_states/kentucky/williams,ja.htm (accessed December 17, 2019).

Bourne, Ann Shanks, Mattie Terhune Davis, Lydia Kennedy Bond, and Lydia K Bond. <hi rend="italic">History of Daughters College (1856-1893) and Its Founder John Augustus Williams</hi>, (Pamphlet, 1900). https://archive.org/stream/historyofdaughte00bour/historyofdaughte00bour_djvu.txt (accessed on December 16, 2019). 

KYR-0001-009-0038.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
