<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000987">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Craig Rush</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name></name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000987">
                    <persName>
                      James Craig Rush
                        (Hart County, Kentucky, attorney, Baptist minister, and chaplain (9th Kentucky Infantry).)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1816-01-14"  ><ab>1816-01-14</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1899-10-24"  ><ab>1899-10-24</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Hart County, Kentucky, attorney, Baptist minister, and chaplain. Kentucky native. Son of John Rush. Married to Louisa J. Holderman Rush in Hardin County, Kentucky, on July 13, 1837. Father of Arabella D. Rush, Cadwallader W. Rush, Mollie V. Rush, Mattie Rush, James Peter Rush, and Ella Rush. Attorney in Hart County, Kentucky, in 1850. Owned two enslaved persons in Hart County in 1850. Owned Bob [Unknown] in Hart County in 1856. Baptist minister in Hart County in 1860. Owned five enslaved persons in Hart County in 1860. Served in the 9th Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.) as chaplain from November 26, 1861, to November 7, 1862. Resigned on account of illness on November 7, 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, p. 264B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, Munfordville, p. 955.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, District 2, p. 138B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, Munfordville, p. 345B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers Who Served in Organizations From the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0234.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994038, Hart County Births.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky, County Marriages, 1797-1954</hi>, Genealogical Society of Salt Lake City, Salt Lake City, UT, Hardin County Marriages, Film 000390788.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Sons of the American Revolution Membership Applications, 1889-1970</hi>, National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, Louisville, KY, National 91435, State 1176.<lb/>
&quot;At an Advanced Aged: The Rev. James C. Rush, a Baptist Minister, Dies,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY), October 28, 1899, p. 12.<lb/>
J. H. Spencer and Burrilla B. Spencer, <hi rend="italic">A History of Kentucky Baptists from 1769 to 1885: Including More than 800 Biographical Sketches</hi>, vol. II (Cincinnati: J. R. Baumes, 1885), 63.<lb/>
&quot;Rev James C. Rush, (1816-1898),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 119987484, accessed August 30, 2023, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/119987484.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
