<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00015189">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Streshly Jackson</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Kevin McPartland</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00015189">
                    <persName>
                      James Streshly Jackson
                        (Christian County, Kentucky, attorney, congressman, and Brigadier General (U.S.A.))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1823-09-27"  ><ab>1823-09-27</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1862-10-08"  ><ab>1862-10-08</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Christian County, Kentucky, attorney, congressman, and Brigadier General (U.S.A.). Fayette County, Kentucky native. Married to Pattie Buford Jackson in Scott County, Kentucky, in 1847. Father of David Jackson, James B. Jackson, Etta Jackson, and Juliet Jackson. Attended Centre College in Danville, Kentucky. Graduated from Jefferson College, in Canonsburg, Pennsylvania, in 1844. Graduated Law School at Transylvania University in Lexington, Kentucky, in 1845. Admitted to the Kentucky Bar in 1845. Served in the 1st Kentucky Cavalry (U.S.A.) as a private and third lieutenant from June 9, 1846 to October 10, 1846. Attorney in Greenup County in 1850. Owned four enslaved persons in Greenup County in 1850. Attorney in Christian County in 1860. Owned thirteen enslaved persons in Christian County in 1860. Served as United States Congressman from Kentucky&#39;s Second District from March 4 1861, to December 13, 1861. Served in the 3rd Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry Regiment (U.S.A) as a colonel from December 13, 1861 to August 13, 1862. Served in McCook&#39;s Corps of the Army of the Ohio (U.S.A.) as a Brigadier General  from July 16, 1862 to October 8, 1862. Killed at the Battle of Perryville in Boyle County, Kentucky, on October 8, 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Greenup County, District 2, p. 158B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules,  Kentucky, Greenup County, District 2, p. 238.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, Hopkinsville, p. 683-4.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, p. 271B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Lineage Book of the Charter Members of the National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution</hi>, eds. Mary S. Lockwood and Susan Riviere Hetzel (Washington, D. C.: National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1891-1939) vol. 166: 1921, p. 99.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), 63.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), 960.<lb/>
&quot;James Streshly Jackson, (1823-1862),&quot; <hi rend="italic">Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</hi>, 1774-Present<hi rend="italic">, https://bioguide.congress.gov/search/bio/J000019 (accessed July 28, 2021). <lb/>
“James Streshly Jackson,” _Appleton&#39;s Cyclopædia of American Biography</hi>, vol. 3, eds. John Fiske and James Grant Wilson (New York: Appleton, 1889), 388.<lb/>
&quot;James Streshly Jackson (1823-1862),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #5894202, accessed July 28, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/5894202.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
