<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000340">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Aaron Harding</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name></name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000340">
                    <persName>
                      Aaron Harding
                        (Taylor County)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1805-02-23"  ><ab>1805-02-23</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1875-12-24"  ><ab>1875-12-24</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Green County, Kentucky, attorney. Kentucky native. Married to Margaret Campbell Harding. Father of John Harding, Samuel Harding, Sarah Harding, and Robert Harding. Married to Sallie A. Callendar Harding. Admitted to the bar in 1833. Commonwealth&#39;s Attorney in Green County from 1833 to 1839. Member of the House of Representatives for the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Green County in 1840. Owned five enslaved people in Green County in 1850. Attorney in Green County in 1860. Owned seven enslaved people in Green County in 1860. Member of the House of Representatives for the United States of American from Kentucky from 1861 to 1867. Member of the Democratic Party. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Sixth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1840), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensburg District 2, p. 182.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, District 1, p. 201.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensburg, District 2, p. 630.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensburg, District 2, p. 77B.<lb/>
“Harding, Aaron,” <hi rend="italic">Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</hi>, accessed September 9, 2023, http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=H000187.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
