<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000809">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Lucien Anderson</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000809">
                    <persName>
                      Lucien Anderson
                        (Representatives)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1824-06-23"  ><ab>1824-06-23</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1898-10-18"  ><ab>1898-10-18</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Graves County, Kentucky, attorney and politician. Kentucky native. Married to Ann R. Lockridge Anderson. Father of Harry C. Anderson, Nancy A. Anderson, Herbert L. Anderson, Robert L. Anderson, Mayes Anderson, and Lillian Anderson. Lived in Mayfield, Kentucky. Studied law and admitted to the bar in 1845. Attorney in Graves Count in 1850. Presidential elector for the Whig Party in 1852. Served as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives from 1855 to 1857. Owned five enslaved persons in 1860. Served the First Congressional District of Kentucky as an Unconditional Unionist member of the United States House of Representative from 1863 to 1865. Delegate to the Republican National Convention in 1864. Charged with working with General Eleazer A. Paine to extort citizens in and around Paducah, Kentucky in July and August 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Graves County, District 2, p. 363B.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Graves County, Mayfield, p. 332. 

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Graves County, Mayfield, p. 219B. 

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Graves County, p. 53A. 

<hi rend="italic">Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</hi>, s.v. “Anderson, Lucien,” http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=A000201 (accessed December 1, 2016).

Berry Craig and Dieter C. Ullrich, <hi rend="italic">Unconditional Unionist: The Hazardous Life of Lucian Anderson, Kentucky Congressman</hi> (Jefferson, N.C.: McFarland &amp; Company, Inc., 2016); 

“Investigation of General Paine’s Administration at Paducah,” <hi rend="italic">Louisville Weekly Journal</hi>, 4 October 1864.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
