<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008859">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Henry Clay McLeod</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008859">
                    <persName>
                      Henry Clay McLeod
                        (Woodford County, soldier, lawyer, and state representative)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1831-06-03"  ><ab>1831-06-03</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1905-02-27"  ><ab>1905-02-27</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Woodford County, Kentucky, soldier, attorney, and state representative. Bourbon County, Kentucky, native. Son of George McLeod and Catherine Miller McLeod. Married to Alice Todd Field McLeod in Woodford County on November 24, 1864. Graduate of Transylvania University Law School in Lexington, Kentucky, in 1857. Farmer in Bourbon County in 1850. Attorney in Woodford County in 1860. Entered partnership to practice law with J. E. Hoskins in Versailles, Kentucky, until 1861. Elected county attorney of Woodford County in 1861 and in 1865. Enrolled in the 6th Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.) from September 23, 1861. Promoted to captain from November 28, 1861. Resigned from service from December 15, 1862. Elected state representative for Woodford County in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bourbon County, District 2. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Woodford County, Versailles, p. 14. <hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Woodford County, Versailles, p. 19. <hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0205. <hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Woodford County Marriages, Film #000252336. <hi rend="italic">The Biographical EncyclopÊdia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 640. <lb/>
&quot;Gallant Soldier and Able Lawyer Dies,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Frankfort Roundabout</hi> (Frankfort, Ky.), March 4, 1905, p. 7. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Capt Henry C. McLeod (1831-1905),&quot; Memorial #132015819, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/132015819 (accessed on July 6, 2018).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
