<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00019597">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Joseph A. Risen</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00019597">
                    <persName>
                      Joseph A. Risen
                        (Green County, Kentucky, farmer.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1820"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1820</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Green County, Kentucky, farmer. Kentucky native. Married to Martha Jane Eastes Risen in Green County, Kentucky, on January 29, 1844. Father of William P. Rison, Emily Rison, John T. Rison, Louisa Rison, Mary E. Rison, and Henry Rison. Farmer in LaRue County, Kentucky, in 1850. Farmer in Green County, Kentucky, in 1860. Arrested on March 2, 1864, on a charge of aiding John Hunt Morgan&#39;s raid in 1862. Signed a loyalty oath to the U.S. government on March 3, 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, LaRue County, Hamiltons District, p. 429A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, District 1, p. 645.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensburg Precinct, p. 408A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994036, Green County Births.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky, County Marriages, 1797-1954</hi>, Genealogical Society of Salt Lake City, Salt Lake City, UT, Green County Marriages, Film 000595013.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Selected Records of the War Department Relating to Confederate Prisoners of War, 1861-1865</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M598.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Unfiled Papers and Slips Belonging in Confederate Compiled Service Records</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M347, Roll 0336.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
