<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00020771">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Milton Sowder</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00020771">
                    <persName>
                      Milton Sowder
                        (Rockcastle County, Kentucky, police judge, cabinet marker, soldier, and blacksmith.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1827-03-05"  ><ab>1827-03-05</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1892-08-04"  ><ab>1892-08-04</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Rockcastle County, Kentucky, police judge, cabinet marker, soldier, and blacksmith. Kentucky native. Married to China Horn Sowder. Father of Granville G. Sowder, Martha Ann &quot;Mattie&quot; Sowder, and Milton F. Sowder. Farmer in Rockcastle County, Kentucky, in 1850. Police judge in Mount Vernon, Rockcastle County. Cabinet maker in Rockcastle County in 1860. Served in the Rockcastle and Lincoln County Home Guard (U.S.A.) as a private from May 7, 1862, to July 7, 1862. Blacksmith in Hendricks County, Indiana, in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Rockcastle County, Northern District, p. 190A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Rockcastle County, Mount Vernon, p. 586.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Indiana, Hendricks County, Eel River Township, p. 348B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers Who Served in Organizations From the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0472.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Henricks County, IN, June 1863, p. 304.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Indiana Death Certificates, 1900–2011</hi>, Indiana State Department of Health and Vital Records, Indiana Archives and Records Administration, Indianapolis, IN, Certificate 433.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994053, Rockcastle County Births.<lb/>
&quot;Milton Sowder (1827-1892),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 119248022, accessed September 25, 2023, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/119248022.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
