<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011628">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Granville C. Torbett</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011628">
                    <persName>
                      Granville C. Torbett
                        (Tennessee, State Treasurer, Congressman)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1810-03-04"  ><ab>1810-03-04</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1872-02-14"  ><ab>1872-02-14</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Monroe County, Tennessee, state treasurer and congressman. Tennessee native. Married to Martha Louisa Barrow on November 33, 2843. Father of Emma L. Torbett, Fannie Torbett, Matthew Torbett, and Elizabeth Torbett. Hotel owner in Madisonville, Tennessee in the 1820s. Member of the Tennessee state House of Representatives for Monroe County from 1841 to 1843. State Senator from 1843 to 1847. Attorney in Madison County, Kentucky in 1850. Worked at a printing firm, Eastman and Torbett, in Nashville, Tennessee in 1852. This firm published and edited <hi rend="italic">The Daily American</hi> newspaper. State Treasurer of Tennessee from 1855 to 1857. Attorney in Nashville, Tennessee in 1860. President of the Bank of Tennessee in 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Tennessee, Madison, District 15, p. 217B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Tennessee, Davidson, Nashville Ward 5, p. 407.<lb/>
&quot;Granville C. Torbett,&quot; <hi rend="italic">Tennessee Department of Treasury</hi> (accessed online December 30, 2019). 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
