<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00016414">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Willis Virgil Pratt</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hailey Brangers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00016414">
                    <persName>
                      Willis Virgil Pratt
                        (Webster Co, KY physician )
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1835"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1835</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Webster County, Kentucky, physician. Kentucky native. Son of William Pratt and Emily F. Pratt. Married to Nancy Ruby Pratt in Webster County, Kentucky, on March 7, 1862. Father of Ella Pratt. Laborer in Christian County in 1850. Graduated from the Eclectic Medical Institute in Cincinnati, Ohio, in 1856. Physician in Webster County, Kentucky, in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, District 2, p. 392A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Webster County, p. 476.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hopkins County, Madisonville, p. 168B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Webster County Marriages, Film #000565876.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Twelfth Annual Announcement of the Eclectic Medical Institute, of Cincinnati.</hi> (Cincinnati: Moore, Wilstach, Keys &amp; Co., 1856), 11.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
