<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00014382">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Littleton Perry</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hailey Brangers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Hailey Brangers</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00014382">
                    <persName>
                      Littleton Perry
                        (Caldwell co. farmer, pvt. 48th ky mtd inf (usa))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1826"  ><ab>1826</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1864-08-07"  ><ab>1864-08-07</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Caldwell County, Kentucky, farmer and soldier. Kentucky native. Married to Eliza Nichols Perry in Caldwell County, Kentucky, on September 29, 1846. Father of Frances M. &quot;Fannie&quot; Perry, William W. Perry, John Perry, America Perry, James Perry, and Sarah Perry. Farmer in Caldwell County in 1850. Farmer in Caldwell County in 1860. Employed Orlean Nichols as a farmhand in Caldwell County in 1860. Served in the 48th Kentucky Volunteer Mounted Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.) as private from October 26, 1863 to August 7, 1864. Died at the Battle of Salem, Kentucky, on August 7, 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, District 1, p. 282A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Princeton, p. 59.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Caldwell County Marriages, Film #000851644, p. 263.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0446.<lb/>
 &quot;Littleton Wright Perry (1826-1864),&quot; Memorial #43580420, Find A Grave, accessed May 3, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/43580420.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
