<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00019521">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Benjamin Flanders Burba</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00019521">
                    <persName>
                      Benjamin Flanders Burba
                        (Green and LaRue County, Kentucky, carpenter and postmaster.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1830-04-01"  ><ab>1830-04-01</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1902-05-27"  ><ab>1902-05-27</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Green and LaRue County, Kentucky, shoemaker, cabinet workman, and postmaster. Hardin County, Kentucky, native. Son of Scammel Burba and Lydia Flanders Burba. Married to Mary E. Rodman Burba in LaRue County, Kentucky, on November 13, 1856. Father of William R. Burba, Martha W. Burba, and George F. Burba. Shoemaker in LaRue County, Kentucky, in 1850. Resident of Green County, Kentucky, in 1856. Cabinet workman in Green County in 1860. Postmaster for Hodgensville in LaRue County from February 3, 1863, to November 29, 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, LaRue County, Hamiltons District, p. 420A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensburg, p. 627.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, LaRue County, Hodgenville, p. 54B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, Roll 994044, LaRue County Marriages.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Record of Appointment of Postmasters, 1832-1971</hi>, Records of the Post Office Department, NARA Series M841, RG 28, LaRue County, Kentucky, vol. 47, p. 111.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Sons of the American Revolution Membership Applications, 1889-1970</hi>, National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, Louisville, KY, National 6997, State 497.<lb/>
&quot;Benjamin Flanders Burba (1830-1902),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 10986569, accessed March 3, 2023, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/10986569.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
