<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000853">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Philip Burton Thompson, Sr.</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Melissa DeVelvis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000853">
                    <persName>
                      Philip Burton Thompson, Sr.
                        (KY prov govt, attorney )
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1821-01-08"  ><ab>1821-01-08</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1908-11-28"  ><ab>1908-11-28</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Mercer County, Kentucky, attorney, soldier, and politician. Harrodsburg, Kentucky, native. Son of John B. and Nancy Robards Thompson. Married to Martha A. Montgomery Thompson. Father of Davis M. Thompson, Philip “Little Phil” Burton Thompson, Jr., and John Burton Thompson. Educated at Centre College in Danville, Kentucky, and Jefferson College in Cannonsburg, Pennsylvania. Admitted to the bar in 1840 and practiced law in Mercer County, Kentucky. Member of the Whig Party. Served as a captain in the Second Regiment Kentucky Foot Volunteers in the Mexican War from 1846 to 1847. Member of the Council of Ten in the Provisional Government of Kentucky. Member of the Committee on Banks and Committee on Military Affairs for the Provisional Government of Kentucky. Received gubernatorial pardon on September 2, 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, District No 1, p. 247A.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, Harrodsburg, p. 686.

Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, Harrodsburg, p. 583B.

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Colonel Phillip Burton Thompson, Sr (1821-1908),&quot; Memorial 126486353, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/126486353  (accessed January 25, 2017).

<hi rend="italic">Case Files of Applications from Former Confederates for Presidential Pardons</hi> (&quot;Amnesty Papers&quot;), 1865-67, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M1003, Roll 0025, Kentucky, p. 641 of microfilm (accessed through ancestry.com on January 8, 2020). 

Lewis Collins and Richard Collins, <hi rend="italic">History of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1 (Collins &amp; Company, 1882), 353.

John J. McAfee, <hi rend="italic">Kentucky Politicians: Sketches of Representative Corncrackers and other Miscellany</hi> (Louisville: Press of the Courier-Journal Job Printing Company, 1886), 156-157.

“Full of Years Noted Man Dies: Col. Phil B. Thompson, Sr., Is No More,” <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, Ky.), November 29, 1908.

<hi rend="italic">The Biographical Cyclopedia of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</hi>, (Chicago: Donohue &amp; Henneberry, 1896): 166-168.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
