<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00009292">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Charles Humphrey Mooar</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Emily D. Moses</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00009292">
                    <persName>
                      Charles Humphrey Mooar
                        (Kenton County, Kentucky, judge and attorney.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1822-06-17"  ><ab>1822-06-17</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1898-03-30"  ><ab>1898-03-30</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Kenton County, Kentucky, judge and attorney. Hillsborough County, New Hampshire, native. Son of Gardner Mooar and Mary Hardy Marden Moore. Married to Phebe Cordelia Flagg Mooar on March 25, 1830. Father of Charles Clarence Mooar, Sarah Oriana Mooar, Mary Alma Mooar, and Evie Louisa Mooar. Graduated from Dartmouth College in Grafton County, New Hampshire, in 1848. Teacher in Louisiana from 1848 to 1849. Gold prospector in California in 1849. Read law with James Turner Morehead in Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky, in 1849. Attorney in Kenton County in 1850. Household owned two enslaved persons in Kenton County in 1850. Judge of the Kenton County Court from 1858 to 1862. Attorney in Covington in 1860. Employed Mary Walker as a servant in Covington in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, p. 149B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, Covington Ward 5, p. 756.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, Covington Ward 8, p. 132B.<lb/>
George T. Chapman, <hi rend="italic">Sketches of the Alumni of Dartmouth College: From the First Graduation in 1771 to the Present Time, with a Brief History of the Institution</hi> (Cambridge, MA: Riverside Press, 1867), 374.<lb/>
George Mooar, <hi rend="italic">Mooar (Moors) Genealogy: Abraham Mooar of Andover, and His Descendants</hi> (Boston: Charles H. Pope, 1901), 82-3.<lb/>
&quot;Judge C.H. Mooar,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Pittsburg Post</hi> (Pittsburg, PA), April 1, 1898, p. 2.<lb/>
&quot;Judge Mooar Dead,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Cincinnati Enquirer</hi> (Cincinnati, OH), April 1, 1898, p. 8.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
