<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00009887">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Jarvis Gladding Cady</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00009887">
                    <persName>
                      Jarvis Gladding Cady
                        (Mason County, KY, merchant, clerk, &amp; US Police Captain)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1830-03-09"  ><ab>1830-03-09</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1875-06-27"  ><ab>1875-06-27</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Maysville, Kentucky, merchant, clerk, and law enforcement officer. Providence, Rhode Island, native. Son of John Cleveland Cady and Lucy Morris Nichols Cady. Married to Mary Louise Mitchell Cady in Mason County on November 23, 1854. Father of Mary L. Cady, William Frank Cady, and  Andrew M. Cady. Merchant in Mason County in 1860. Clerk at Pearce &amp; Son, Cincinnati, Ohio, in 1863. U. S. police captain in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mason County, Maysville, p. 291.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fleming County, Flemingsburg, p. 413A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Kentucky, 9th Congressional District, Vol. 1, September 1863, p. 63, p. 66 of microfilm, (Accessed via ancestry.com on May 27, 2020).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Jarvis Gladding Cady (1830-1875),&quot; Memorial 128446380, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/128446380 (accessed May 27, 2020).<lb/>
Cleveland, Edmund Janes, 1842-1902, and Horace Gillette Cleveland. The Genealogy of the Cleveland And Cleaveland Families: An Attempt to Trace, In Both the Male And Female Lines, the Posterity of Moses Cleveland ... [and] of Alexander Cleveland ... With Numerous Biographical Sketches; And Containing Ancestries of Many of the Husbands And Wives, Also a Bibliography of the Cleveland Family And a Genealogical Account of Edward Winn of Woburn, And of Other Winn Families. (Hartford, Conn.: Printed for the subscribers by the Case, Lockwood &amp; Brainard company, 1899), 1573.<lb/>
Ella Hazel Spraker and Jesse Procter Crump, <hi rend="italic">The Boone family: a genealogical history of the descendants of George and Mary Boone, who came to America in 1717…</hi> (Rutland, VT: Tuttle Co., 1922), 483.<lb/>
KYR-0002-022-0128.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
