<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011382">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert E. Pitt </title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Carl Creason</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011382">
                    <persName>
                      Robert E. Pitt 
                        (Calloway County, KY, merchant, soldier, and prov gov)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1838-10-20"  ><ab>1838-10-20</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1913-12-08"  ><ab>1913-12-08</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Calloway County, Kentucky, merchant and soldier. Kentucky native. Son of Tabitha Pitt. Resident of Calloway County in 1850. Merchant in Calloway County in 1860. Served in the 3rd Kentucky Mounted Infantry Regiment (C.S.A.) as a private from August 1861 to October 1861. Member of the convention of the provisional government held at Russellville in November 1861. Merchant in Calloway County in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Calloway County, District 1, p. 483B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Calloway County, Murray, p. 189.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Calloway County, Murray, p. 88A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Confederate Soldiers who Served in Organizations from the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M319, Roll 0094.<lb/>
KYR-0004-033-0001.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865 (Civil War Union Draft Records), Calloway County, KY, June-July 1863, p. 551, (Accessed via Ancestry.com).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;R. E. Pitt (Oct. 20, 1838-Dec. 8, 1913),&quot;Memorial #25022769, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/25022769 (accessed December 16, 2019).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
