<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00016824">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Elijah Adams Coppage</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00016824">
                    <persName>
                      Elijah Adams Coppage
                        (Marion County, Kentucky, farmer, merchant, second lieutenant (U.S.A.) and postmaster)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1828-04-27"  ><ab>1828-04-27</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1904-12-15"  ><ab>1904-12-15</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Marion County, Kentucky, farmer, merchant, soldier, and postmaster. Kentucky native. Son of Joel Coppage and Lucinda Coppage. Married to Elizabeth Knott Coppage. Father of Emma Coppage. Farmer in Marion County, Kentucky, in 1850. Merchant in Marion County in 1860. <lb/>
Served as second lieutenant in the 8th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry (U.S.A.) in from September 8, 1862 to November 18, 1862. United States postmaster in Marion County from December 24, 1862 to November 23, 1864. United States postmaster in Marion County in 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Marion County, p. 831 A-B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Marion County, District 2, p. 695.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Marion County, Raywick, p. 160 A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0088.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Record of Appointment of Postmasters, 1832-1971</hi> Records of the Post Office Department, NARA Series M841, RG 28, Marion County, Kentucky, vol. 28, p. 153.<lb/>
Bureau of the Census: Department of Commerce and Labor. <hi rend="italic">Official Register of the United States, Containing a List of the Officers and Employees in the Civil, Military, and Naval Service on the Thirtieth September, 1865.</hi> (Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office.) 116.<lb/><lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), 217.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Death Certificates, 1911-1965</hi>, Kentucky Office of Vital Statistics, KDLA, Frankfort, KY, File #31652.<lb/>
&quot;Elijah Adams Coppage (1828-1904),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #112102920, accessed December 16, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/112102920.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
