<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004533">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Edmund Haynes Taylor, Sr.</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004533">
                    <persName>
                      Edmund Haynes Taylor, Sr.
                        (Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky, banker and Kentucky Military Board member.)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1799-06-04"  ><ab>1799-06-04</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1873-04-24"  ><ab>1873-04-24</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky, banker and Kentucky Military Board member. Jefferson County, Kentucky, native. Son of Richard Taylor, Jr., and Mary Taylor. Married to Martha Southgate Taylor. Father of Mary Bell Taylor and Lucy Taylor. Married to Elizabeth Fell Taylor. Father of Phillip S. Taylor and Sarah J. Taylor. Guardian and adoptive father of nephew Edmund Haynes Taylor, Jr. Resident of Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky, in 1811. Clerk in the office of the State Auditor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky in 1818. Quartermaster General of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. Resident of Frankfort in 1830. Owned one enslaved person in Frankfort in 1830. Cashier of the Frankfort branch of the Bank of Kentucky from 1835 to 1873. Resident of Franklin County in 1840. Owned nine enslaved persons in Franklin County in 1840. Bank Cashier in Franklin County in 1850. Owned nineteen enslaved persons in Franklin County in 1850. Resident of Frankfort in 1860. Owned fourteen enslaved persons in Frankfort in 1860. Held an additional six enslaved persons for the estate of Mary C. Gore in Frankfort in 1860. Household owned an additional fourteen enslaved persons in Frankfort in 1860. Member of the Military Board of Kentucky from September 25, 1861 to March 15, 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Fifth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1830), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, p. 111.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Sixth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1840), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, p. 327.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, District 2, p. 105B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, District 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort District 1, pp. 240-241.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort District 1, pp. 489A, 492B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, p. 142A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), vii.<lb/>
E. Polk Johnson, <hi rend="italic">A History of Kentucky and Kentuckians: The Leaders and Representative Men in Commerce, Industry and Modern Activities</hi>, vol. III (Chicago and New York: Lewis Publishing Company, 1812), 1704.<lb/>
F. Paul Pacult, <hi rend="italic">Buffalo, Barrels, &amp; Bourbon: The Story of How Buffalo Trace Distillery Became the World&#39;s Most Awarded Distillery</hi> (Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc., 2021), pp. 52-53.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Sons of the American Revolution Membership Applications, 1889-1970</hi>, National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, Louisville, KY, National 60174, State 840.<lb/>
&quot;Edmund Haynes Taylor, Sr. (1799-1873),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 66970240, accessed November 23, 2022, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/66970240.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
