<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008185">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Junius R. Ward</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008185">
                    <persName>
                      Junius R. Ward
                        (Washington County, Mississippi, and Scott County, Kentucky, planter and livestock breeder)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1802"  ><ab>1802</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1883-08"  ><ab>1883-08</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Washington County, Mississippi, and Scott County, Kentucky, planter and livestock breeder. Scott County native. Son of William Ward and Sarah Johnson Ward. Married to Matilda Viley Ward. Father of George Ward, Elizabeth Ward, Sarah Ward, Mary Ward, Junius R. Ward, and Matilda Ward. Admitted to the U.S. Military Academy at West Point, New York, in 1820. Planter in Washington County and Scott County in 1850 and 1860. Owned 107 enslaved persons in Washington County in 1850.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Scott County, District No. 2. <hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Mississippi, Washington County, District No. 2. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), [Population/Slave] Schedules, [State], [County], [City/District], p. X. <hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Mississippi, Washington County, District No. 1, p. 109. Davis, John H., <hi rend="italic">The American Turf: History of the Thoroughbred, Together with Personal Reminiscences by the Author, Who, in Turn, Has Been Jockey, Trainer and Owner</hi> (New York: The John Polhemus Printing Company, 1907), 139. William Ward, <hi rend="italic">List of Cadets Admitted into the United States Military Academy, West Point, N.Y., From its Origin till September 1, 1886, (Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, 1887), 65. Franklin L. Riley, ed., _Publications of the Mississippi Historical Society</hi> (University, Mississippi: Mississippi Historical Society, 1914), 271. <hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Junius R. Ward (1802-1883),&quot; Memorial #97066606, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/97066606/junius-r.-ward (accessed January 5, 2018).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
