<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003319">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Benjamin Gratz Bruce</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>MontanaWilliamson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003319">
                    <persName>
                      Benjamin Gratz Bruce
                        (Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky, grocer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1827-12-19"  ><ab>1827-12-19</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1891-09-23"  ><ab>1891-09-23</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky, grocer and city councilman. Kentucky native. Son of John Bruce and Margaret Ross Hutton Bruce. Married to Louisa A. Chiles Bruce in Estill County, Kentucky, on November 1, 1849. Father of Margaret &quot;Maggie&quot; Bruce and Louisa Bruce. Attended Transylvania University in Lexington, Kentucky, from 1845 to 1847. Physician in Estill County in 1850. Household owned eighteen enslaved persons in Estill County in 1850. Grocer in Lexington in 1860. Grocer in Fayette County in 1863. Member of the Lexington City Council in 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Estill County, p. 103A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Estill County. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, Lexington, p. 421.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Annual Announcement of Transylvania University, 1846-1847</hi> (Lexington, KY: Printed at the Observer and Reporter Office, 1847) 6.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Fayette County, KY, June and July 1863, p. 3.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Estill County Marriages, Film 000254628.<lb/>
&quot;A Handsome Tribute,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Kentucky Leader</hi> (Lexington, KY), October 9, 1891, p. 5.<lb/>
Robert Peter, <hi rend="italic">History of Fayette County, Kentucky: With an Outline Sketch of the Blue Grass Region</hi>, ed. William Henry Perrin (Chicago: O. L. Baskin &amp; Col, 1882), pp. 564-565.<lb/>
&quot;Benjamin Gratz Bruce (1827-1891),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 9303295, accessed September 1, 2022, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/9303295.<lb/>
KYR-0001-004-0494.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
