<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007487">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James L. Arnold</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>James N. McAllister</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007487">
                    <persName>
                      James L. Arnold
                        (Nicholas Co, KY, farmer and clerk)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1822"  ><ab>1822</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1899"  ><ab>1899</ab></event>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Nicholas County, Kentucky, farmer and clerk. Kentucky native. Son of Lewis H. Arnold. Married to Mary Ann Tureman Arnold in Nicholas County on January 11, 1842. Father of Virginia M. Arnold, Ann Elizabeth Arnold, Mary Arnold, and Joseph W. Arnold. Farmer in Nicholas County in 1850. Owned four enslaved persons in Nicholas County in 1850. Household owned five additional enslaved persons in Nicholas County in 1850. Farmer in Nicholas County in 1860. Owned nine enslaved persons in Nicholas County in 1860. Clerk in Nicholas County in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nicholas County, District 2, p. 396A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Nicholas County, District 2, p. 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nicholas County, District 1, p. 317.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Nicholas County, District 1, p. 138A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Trimble County, Bedford, p. 191B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Nicholas County Marriages, Film #000252392, p. 86.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Kentucky, 7th Congressional District, Vol. 2, July 1863, p. 181, (Accessed via ancestry.com on March 18, 2020).<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;James L. Arnold (1822-1899),&quot; Memorial 25973305, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/25973305  (accessed March 18, 2020).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
