<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002379">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Tecumseh Sherman</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Samuel T. Whittaker</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002379">
                    <persName>
                      William Tecumseh Sherman
                        (U.S. Army soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1820-02-08"  ><ab>1820-02-08</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1891-02-14"  ><ab>1891-02-14</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>U.S. Army soldier. Lancaster, Ohio, native. Married to Eleanor Boyle Ewing Sherman. Graduated from the U.S. Military Academy at West Point, New York, in 1840. Breveted captain as administrative officer in California during the Mexican-American War. Resigned U.S. Army in 1853. Banker in San Francisco, California, from 1853 to 1857. Attorney in Fort Leavensworth, Kansas. Superintendent and professor of engineering at the Louisiana Seminary for Learning and Military Academy from 1859 to 1861. President of a street car company in St. Louis, Missouri in 1861. Commissioned a colonel of the 13th U.S. infantry in May 1861. Promoted to brigadier general in August 1861. Commander of U.S. forces in Kentucky in October 1861. Served in the Western Theatre in Kentucky, Tennessee, and Mississippi. Promoted to major general in May 1862. Commander of the Army of the Tennessee. Commander of all U.S. forces in the Western Theatre in 1864. Received the surrender of Confederate General Joseph E. Johnston&#39;s command at Duraham, North Carolina, on April 26, 1865. Appointed commander of the Military Division of the Mississippi in June 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Louisiana, Rapides Parish, p. 84.<lb/>
Ezra J. Warner, Jr., <hi rend="italic">Generals in Blue: Lives of the Union Commanders</hi> (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1964), 441-444.<lb/>
&quot;William Tecumseh Sherman (1820-1891),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 951, accessed January 12, 2018, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/951.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
