<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00011383">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Philip L. Lee</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Carl Creason</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Carl Creason</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00011383">
                    <persName>
                      Philip L. Lee
                        (Bullitt County, Kentucky, attorney, soldier, and provisional government convention member)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1832-10-23"  ><ab>1832-10-23</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1875-07-12"  ><ab>1875-07-12</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Bullitt County, Kentucky, attorney, soldier, and provisional government convention member. Native of Bullitt County, Kentucky. Son of Wilford Lee and Margaret Lee. Graduate of St. Joseph&#39;s College (Bardstown, Kentucky) in 1850. Graduate of the University of Louisville School of Law in 1852. Served two terms in the Kentucky Legislature from 1853 to 1857. Candidate for presidential elector for the American Party in 1856. Attorney in Bullitt County in 1860. Campaigned on behalf of the Constitutional Union Party in 1860. Member of the convention of the provisional government held at Russellville in November 1861. Served in the 2nd Kentucky Mounted Infantry (C.S.A.) as a captain, major, and lieutenant colonel from July 12, 1861 to 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Bullitt Kentucky, County, Shephersdville, p. 677.<lb/>
Ed Porter Thompson, <hi rend="italic">History of of the Orphan Brigade</hi> (Louisville, KY: L. N. Thompson, 1898), 399-402.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Confederate Soldiers who Served in Organizations from the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M319, Roll 0084.<lb/>
KYR-0004-033-0001.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Philip Lightfoot Lee (Oct. 23, 1832-July 12, 1875),&quot; Memorial #627519, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/627519 (accessed April 21, 2020).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
