<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018958">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Martin Gardner Holmes</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Matthew Roberts</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Matthew Roberts</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018958">
                    <persName>
                      Martin Gardner Holmes
                        (Louisville, Kentucky, constable and keeper of work house)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="death"  when="1871-02-22"  ><ab>1871-02-22</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, constable and keeper of work house. Kentucky native. Married to Rosamond A. Robards in Bullitt, Kentucky, on December 4, 1834. Father of Francis Holmes, Sarah E. Holmes, Keturah T. Holmes, and Dick Holmes. Constable in Louisville, Kentucky, in 1850. Keeper of Work House in Louisville, Kentucky, in 1860. Employed Joseph H. Roberts in Louisville, Kentucky, in 1850. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville District 1, p. 4A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, District 2, p. 915.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 12, p. 626B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Bullitt County Marriages, Film 000482690.<lb/>
&quot;Martin Gardner Holmes (unknown-1871),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 161632587, accessed December 1, 2022, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/16132587.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
