<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00018154">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Caleb Cummins</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Ian Iverson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00018154">
                    <persName>
                      Caleb Cummins
                        (Pendleton County, Kentucky, laborer and farmer. )
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1832-10-11"  ><ab>1832-10-11</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1904-11-26"  ><ab>1904-11-26</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Pendleton County, Kentucky, laborer, farmer, and soldier. Bracken County, Kentucky, native. Son of James Cummins and Resa A. Cummins. Married to Lydia Brown Cummins in Pendleton County, Kentucky, on June 2, 1853. Father of Augustus Cummins, Eleanora Cummins, Albertus Cummins, and Daniel Cummins. Laborer in Pendleton County in 1850. Farmer in Pendleton County in 1863. Served in the 54th Kentucky Volunteer Infantry (U.S.A.) as a private from September 21, 1864, to September 1, 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Pendleton County, District No. 1, p. 356A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Boone County, Bighorn Precinct, p. 152A. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From the State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0460.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi>, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), NARA RG 110, Pendleton County, KY, June and July 1863, p. 102.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, X County Marriages, Film #000272800.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), p. 550.<lb/>
&quot;Caleb Cummines (1832-1904),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #13366337, Accessed July 14, 2022, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/13366337.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
