<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00009437">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William H. Shook</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Sarah Haywood</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Lucas R. Somers</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00009437">
                    <persName>
                      William H. Shook
                        (Spencer County, Indiana, carpenter, farmer, customs collector, and major (KY State Militia))
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1812"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1812</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Spencer County, Indiana, carpenter, farmer, customs collector, and soldier. Indiana native. Married to Margaret Jane Kerr Shook in Harrison County, Indiana, on November 13, 1833. Father of Lemuel Shook, James C. Shook, George T. Shook, and William H. Shook, Jr. Married to Mary Ann Johnson Shook in Clark County, Indiana, on February 23, 1850. Father of Sarah E. Shook, Delana Wiley Shook, Meletus Edwin Shook, and Catherine E. Shook. Married to Lucretia M. Tindall Shook in Spencer County, Indiana, on December 19, 1860. Ship carpenter in Clark County, Indiana, in 1850. Farmer in Spencer County in 1860. Customs collector for Evansville in 1863. Resident of Union County, Kentucky, in 1863. Served in the North Cumberland Battalion of the Kentucky Enrolled Militia (U.S.A.) as major and provost marshal from December 1, 1864, to May 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Indiana, Clark County, Jeffersonville, p. 182B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Indiana, Spencer County, Luce, p. 307.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Indiana, Spencer County, Luce, 563A-B. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Indiana Marriage Records, 1801-1952</hi>, Indiana Archives and Record Administration, Office of the Harrison County Clerk. Harrison County, Indiana, Marriage Records, volume A.3, 1832- 1846, p. 23.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Indiana Marriage Records, 1801-1952</hi>, Indiana Archives and Record Administration, Office of the Clark County Clerk. Clark County, Indiana, Marriage Records, volume F, 1848-1855, p. 120.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Indiana Marriage Records, 1801-1952</hi>, Indiana Archives and Record Administration, Office of the Spencer County Clerk. Spencer County, Indiana, Marriage Records, volume 4, 1855- 1863, p. 387<lb/>
United States Department of the Interior, <hi rend="italic">Register of Officers and Agents, Civil, Military, and Naval, in the Service of the United States on the Thirtieth September, 1863</hi>, (Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, 1864), p. 92.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), p. 766, 958.<lb/>
KYR-0001-004-0221.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
