<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000924">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Mason Brown</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000924">
                    <persName>
                      John Mason Brown
                        (Frankfort, Kentucky, attorney and soldier)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1837-04-26"  ><ab>1837-04-26</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1890-01-29"  ><ab>1890-01-29</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Frankfort, Kentucky, attorney and soldier. Frankfort native. Son of Mason Brown and Mary Yoder Brown. Married to Mary O. Preston Brown. Father of at least four children. Attended school with Mr. Sayre in Frankfort, Kentucky. Graduate of Yale College in 1856. Admitted to the bar in 1858. Attorney in St. Louis, Missouri and Frankfort, Kentucky. Served in the 10th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry Regiment (U.S.A.) as major from October 1862 to April 1863. Assistant inspector general of Kentucky with the rank of colonel from November 1863 to February 1864. Served in the 45th Kentucky Volunteer Mounted Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.) as colonel from February 1864 to December 1864. Attorney in Frankfort in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl>Obituary Records of Graduates of Yale University, (http://mssa.library.yale.edu/obituary<hi rend="italic">record/1859</hi>1924/1889-90.pdf, 584-585) (accessed on February 16, 2017). 

H. Levin, <hi rend="italic">The Lawyers and Lawmakers of Kentucky</hi> (Chicago: The Lewis Publishing Company, 1897), 209. 

“Died in His Prime: Col. John Mason Brown’s Illness Terminated By Death Yesterday,” <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, Ky.), January 30, 1890. 

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Col James Mason Brown (April 26, 1837-January 29, 1890),&quot; Memorial #73732532, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/73732532 (accessed  February 16, 2017).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
