<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00010361">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Ignatius C. Mattingly</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Christina Adkins</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00010361">
                    <persName>
                      Ignatius C. Mattingly
                        (Nelson Couny)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1802"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1802</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1886"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1886</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Bardstown, Nelson County, Kentucky, tailor and postmaster. Maryland native. Married to Mary E. Smith Mattingly in Nelson County in November 1826. Father of Austin Mattingly, Benjamin Mattingly, Eliza Mattingly, John R. Mattingly and Sallie Mattingly. Resident of Nelson County in 1830. Owned two enslaved persons in Nelson County in 1830. Engaged in manufacture and trade in Nelson County in 1840. Owned  three enslaved persons in Nelson County in 1840. Tailor in Nelson County in 1850.  Household owned thirteen slaves in Nelson County in 1850. Postmaster of Bardstown from September 30, 1856, to August 20, 1863. Owned four enslaved persons in Nelson County in 1860. Household owned an additional eight slaves in Nelson County in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Fifth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1830), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, Bardstown, p. 138.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Sixth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1840), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, North East District, p. 30.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 2, p. 388B-389A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 2, p. 215.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 1, p. 184.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, District 1, p. 119A and 107A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Nelson County, Bardstown, p. 74B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Nelson County Marriages, Film #000481488, p. 118.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Record of Appointment of Postmasters, 1832-1971.</hi> Records of the Post Office Department, NARA Series M841, RG 28, Nelson County, Kentucky, Volume 28, p. 272 of microfilm.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Ignatius C. Mattingly (1802-1886),&quot; Memorial 41789152, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/41789152  (accessed April 16, 2020).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
