<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006126">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Charles S. Brent</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Stephen Powell</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Brian M. Trump</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006126">
                    <persName>
                      Charles S. Brent
                        (Bourbon County, Kentucky, banker)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1811-01-28"  ><ab>1811-01-28</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1881-02-16"  ><ab>1881-02-16</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Bourbon County, Kentucky, merchant and banker. Son of Hugh Brent. Married to Susan Clarissa Taylor Brent in Bourbon County on July 19, 1831. Father of Hugh Brant. Married to Matilda Chambers Brent. Father of John Brent, Elizabeth Brent, J. Sprigg Breant, Belle Hart Brent, Charles Brent, Hannah Brent, Thomas J. Brent, James A. Brent, Matilda Brent, Henry C. Brent, and Kelly Brent. Married to Martha Harding Ford Brent. Merchant in Bourbon County in 1850. Owned twelve enslaved persons in Bourbon County in 1850. Banker in Bourbon County in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bourbon County, District 2, p. 246A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Bourbon County, District 2.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bourbon, Paris, p. 489.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bourbon, Paris Ward 1, p. 424B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Bourbon County Marriages, Film 000851644.<lb/>
George Norbury Mackenzie, ed., <hi rend="italic">Colonial Families of the United States of America: In Which is Given the History, Genealogy and Armorial Bearings of Colonial Families Who Settled in the American Colonies from the Time of the Settlement of Jamestown, 13th May, 1607, to the Battle of Lexington, 19th April, 1775</hi>, vol. II (Baltimore, MD: Genealogical Publishing Company, 1966), p. 419.<lb/>
&quot;Charles Scott Brent (1811-1881),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial 89874910, accessed December 8, 2022, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/89874910.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
