<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00005692">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Curran Pope</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Kristen Bailey</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00005692">
                    <persName>
                      Curran Pope
                        (Louisville, KY, attorney, trustee, and colonel 5th KY Inf)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1813-07-30"  ><ab>1813-07-30</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1862-11-05"  ><ab>1862-11-05</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, attorney, trustee, and soldier. Louisville, Kentucky, native. Son of Worden Pope and Elizabeth Taylor Thruston Pope. Married Matilda Prather Jacob Pope in Jefferson County, Kentucky, on October 23, 1838. Father of John J. Pope, Patrick H. Pope, and Mary Tyler Pope. Graduate of the United States Military Academy at West Point, New York, in 1834. Served in the United States Artillery as a second lieutenant in 1834. Assistant engineer on the Kentucky River and Cumberland River in 1835. Clerk of the Jefferson County Court in 1850. Owned six enslaved persons in Louisville in 1850. Chairman of the board of trustees of the Presbyterian Female School of Louisville in 1858. Attorney in Louisville in 1860. Owned four enslaved persons in Louisville in 1860. Commander of Kentucky Home Guards in 1861. Served in the 15th Kentucky Volunteer Infantry Regiment (U.S.A.) as colonel from December 14, 1861, to November 5, 1862. Died on November 5, 1862, of wounds received at the Battle of Perryville on October 8, 1862. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 2, p. 226A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 2, p. 15-16.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, Ward 3, p. 707.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, Ward 3, p. 3.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 115-16.<lb/>
&quot;Col. Curran Pope (1813-1862),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #57357318, accessed May 12, 2017, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/57357318. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 285.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Jefferson County Marriages, Film #000817877, p. 74 of 337 microfilm.<lb/>
“Presbyterian Female School of Louisville, KY.” <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY). Aug. 29, 1857.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), 892-93.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), 942.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">U.S. Civil War Pension Index: General Index to Pension Files, 1861-1934</hi>, NARA RG 15, Microfilm Series T288, Kentucky, Application #61799, Certificate #44323.<lb/>
KYR-0002-222-0021.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
