<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00015854">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Archibald Alexander Gordon</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Daniele Celano</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00015854">
                    <persName>
                      Archibald Alexander Gordon
                        (Jefferson County, Kentucky, merchant, banker and trustee)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1811-08-05"  ><ab>1811-08-05</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1879-12-22"  ><ab>1879-12-22</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Jefferson County, Kentucky, merchant, banker, and trustee. Virginia native. Married to Priscilla Chirstian Bullett Gordon in Shelby County, Kentucky, on April 25, 1843. Father of Penelope Gordon, Charles Bullett Gordon, Henry W. Gordon, Harriett Gordon, John L. Gordon, Helen Gordon, Edward E. Gordon, Fannie Gordon, and Archibald A. Gordon. Merchant in Jefferson County, Kentucky, in 1850. Owned three enslaved persons in Jefferson County in 1850. Delegate to the Kentucky Whig Party convention in Louisville in 1856. Member of the Board of Directors of the Louisville Insurance Company in Jefferson County in 1858. Member of the Board of Trustees of the Presbyterian Female School of Louisville  in Jefferson County in 1858. Merchant in Jefferson County in 1860. Dry goods merchant in partnership with James W. Gordon in A.A. Gordon and Company in Louisville in 1861. President of the Southern Bank of Kentucky in Louisville from 1858 to 1862. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 3, p. 320B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville District 3, p. 847.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, Ward 5, p. 118.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, Ward 7, p. 30B. <lb/>
&quot;Archibald Alexander Gordon (1811-1879),&quot; Find A Grave, Memorial #93561937, accessed September 28, 2021, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/93561937.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The Bankers’ Magazine and Statistical Register</hi>, ed. J. Smith Homans, vol. 12 (January 1858), 996.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">The Bankers’ Magazine and Statistical Register</hi>, ed. J. Smith Homans, vol. 14 (January 1860): 995.<lb/>
“Diamond Island for Sale.”<hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY). May 25, 1859. <lb/>
“For the Louisville Journal.” <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY). July 2, 1856.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Kentucky Marriage Records</hi>, Madison County Courthouse, Richmond, Kentucky, Shelby County Marriages, Film #000259288, p. 1212.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Lineage Book of the Charter Members of the National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution</hi>, eds. Mary S. Lockwood and Susan Riviere Hetzel (Washington, D. C.: National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1891-1939) vol. 38: 1901, p. 149.<lb/>
“Louisville Insurance Company.” <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY). July 5, 1857. <lb/>
“Presbyterian Female School of Louisville, KY.” <hi rend="italic">Courier-Journal</hi> (Louisville, KY). Aug. 29, 1857. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Tanner’s Louisville Directory and Business Advertiser for 1861</hi> ed. Henry Tanner (Louisville: Directory Publication and Advertising Agency, 1861), 102, 290, 325.<lb/>
KYR-0001-031-0051.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
