<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00012026">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Elias T. Oberdorfer</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00012026">
                    <persName>
                      Elias T. Oberdorfer
                        (Jefferson County, KY, flour dealer &amp; grocer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1814-06-25"  ><ab>1814-06-25</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1897-08-25"  ><ab>1897-08-25</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Jefferson County, Kentucky, grocer and flour dealer. Native of Germany. Married to Frances “Fanny” Lewis Oberdorfer in Cincinnati, Ohio, in July 1843. Father of Gertrude Oberdorfer, David Oberdorfer, Henry Oberdorfer, and Rosa Oberdorfer. Merchant in Breckinridge County in 1850. Owned one enslaved person in Breckinridge County in 1850. Retail grocer in Louisville in 1859. Grocer in Louisville in 1860. Employed C. Wood as a servant in Louisville in 1860. Signed a petition as a flour dealer in May 1861 to appoint W. G. Timberlake as flour inspector.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Breckinridge County, District 1, p. 97B.

<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Breckinridge County, District 1, p. 675, p. 7 of microfilm.

<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 6, p. 379.

<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 8, p. 135B.

<hi rend="italic">Ohio, County Marriage Records, 1774-1993</hi>. Hamilton County marriages, 1842-1844, Film #000344456, p. 180 of microfilm.

Henry Tanner, ed., <hi rend="italic">The Louisville Directory and Business Advertiser for 1859-60</hi> (Louisville: Maxwell &amp; Co., 1859), 176, 282.

<hi rend="italic">Birth and Death Records: Covington, Lexington, Louisville, and Newport – Microfilm (before 1911)</hi>, KDLA, Roll #7007129: Jefferson County, Books 9-11, p. 293 of microfilm.

<hi rend="italic">Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Elias Oberdorfer (1814-1987),&quot; Memorial 71701650, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/71701650 (accessed January 27, 2020).

<hi rend="italic">Sons of the American Revolution Membership Applications, 1889-1970</hi>. Louisville, Kentucky: National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution. Microfilm, volume 227, p. 23 of microfilm (accessed through Ancestry.com on January 27, 2020).

KYR-0001-017-0163. 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
