<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00014108">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James H. Calvert</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00014108">
                    <persName>
                      James H. Calvert
                        (Caldwell County, Kentucky, physician, surgeon 25th TN Inf CSA)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1828"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1828</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Caldwell County, Kentucky, physician and soldier. Kentucky native. Physician in Yuba County, California, in 1850. Physician in Princeton, Kentucky, in 1860. Owned two enslaved persons in Caldwell County in 1860. Served in the 25th Tennessee Volunteer Infantry Regiment (C.S.A) as a surgeon from September 26, 1862, to May 19, 1863. Captured near Ashbysburg, Kentucky, on December 24, 1864. Held at the military prison at Louisville, Kentucky, transferred to Camp Chase, Ohio, and then to Fort Delaware in Delaware, from December 31, 1864, until forwarded to Camp Hamilton, Virginia, on January 17, 1865, for a prisoner exchange. Surrended to U.S. forces in Atlanta, Georgia, on May 18, 1865. Signed a loyalty oath to the U. S. government on May 23, 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, California, Yuba County, Grass Valley, p. 311A.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Princeton, p. 111.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Princeton, p. 218.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Confederate General and Staff Officers, and Nonregimental Enlisted Men</hi>, NARA RG 109, Microfilm Series M331, Roll 0045.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
