<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN001778">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James R. Page</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Charles Welsko</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Natalie Smith</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Samuel T. Whittaker</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N001778">
                    <persName>
                      James R. Page
                        (Frankfort, KY, asst. sec. state)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1827"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1827</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1875"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1875</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky, merchant, soldier, and assistant secretary of state. Married to Susan Page in 1850. Father of Isaac R. Page, Henry C. Page, and John H. Page. Married to Mary T. Hodges Page in Franklin County on December 8, 1858. Father of James R. Page, Albert M. Page, and Lizzie D. Page. Clerk in Frankfort in 1850. Owned three enslaved persons in Franklin County in 1850. Merchant in Frankfort in 1860. Served in the 9th Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry Regiment (U.S.A.) as captain and major from August 22, 1862 to February 14, 1863. Assistant secretary of state under Ephraim Van Winkle. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Kentucky Birth, Marriage and Death Records – Microfilm (1852-1910)</hi>, KDLA, Rolls #994027-994058, Franklin County Marriages, p. 14 of microfilm.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, District N. 1, p. 39B.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, District No. 2, p. 914.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, pp. 241-2. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Illinois, Richland County, Denver Township, p. 517B.<lb/>
“Decoration Day,” <hi rend="italic">The Frankfort Roundabout</hi> (Frankfort, Ky.), May 28, 1892, p. 3. &quot;Memorandum,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Louisville Daily Courier</hi> (Louisville, Ky.), May 31, 1867, p. 1. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of Kentucky</hi>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M397, Roll 0098.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), 228-29, 251.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
