<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN001004">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Fisher Robinson</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>James Bartek</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Deborah J. Thompson</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name></name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N001004">
                    <persName>
                      James Fisher Robinson
                        (governor, state senator, businessman, attorney, and farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1800-10-04"  ><ab>1800-10-04</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1882-10-31"  ><ab>1882-10-31</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Twenty-second governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from August 18, 1862 to September 1, 1863. Son of Jonathan Robinson and Jane Black Robinson. Married Susan D. Mansell Robinson on December 26, 1821. Father of Emilie Jane Robinson and James F. Robinson, Jr. Married Willina S. Herndon Robinson on May 30, 1842. Father of Scott Herndon Robinson, John McCracken Robinson, George Sidney Robinson, Madison Johnson Robinson, Stephen Gano Robinson, Willa Ewing Robinson, Philip Eldon Robinson, and Stephen Gano Robinson. Educated at Forest Hill Academy and Transylvania University in Lexington, Kentucky. Owned thirty-five enslaved persons in 1860. Trustee of Georgetown College. President of the Farmers&#39; Bank of Georgetown. Represented Fayette and Scott counties in the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1851 to 1855. Represented Fayette and Scott counties in the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1861 until he became governor on August 18, 1862. Speaker of the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from September 3 to September 5, 1861. Speaker of the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from August 16 to August 18, 1862. Returned to practicing law and farming on retiring from politics in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl>John David Smith, “James F. Robinson (1862-1863)” in Lowell H. Harrison, Ed., <hi rend="italic">Kentucky’s Governors</hi> (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 2004), 89-92. <lb/>
William Henry Engle, <hi rend="italic">Pennsylvania Genealogies: Scotch-Irish and German</hi> (Harrisburg: Lane S. Hart, 1886), 553, 556-7. <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Scott County, District No 1, p. 216B, 230, . <lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Scott County, District No 2, pp. 235, 236, 252.<lb/>
<hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville Ward 4, p. 266.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
