<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DO00012610">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">City Work House of Louisville</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Carl Creason</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Carl Creason</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

        <encodingDesc>
            <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
                <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
                </prefixDef>
            </listPrefixDef>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term type="type">Organization</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc>
                <org xml:id="O00012610">
                    <orgName>City Work House of Louisville</orgName>
                        <event type="begun"  when="1832"  ><ab>1832</ab></event>
                        <event type="ended"  when="1954"  ><ab>1954</ab></event>
                </org>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky workhouse. Held petty criminals, the poor, and diseased residents of the city. Opened in 1832 in a building on Chestnut Street to confine both male and female prisoners and wards. Relocated in 1850 to a brick structure on Payne Street near Cave Hill Cemetery. Included 400 cells and 12 dungeons. Managed by a committee of three trustees and a superintendent. Daily operations overseen by an elected keeper who served one-year terms. The keeper appointed day and night guards to prevent escapes and transport prisoners from the Louisville City Court to the Work House. Prisoners worked twelve-hour days in the months of April through September and ten-hour days in the months of October through March. Prisoner duties included rock-breaking to support the construction of city roads and supply a stone quarry in Louisville.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Charter of the City of Louisville, Ky.</hi> (Louisville: L. A. Civill, Printer, 1862), 332-336.

Morton O. Childress, <hi rend="italic">Louisville Division of Police History and Personnel</hi> (Paducah, KY: Turner Publishing Company, 2005), 62.

Gary Falk, <hi rend="italic">Louisville Remembered</hi> (Charleston, SC: The History Press, 2009).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
